<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Wine | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/wine/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-20T14:56:07-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Niagara]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/15/niagara/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-15T13:05:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/15/niagara</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Flying to Toronto, I saw the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niagara_Falls">Niagara Falls</a> as a misty interruption of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niagara_River">Niagara River</a>. Turns out they&rsquo;re only about a 1.5hr drive from Toronto, so we decided to head there for an overnight trip. Extra bonus: to get there you travel through <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ontario_wine">Ontario wine country</a>, so we stopped off at a winery on the way back.</p>

<p>Niagara Falls (the town) is very&hellip; commercial. It&rsquo;s almost like a damp Las Vegas. The Canada side (with the better views) has a bunch of casinos, super-tall hotels, chain restaurants. It&rsquo;s a little overwhelming, especially if you imagined it would just be a beautiful waterfall surrounded by nature.</p>

<p>We stayed at the Hilton, which had pretty neat views of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_Falls">American Falls</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/hotel-view.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/hotel-view.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">View from our room. That&#8217;s the U.S.A. across that bridge!</div>
</div>


<p>We arrived at 6pm, and headed straight for the <a href="http://www.niagaracruises.com/">Hornblower</a>. It&rsquo;s the Canadian version of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maid_of_the_Mist">Maid of the Mist</a> boat.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/panorama.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/panorama.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Panorama on the Hornblower</div>
</div>


<p>You take a route up the river, past the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_Falls">American Falls</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bridal_Veil_Falls_(Niagara_Falls)">Bridal Veil Falls</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/american-bridal.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/american-bridal.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">American Falls and Bridal Veil Falls</div>
</div>


<p>After that, the boat goes right into the mist spray of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horseshoe_Falls">Horseshoe Falls</a>. <strong>Pro-tip</strong>: if you have contact lenses, wear them. I was running out of dry bits of T-shirt to wipe my glasses with.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Horseshoe Falls</div>
</div>


<p>This next photo adequately captures what it feels like in the middle: it&rsquo;s windy and there&rsquo;s mist everywhere and it&rsquo;s loud.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/in-horseshoe.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/in-horseshoe.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">In the middle of the falls</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Posing</div>
</div>


<p>After we got off the boat (thankfully it was pretty warm, so we dried quickly), we headed to our evening meal at <a href="http://www.weinkeller.ca/">Weinkeller</a>. But on the way, we passed a haunted house: Dracula&rsquo;s Haunted Castle <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/@43.0912213,-79.0744428,3a,75y,21.98h,80.75t/data=!3m4!1e1!3m2!1siKb9ZlIUyOeNtBlIvdj2Tg!2e0">on Clifton Hill</a>. We like that sort of thing, so went inside. It was $10 each, and you can choose your scare level – we chose medium.</p>

<p>We were the only ones in there, and after paying headed up some stairs in pitch-black darkness. The first few rooms are dull – mostly poorly-done wa figures. However, towards the latter half the scare actor(s?) come in. He was amazing – he growled and chased us through the maze. It was pretty terrifying, I have to admit. I&rsquo;ve never been more relieved than seeing those stairs leading to the exit.</p>

<p>Anyway, we continued up Clifton Hill to the restaurant. Turns out haunted houses are a big deal in Niagara Falls. We counted three more on the walk. There was one next door/above Weinkeller, too!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/weinkeller-nextdoor.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/weinkeller-nextdoor.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Next door to Weinkeller</div>
</div>


<p>Weinkeller is the <a href="http://www.tripadvisor.ca/Restaurants-g154998-Niagara_Falls_Ontario.html">top-rated TripAdvisor restaurant for Niagara Falls</a>. If you use TripAdvisor, I probably don&rsquo;t need to describe the atmosphere – keen service, slightly older clientele, great value, and delicious food. It amuses Hampton and me to compare ratings on TripAdvisor, Yelp, and FourSquare. Each site&rsquo;s audience has subtley different things they look for in a restaurant.</p>

<p>I think the restaurant space used to be a cheap Italian restaurant. The decor was a little&hellip; lacking. Who puts colour-changing lights in a restaurant? But the wait staff were incredible – making jokes, smiling all the time. One of the menu options is a five-course meal but (get this) you can replace up to two of the courses with a glass of wine. Perfect!</p>

<p>Speaking of wine, they make their own. You can see the casks in the back. It was really quite good. The food was amazing. I had some incredible steak tartare, and my main was a super-juicy pork chop. Hampton had a great seared-tuna thing.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/weinkeller-starter.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/weinkeller-starter.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Tuna</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/weinkeller-main.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/weinkeller-main.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Main course at Weinkeller</div>
</div>


<p>After the meal, we walked back to our hotel and grabbed a drink at Myst, the top-floor bar. The drinks were OK. The view was good – but at night Niagara Falls isn&rsquo;t nearly as impressive. They light the falls with a dim rainbow of colours. Super-tacky. You can&rsquo;t really get a good photo, so you&rsquo;ll have to imagine it.</p>

<p>The next morning we did the other Niagara Falls tourist trap: going behind the Horseshoe Falls. Walking close to the edge of the falls was pretty spectacular. The water is much clearer than I thought it was going to be.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-edge.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-edge.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The edge of Horseshoe Falls</div>
</div>


<p>You take a lift down to the bottom of the falls, and it opens up into these dank tunnels.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-tunnel.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-tunnel.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Tunnels underneath Horseshoe Falls</div>
</div>


<p>You can go outside to just where the falls hit the water, which is extremely loud and incredibly close.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-behind.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-behind.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Where Horseshoe Falls meets the river</div>
</div>


<p>I was always fascinated by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waterfall#mediaviewer/File:WaterfallCreationDiagram.svg">waterfall geography</a> (I was a cool kid). It&rsquo;s so strange to think that Niagara Falls started way downstream and has been slowly moving since then.</p>

<p>You walk down some more tunnels to get behind the actual falls. They have a couple of holes cut in the rock and you can look out. But you can&rsquo;t see much – it&rsquo;s mostly a white mist. It&rsquo;s really loud, too.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-back.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-back.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Behind Horseshoe Falls</div>
</div>


<p>After that, we left Niagara Falls. It was fun going there, but I&rsquo;m not sure I&rsquo;d do it again any time soon. A day there was enough to see and do most things, I think.</p>

<p>The drive back to Toronto goes through wine country, so we stopped off at one of Hampton&rsquo;s favourite wineries: <a href="http://www.fieldingestatewinery.ca/">Fielding Estate</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-entrance.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-entrance.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Entrance to Fielding Estate</div>
</div>


<p>Californian wines aren&rsquo;t really our thing. It&rsquo;s nice going to Napa or Sonoma and doing a wine tour, but we prefer whites grown in colder regions. We like whites from the Alsace, Austria, Ontario or Washington. Fielding Estate Winery has some great wines – aromatic and floral, but not too sweet.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside the tasting room/shop</div>
</div>


<p>We tried about six wines in total, and bought four bottles. The gewurztraminer, the viogner, and the Rock Pile Pinot Gris were the best.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-vats.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-vats.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Casks of wine</div>
</div>


<p>There&rsquo;s an awesome view over the vineyards, too. If we had more time, we would have definitely had a glass outside.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-view.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-view.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">View over the vinyards</div>
</div>


<p>You should definitely visit Fielding Estate if you&rsquo;re in the Niagara area. Or keep an eye out for their wines. They&rsquo;re super-tasty!</p>

<p>Next up, I&rsquo;ll be posting about delicious food and drink we&rsquo;ve had since we&rsquo;ve been in Toronto.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
