<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Orlando | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/orlando/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-18T13:42:57-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halloween Horror Nights 24]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/11/18/halloween-horror-nights/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-18T10:03:17-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/11/18/halloween-horror-nights</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halloween_Horror_Nights">Halloween Horror Nights</a> (also known as &ldquo;HHN&rdquo;) is an annual even put on by the Universal Studios resort in Florida. On select evenings for some of September and most of October, the park is transformed into a halloween scare-park.</p>

<p>There are usually eight or so haunted houses built in soundstages. These will be themed around something, and you walk through decorated rooms while loud noises play and actors jump out at you. There are also scare zones – areas of the park usually just for walking between rides. In these, there will be a few props around a theme, plus some scare actors who move amongst the crowds.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/entrance.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/entrance.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Universal Studios&#8217; Entrance during Halloween Horror Nights</div>
</div>


<p>This year&rsquo;s event was a blast. We were worried that attending on 31st October (Halloween itself), <strong>and</strong> because it was a Friday this year, the queues would be incredibly long. We bought the express pass (an extra cost on top of the regular cost) but we were still unsure as to whether we&rsquo;d be stuck in two-hour-plus lines to see the houses. The express pass often only cuts the regular lines down by half.</p>

<p>So, we implemented a plan laid out in <a href="http://www.orlandoinformer.com/universal/halloween-horror-nights-2014/">Orlando Informer</a> – by far the best resource to look at if you&rsquo;re thinking of visiting HHN. The trick to HHN is that you can get early entry <em>if you have a ticket for Universal Studios that day</em>.</p>

<p>The park closes at 5pm on HHN nights. Around 4:45pm, the staff set up areas of the park where you can sit and wait until HHN begins. The official start time of HHN is 6:30pm. However you&rsquo;re often let out of the areas closer to 5:45pm. That&rsquo;s a good chunk of time to explore houses before people are let in.</p>

<p>The best area to wait is in New York at Finnegans, an Irish pub. It&rsquo;s packed in there, but we got some drinks and took them outside. We put our names in for a table (it was a 40-minute wait, but we thought we&rsquo;d chance it just in case). At about 5:15pm we sat down and ate a quick salad before leaving the &ldquo;pen&rdquo; and heading into the event.</p>

<p>The Orlando Informer article gives some great advice – head to the houses first, then do the scare zones. The lines for two of the most popular mazes – <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Walking_Dead_(TV_series)">The Walking Dead</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_vs._Predator_(film)">Alien vs Predator</a> – were 20 minutes, which was great! We did those in quick succession.</p>

<p>The Walking Dead was touted as the largest house they&rsquo;d done – and it was filled with scare actors. Overall it was entertaining but unmemorable. There was one great scene in a forest, where I truly felt like zombies were coming at me from all sides. But apart from that, it seemed like a bunch of generic zombie scenes. Maybe I wasn&rsquo;t paying attention to season 4 enough?</p>

<p>Alien vs Predator did a great job of putting you in the <a href="http://avp.wikia.com/wiki/Weyland-Yutani">Weyland-Yutani</a> corporation as the Aliens take over and Predators are brought in to control them. At least, that&rsquo;s what I think the gist of the house was – it wasn&rsquo;t incredibly clear. I&rsquo;m an Alien fan, so I mostly delighted in the incredible puppet animatronics they had. Plus the ending – crawling through a narrow air-duct with an Alien waiting at the end – was an exhilarating finish.</p>

<p>We headed over to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halloween_(1978_film)">Halloween</a> house, which was over at the other end of the park. Here&rsquo;s another pro-tip: if the regular queue is pretty short, don&rsquo;t bother using your express pass. You can only use your express pass once per house. When we first went to the Halloween house, the queue was only 5 minutes – definitely not worth wasting our express on.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/halloween.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/halloween.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Front of the Halloween house</div>
</div>


<p>The house had every major scene from the 1978 classic. It was a lot of fun entering the (almost clichéd) house. The decor was perfectly 70s and I&rsquo;m glad we had a second pass at the house later on in the evening. There were a number of scenes we missed the first time around.</p>

<p>After these, we did the &ldquo;non-property&rdquo; houses. These are houses that aren&rsquo;t based on any existing intellectual property. This year, there were three: Giggles and Gore (about clowns), Roanoake (about cannibals), and Dollhouse of the Damned (about creepy dolls).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/dollhouse.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/dollhouse.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Front of Dollhouse of the Damned</div>
</div>


<p>Once we&rsquo;d done those, we were free to wander around the scare zones and attend the shows (they have special halloween-only live shows during HHN). My favourite scare zone was based around <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Purge">The Purge</a>. Hampton and I both enjoyed the films, and the theme fits well with the New York area of Universal Studios.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/gone-purging.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/gone-purging.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;Gone Purging&#8221; sign in the New York area</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/purge-bus.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/purge-bus.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hampton supports our new founding fathers</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/flowers.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/flowers.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Signature blue flowers</div>
</div>


<p>We noticed all of the above while touring the park during the day. At night, they bring out some extra props, like this sign.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/purge-sign.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/purge-sign.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Enjoy the Purge!</div>
</div>


<p>The other scare zone I enjoyed was based around the reality show <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Face_Off_(TV_series)">Face Off</a>. Some of the most famous make-ups they&rsquo;ve had on the show were there.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/face-off-1.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/face-off-1.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">FaceOff scarecrow thing</div>
</div>


<p>It was cool seeing them, but the scare zone just turned into a photo opportunity. We were guilty, too – we stood in front of the couple of make-ups we enjoyed from the series and took some photos. So not that scary, but fun nonetheless.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/face-off-2.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/face-off-2.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">FaceOff minotaur thing</div>
</div>


<p>Halloween Horror Nights isn&rsquo;t <em>that</em> scary. We&rsquo;ve found that smaller, local events are far scarier. Scare-actors at Universal Studios can&rsquo;t touch you. You move through the houses in a giant conga-line, rather than small groups.</p>

<p>With that said, Universal puts so much money into these houses that they&rsquo;re above and beyond anything you&rsquo;ll see at another horror event. The mazes are detailed and, for those based on films or TV shows, often amazingly accurate.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal Studios' London/Diagon Alley]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/11/13/universal-studios/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-13T14:47:30-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/11/13/universal-studios</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Orlando is a strange place. Knowing a number of people who live (and have lived) there, we&rsquo;re always instructed to explore the city. &ldquo;There&rsquo;s so much more than theme parks!&rdquo; we&rsquo;re told. And that&rsquo;s true! We explored a little last year – we were recording with Treehouse and found a couple of great places. <a href="https://www.facebook.com/hansonsshoerepair">Hanson&rsquo;s Shoe Repair</a> is a cool speakeasy hidden behind a downtown bar/club. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Winter_Park,_Florida">Winter Park</a> area seems neat, too – we had a great meal at the <a href="http://www.theravenouspig.com/">Ravenous Pig</a>.</p>

<p>But exploring Orlando as a city wasn&rsquo;t on the agenda during this trip. We had four days booked at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_Orlando">Universal Orlando</a>, probably our favourite theme park complex.</p>

<p>In particular, we were there for two things: visiting the London/Diagon Alley extension of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Wizarding_World_of_Harry_Potter_(Universal_Orlando_Resort)">The Wizarding World of Harry Potter</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halloween_Horror_Nights">Halloween Horror Nights</a>.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll talk about Halloween Horror Nights in another post. Here I&rsquo;ll sum up the new Harry Potter area in Universal Studios. The London/Diagon Alley extension opened <a href="http://www.themeparkinsider.com/flume/201407/4112/">earlier this summer</a>. In all, they&rsquo;ve done a very good job. You start in London – it looks like a bunch of generic London buildings stuck together. The most exciting one (for me) was the King&rsquo;s Cross replica.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/kings-x.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/kings-x.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">King&#8217;s Cross Station</div>
</div>


<p>I liked the fact that they used King&rsquo;s Cross (rather than the more gothic <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St_Pancras_railway_station">St Pancras station</a> that was used in the films). It&rsquo;s a really good replica of the station (it was my London terminus when we lived in Cambridge). The departure board has legitimate trains – I&rsquo;ve been through Finsbury Park many times.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/departure-board.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/departure-board.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Departure board</div>
</div>


<p>You can walk into Platform 9 &frac34; and catch the Hogwarts Express to Hogsmede (in Islands of Adventure).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/platform-934.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/platform-934.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Platform 9 3/4</div>
</div>


<p>The train ride is a lot of fun – the windows project your journey from London to Hogsmede. The train takes passengers back, with a different story, so make sure you ride it both ways. If you&rsquo;re short for time, we both preferred the London -> Hogsmede direction.</p>

<p>Diagon Alley itself is hidden behind an unassuming brick wall. So unassuming, we had to have it pointed out by a Universal employee. She saw our confused looks and whispered, &ldquo;You might want to check out that brick wall over there!&rdquo;</p>

<p>It opens up into a narrow alleyway with an imposing dragon perched at the far end. It&rsquo;s sat on top of Gringotts and it makes for a stunning visual introduction to the area.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/diagon-alley.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/diagon-alley.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Diagon Alley</div>
</div>


<p>Make sure to check out the side alleys – there&rsquo;s one to each side as you walk in. In particular, Nocturn Alley (on the left as you walk in) is a dark and spooky area where you can buy all the skull-shaped items you could ever dream of.</p>

<p>Anyway, onto the new ride: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_Potter_and_the_Escape_from_Gringotts">Escape from Gringotts</a>. We had high hopes – <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_Potter_and_the_Forbidden_Journey">The Forbidden Journey</a>, over in Hogsmede, is one of our favourite rides.</p>

<p>The line times are pretty hefty – we were lucky enough to get in pretty early on a Thursday with only 30 minutes to wait. For the rest of the weekend, it was at least 120 minutes. The queue area is neat – you walk into Gringotts and see the main banking area.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-entrance.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-entrance.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Entrance to Gringotts</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-hall.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-hall.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Main room</div>
</div>


<p>Along the hallway are animatronics of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magical_creatures_in_Harry_Potter#Goblins">goblin</a> bank tellers.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-men.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-men.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Goblin bankers</div>
</div>


<p>You walk past these into the vaults and back rooms of Gringotts.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-vaults.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-vaults.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Gringotts vaults</div>
</div>


<p>There&rsquo;s a weird break in the queue where you have your photo taken. I don&rsquo;t know why they do this – it&rsquo;s just against a plain background. Maybe it&rsquo;s because they didn&rsquo;t want to put a camera on the ride? Not a clue. But there&rsquo;s more queuing after that.</p>

<p>Then you&rsquo;re put in a &ldquo;lift&rdquo; that takes you into the deepest vault area. You then walk <em>up</em> some stairs, grab some 3D goggles, and enter a mine-cart-like-thing. It looks a little like the one from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Revenge_of_the_Mummy">Revenge of the Mummy</a>.</p>

<p>The ride is mostly large 3D projections following some half-arsed story about Voldemort. It is not an enjoyable ride. It fails in a couple of ways. To begin with, there&rsquo;s very little use of the track as a rollercoaster – there are maybe two small drops in total. It&rsquo;s definitely not an exciting ride, and makes me wonder why they decided to use a rollercoaster-style track without utilising any rollercoaster features.</p>

<p>Also, the ride is essentially a series of short 3D films. The great thing about The Forbidden Journey (or the older <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Amazing_Adventures_of_Spider-Man">Spider-man ride</a>) was that they seamlessly blended real-life features (animatronics, props, forced perspective) with pre-done projected segments. The problem with Gringotts (and the recently-opened <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transformers:_The_Ride">Transformers: The Ride</a>) is that there&rsquo;s no inventiveness – you just move from one projection to the next, and that&rsquo;s the adventure.</p>

<p>Anyway, we were pretty disappointed. We wanted to ride it again to see if it improved on second ride, but with 120 minute queues we weren&rsquo;t willing to wait. The good news is that the rest of the area (and the Hogwarts Express to Hogsmede) was really fun – and that&rsquo;s enough reason to go.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
