<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-04T17:16:51+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Museums in Amsterdam]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/04/amsterdam-museums/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-04T16:36:21+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/04/amsterdam-museums</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We toured the four main museums in Amsterdam: the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rijksmuseum">Rijksmuseum</a>, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Van_Gogh_Museum">Van Gogh Museum</a>, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anne_Frank_House">Anne Frank House</a> and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stedelijk_Museum_Amsterdam">Stedelijk Museum</a>.</p>

<p>The Rijksmuseum has recently undergone a huge rennovation, and opened in April 2013. It certainly shows – the internal atrium is beautiful and the layout is intuitive. Pro-tip: don&rsquo;t pay €5 for the museum audio guide! The museum has a free app for iPhone/iPod – with all the same information on it. Use that instead!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/rijksmuseum.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/rijksmuseum.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Rijksmuseum, canal-side</div>
</div>


<p>The app offers a 90-minute &ldquo;highlights&rdquo; tour, which we did. I could have spent more time in the Dutch masters area (on the second floor). The impressionist and romantic areas were a little less exciting. The museum itself is <em>packed</em>. Admittedly, we are in the middle of tourist season, but it was a Monday. It was difficult to get a quiet moment with any painting – but I guess that&rsquo;s what happens when a museum is closed for a while and it&rsquo;s the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_most_visited_art_museums_in_the_world">19th most visited museum in the world</a>.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a couple of super-famous paintings on the tour, the most famous being the Night Watch by Rembrandt. Of course, it was in an insanely-crowded room. It was pretty easy to get close, though.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/rijksmuseum-nightwatch.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/rijksmuseum-nightwatch.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Who watches the Night Watch?</div>
</div>


<p>The information cards they had were really useful. They circle particular elements of the painting, drawing out</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/rijksmuseum-carcosa.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/rijksmuseum-carcosa.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Please show me to Carcosa, creepy chandelier lady</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Touring Amsterdam]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/02/amsterdam/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-02T16:57:53+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/02/amsterdam</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was always a little ashamed that I&rsquo;d never visited Amsterdam. It&rsquo;s only a short flight from London and people always list it as a highlight of Europe. Hampton&rsquo;s parents were in Amsterdam for a week, so we decided to join them and find out what all the fuss was about.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/canal.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/canal.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Houses along the canal, a bridge, and cyclists</div>
</div>


<p>In a lot of ways, Amsterdam was exactly what I was expecting. Canals criss-crossed with beautiful bridges, cyclists going far too fast.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/touring.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/touring.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hampton and his Dad as we wandered around the canals</div>
</div>


<p>We decided to do a walking tour on foot. We stayed near the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leidseplein">Leidseplein</a>, and walking all the way to the center took about 40 minutes. We walked to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dam_Square">Dam Square</a>, the centre of the city. It was nice, but touristy. You had to pay to go in the church or the palace, and we skipped both of them.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/dam-palace.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/dam-palace.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Royal Palace in Dam</div>
</div>


<p>What I would recommend is taking a canal boat around the city. We used the <a href="https://www.canal.nl/en/canal-bus">Canal Bus</a>, which is advertised as a hop-on/hop-off tour. However we just used it to see the city from another angle.</p>

<p>It stopped at most of the standard things – Dam Square, the Anne Frank House, Rembrandt&rsquo;s House, etc. – but it was nice to see some other bits of the city. In particular, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EYE_Film_Institute_Netherlands">Eye Film Institute</a> had a beautiful building.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/eyefilm.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/eyefilm.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Eye Film Institute</div>
</div>


<p>It&rsquo;s across the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IJ_(Amsterdam)">IJ</a> (the main waterfront of Amsterdam) from most of the city, and it&rsquo;s something we wouldn&rsquo;t have seen by just walking.</p>

<p>Another pro-tip: walk around at dusk. Especially in the summer, it&rsquo;s so relaxed and the houses look inviting. There are often people having parties on boats and people dining along the canals.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/dusk.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/dusk.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Dusk over houses</div>
</div>


<p>There&rsquo;s definitely a lot more to the city than hookers and weed (although you can find those in certain areas if you must).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AnonymouS Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/30/anonymous-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-30T10:10:05+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/30/anonymous-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>Our time in Prague is almost at an end – today, we&#8217;re taking a flight to Amsterdam. We saved an intriguing bar for our last new experience in the cocktail world of Prague. <a href="http://www.anonymousbar.cz/cs"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">AnonymouS Bar</span></a> (their weird capitalisation, not mine) is off a small alley in the old town, and it is themed around the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gunpowder_Plot">gunpowder plot</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/V_for_Vendetta">V for Vendetta</a>, and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anonymous_(group)">Anonymous</a> movement.</p>

  <p>Inside, the bar is styled like the interior of V&#8217;s hideout in the comic book/film. It allows the use of comfortable chairs, but also brick-showing-through-plaster murals and classic portraits with faces replaced by the Guy Fawkes mask. It kind of reminded us (in the best way possible, as we&#8217;re theme park nerds) of a Universal Studios or Disney experience.</p>

  <p>The menu has a really great concept: a list of standard drinks on one page, paired up with an AnonymouS-bar twist on the classics. It was a goodway to quickly pick out a drink you&#8217;d be sure to like. I went for the St Marry&#8217;s Virus – again, that&#8217;s their weird spelling, and I&#8217;m not sure if it&#8217;s deliberate or not. It was a twist on the Piccadilly martini. The bartender came over with a biohazard box, which opened to reveal a giant syringe containing the cocktial.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-st-marrys.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-st-marrys.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">St Marry&#8217;s Virus</div>
  </div>

  <p>Hampton went for a take on a gimlet, and it was really delicious! I think they added cucumber and some other stuff.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-butterfly.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-butterfly.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">M. Butterfly</div>
  </div>

  <p>The menu, aside from the drink and liquor list, was pretty entertaining. They had neat explanation of their thought process behind the concept. As I was flicking through, I noticed there was a cocktail set apart from the rest, alone on the very first page. It didn&#8217;t have a description, aside from the old rhyme: &#8220;Remember, remember the fifth of November&#8230;&#8221; It was too puzzling not to get.</p>

  <p>Hampton got it after me, so I have photos of what it entailed. The bartender handed you a Guy Fawkes mask and took your photo.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-photo.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-photo.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">They had to find more film</div>
  </div>

  <p>After that, they make the drink. It involved lining a brandy snifter with liquor and setting it on fire. Once the fire had died down, they poured in a whisky-based old-fashioned-esque cocktail. They placed the photo on top to stop the smoke from the flames coming out.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-remember.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-remember.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Remember</div>
  </div>

  <p>Here are the photos of our night. It&#8217;s nice to have something to keep after a night out. Especially once you&#8217;ve had a few cocktails.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-polaroid.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-polaroid.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Ahh, memories!</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">The themeing theatricality of AnonymouS bar is great, but it&#8217;s really backed up by the delicious cocktails on offer.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">8.5</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[La Degustation]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/27/la-degustation/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-27T11:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/27/la-degustation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.ladegustation.cz/en/#index"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">La Degustation</span></a>, one of two restaurants in Prague to have <a href="http://www.viamichelin.com/web/Restaurants/Restaurants-Prague-_-Praha_hlavni_mesto-Czech_Republic?strLocid=31MzhkeDEwY05UQXVNRGczT0RFPWNNVFF1TkRJd05EWT0=">a Michelin star</a>, was our special treat as our time in Prague is coming to an end. Its slogan is &#8220;bohême bourgeoise,&#8221; which I found amusing.</p>

  <p>Inside, I don&#8217;t know if anything can be gothic minimalist, but I think that&#8217;s an accurate description. Arches ribbed the ceiling, and artfully-placed dim spotlights created wonderful shadows. The walls were bare and painted a light grey, and the furniture was all low-backed and dark wood. The windows onto the street had the restaurant&#8217;s signature checkered pattern.</p>

  <p>As we sat down, the waiter came over and gave us an envelope.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/envelope.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/envelope.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">We were handed an envelope</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/back-envelope.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/back-envelope.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The back of the envelope</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/contents.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/contents.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Open it to find the checkered pattern</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/menu.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/menu.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Two menu options</div>
  </div>

  <p>We went for the eleven-course menu, with wine pairings. It was definitely a lot of food, and I wish I hadn&#8217;t eaten so much of the delicious bread they brought. The menu focussed on Czech ingredients and dishes, but with modern, vaguely molecular-gastronomic twists. Apparently a lot of the inspiration for their dishes comes from a late-19th century Czech cookbook.</p>

  <p>I didn&#8217;t take pictures and I won&#8217;t bore you with a course-by-course detailing of everything. A couple of stand-out dishes, though: dijon mustard ice-cream with hot tomato sauce. The sauce was the perfect distillation of tomato flavour. Add that to the mustard (which wasn&#8217;t too spicy), plus the mixing of the hot sauce with the cold ice-cream and you get an incredible dish that&#8217;s not quite like anything I&#8217;ve had before.</p>

  <p>There was a foie gras course where the liver had been finely grated over wine jelly and pistachio. I&#8217;d never eaten foie gras grated before, and it really helped take away the heaviness you sometimes get. Then there was the beef tongue &#8220;signature dish.&#8221; </p>

  <p>I really enjoyed the wine pairings. They used mostly Czech wines, and it was nice to see the variety in types they produce here. There was also a great unfiltered Slovenian wine called <a href="http://www.scurek.com/www/index.php/en/wines/white-wines">Kontra</a>. The cheese course came with a delicious IPA from the <a href="http://www.beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/23493/">Matuška Brewery</a>.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">If you&#8217;re willing to splash out, this place is definitely worth it. It&#8217;s a modern take on Czech flavours and ingredients, and the courses are presented beautifully.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">9.3</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Touring the Jewish Quarter of Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/25/jewish-quarter-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-25T12:58:05+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/25/jewish-quarter-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Josefov">Jewish Quarter</a> (or Josefov) of Prague is in the Old Town, just north of the Old Town Square. We&rsquo;d been told that the <a href="http://www.jewishmuseum.cz/en/apinkas.htm">Pinkas Synagogue</a> was a must-see, so we set off on a visit without learning much about it. All I knew was that it&rsquo;s now a memorial to victims of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Holocaust">Holocaust</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Pinkas Synagogue from the outside</div>
</div>


<p>We arrived at lunchtime and the queue was really long and slow-moving. Not good.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-queue.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-queue.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Long queue waiting for tickets</div>
</div>


<p>However! We found an EXPERT WORK-AROUND for buying tickets without having to wait in line. Head slightly east on the same road and take the first left. You&rsquo;ll find <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Maiselova+38%2F15,+110+00+Praha-Praha+1,+Czech+Republic/@50.089592,14.4181715,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x470b94e8669ff2a5:0xb73abb80fc435169">a ticketing office</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ticket-office.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ticket-office.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Just around the corner – under 2 mins walk.</div>
</div>


<p>There was no queue and we got our tickets immediately. You can&rsquo;t buy a single ticket to see the synagogues/museums of Josefov individually – you have to buy a multi-attraction ticket. The most basic ticket was 300Kč (~$15) for four attractions: the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Jewish_Cemetery,_Prague">Old Jewish Cemetery</a>, the <a href="http://www.jewishmuseum.cz/en/aklaus.htm">Klausen Synagogue</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jewish_Ceremonial_Hall,_Prague">Ceremonial Hall</a>, and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_Synagogue_(Prague)">Spanish Synagogue</a>. You could pay 100Kč more if you wanted to see the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_New_Synagogue,_Prague">Old New Synagogue</a>, but we gave that one a miss. The ticket is valid over seven days, though, which is good if you don&rsquo;t have enough time to visit all the places in one day.</p>

<p>After we bought our tickets we went back to the Pinkas Synagogue and sailed past the line there to buy tickets.</p>

<p>The inside of the Pinkas Synagogue serves as a memorial to the 80,000 Bohemian and Moravian Jews that were victims of the Holocaust.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-room.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-room.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside the synagogue</div>
</div>


<p>There were about five rooms like the one above – and see those red and black, floor-to-ceiling patches that line the walls? Those are the victims&#8217; names, birth-dates and death-dates. Across the rooms they&rsquo;re written out like that, in letters maybe a centimetre high.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-names.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-names.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Names, births and deaths of victims</div>
</div>


<p>At first, you don&rsquo;t quite understand it. Then as you start reading, seeing the families grouped together, it&rsquo;s a little overwhelming. Especially when you see room after room of them. It was powerful stuff, and something I&rsquo;d recommend everyone do while they&rsquo;re in Prague.</p>

<p>After exiting the synagogue, you walk through the Old Jewish Cemetery. While not that large geographically, it apparently contains over 12,000 tombstones.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Old Jewish Cemetery</div>
</div>


<p>Needless to say, it was crowded with graves. The tombstones stuck out at all kinds of angles, and many were only just sticking out of the soil.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery2.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery2.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Another view of the cemetery</div>
</div>


<p>The cemetary exit leaves you just outside of Ceremonial Hall and the Klausen Synagogue. As we already had the multi-ticket, we decided to give them a visit.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Ceremonial Hall outside</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall-floor.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall-floor.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Ceremonial Hall tiled floor</div>
</div>


<p>The Ceremonial Hall used to be a kind of mortuary, so had a bunch of exhibits on the rituals surrounding death in Judaism. It was kind of interesting, but mostly just items in display cases.</p>

<p>The Klausen Synagogue was similar. Apart from the Pinkas Synagogue earlier on, I&rsquo;d never been inside a synagogue before. I&rsquo;m not quite sure what I was expecting from the inside of a synagogue, but I was kind of disappointed that it looked just like a Christian church.</p>

<p>Inside the main area of the Klausen Synagogue, there were display cases showing items relating to Judaism. I found it a little strange. I almost wanted the museum part and the religious-building part to be more separate. Maybe it&rsquo;s just because I wasn&rsquo;t expecting it to be so much of a museum.</p>

<p>After leaving the Klausen Synagogue, the route to the next stop on our ticket took us past the Old New Synagogue. I only learnt afterwards that it&rsquo;s Europe&rsquo;s oldest active synagogue. Apparently, its attic is also the storage place for the infamous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golem#The_classic_narrative:_The_Golem_of_Prague">Golem of Prague</a> (<em>spooky noises</em>).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/old-new.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/old-new.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Old New Synagogue</div>
</div>


<p>We continued walking, made a couple of quick turns, and found ourselves at the Spanish Synagogue. Not much to look at from the outside, inside it&rsquo;s absolutely stunning.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Spanish Synagogue interior</div>
</div>


<p>The walls are covered in intricate patterns, mostly using reds and golds. The Star of David appears in motifs everywhere, and I spent ages just following the patterns and their interplay across the walls. The central dome is beautiful and has a Star of David-shaped chandelier in the centre.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish-dome.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish-dome.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Dome of the Spanish Synagogue</div>
</div>


<p>Fun fact: it doesn&rsquo;t seem to be clear why it&rsquo;s called the Spanish Synagogue. One theory is that the interior design reminded people of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golden_age_of_Jewish_culture_in_Spain">&ldquo;Golden Age&rdquo;</a> of Judaism in Spain. Another theory is that it used to be a location for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romaniotes">Byzantine Jewish</a> worship, and that led to legends of the Iberian <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sephardi_Jews">Sephardi Jews</a> once worshipping there.</p>

<p>Like the Klausen Synagogue, the Spanish Synagogue is a museum as well as a religious building. I was mostly distracted by the detailing on the walls, but I did look at a couple of the display cases in the upper balconies. They were pretty interesting, detailing the history of Josefov across the centuries. If it hadn&rsquo;t been over 30ºC in there, I would have stayed longer.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m glad we ended up seeing more of the Jewish Quarter than just the Pinkas Synagogue, but I&rsquo;m not sure I&rsquo;d see the Klausen Synagogu and the Ceremonial Hall if I were pushed for time. I definitely found it more rewarding than most of Prague Castle, though. I made a <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/dir/Maiselova+38%2F15,+110+00+Praha,+Czech+Republic/Pinkas+Synagogue,+%C5%A0irok%C3%A1+23%2F3,+110+00+Praha,+Czech+Republic/Klausov%C3%A1+synagoga,+U+star%C3%A9ho+h%C5%99bitova+3a,+110+00+Praha-Josefov,+Czech+Republic/The+Old-New+Synagogue,+Maiselova+18,+110+01+Praha+1,+Czech+Republic/50.0900973,14.4211259/@50.090032,14.4178231,18z/data=!4m32!4m31!1m5!1m1!1s0x470b94e8669ff2a5:0xb73abb80fc435169!2m2!1d14.4181715!2d50.089592!1m5!1m1!1s0x470b94e85e9af185:0x294f2ae19539722d!2m2!1d14.416972!2d50.089277!1m5!1m1!1s0x470b94e877e558db:0xdd1a2cc59bf35380!2m2!1d14.417069!2d50.09002!1m10!1m1!1s0x470b94e868e5c8c9:0x94be0e2fdb884bfa!2m2!1d14.418567!2d50.090051!3m4!1m2!1d14.4190562!2d50.0899754!3s0x470b94e844b3b4d3:0x32c184f0e15a1660!1m0!3e2">map of the route we took</a> – but note that the bit from the Pinkas to Klausen is through the cemetery rather than around Maiselova.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orange Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/orange-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-23T10:33:48+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/orange-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.orangebar.cz/en/homepage.html"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Orange Bar</span></a> is pretty close by to us and has decent reviews. It&#8217;s a little tricky to find, down a couple of side-streets, but there&#8217;s a nice orange-shaped sign outside to let you know when you&#8217;re there.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/outside.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/outside.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">From the street</div>
  </div>

  <p>From the outside, it looks pretty normal, right? Inside, though, it reminded me of a bar in Dune or something. The only lights had orange filters, and all the walls were molded to give the appearance of being dug out of a cave.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/bar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/bar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The bar (I think the spice is kept on the top shelf)</div>
  </div>

  <p>The bar shelves were all integrated into the back wall. The other walls had fake columns with cubbies for desert plants.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/plants.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/plants.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Walls with plants</div>
  </div>

  <p>The cocktail list leaned heavily towards rum-based beach drinks – mai tais, piña coladas, zombies etc. There&#8217;s also a good list of classics, too. Hampton went for (of course) a manhattan. I tried out the mai tai but it was a little too sweet for me.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/cocktails.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/cocktails.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Manhattan and a mai tai</div>
  </div>

  <p>We were there during a massive thunderstorm and didn&#8217;t have umbrellas, so we stayed for another round (or two). The moscow mule was <em>much</em> better. Get that! It had a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physalis_peruviana">physalis</a> garnish too, which is awesome.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/moscow-mule.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/moscow-mule.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Moscow mule</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Orange bar has a neighbourhood feel and a fun theme. The drinks are sweet, but tasty, so I&#8217;d stick to non-tiki drinks (unless you&#8217;re a particular fan).</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">7.1</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hoffa, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/hoffa-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-23T10:32:20+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/hoffa-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>For some reason, there&#8217;s a bar in Prague named after <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jimmy_Hoffa">Jimmy Hoffa</a>, the American union leader who went missing in the 70s. Unfortunately, my lack of Czech skills (and poor Google translating) don&#8217;t help much with the &#8220;About&#8221; page on the <a href="http://hoffa.cz"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Hoffa</span></a> website.</p>

  <p>First and foremost: this is a non-smoking bar! Yay! That automatically gets you points in my book. Most bars have smoking and non-smoking areas, but that&#8217;s not quite the same. Location-wise, it&#8217;s on a little intersection near the main train station (so great for people-watching), and has big windows. The decor is neat – they have a massive trompe-l&#8217;œil mural on one side so it looks like you&#8217;re in a warehouse.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-mural.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-mural.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Mural in Hoffa</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-bar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-bar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The bar</div>
  </div>

  <p>They have mostly traditional drinks, with some specials on a chalkboard. The drink I had was pretty good, but nothing amazing. I went for a glass of Pimm&#8217;s as it was ridiculously hot outside.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-pimms.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-pimms.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Pimm&#8217;s!</div>
  </div>

  <p>They offer decent bar snacks, too. We got some tortilla chips with salsa and sour cream.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-tortillas.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-tortillas.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Tortilla chips with salsa and sour cream</div>
  </div>

  <p>We also got some hamburgers, which were amazing. They were juicy, cooked medium-rare, and had spicy-sweet secret sauce on them. Delicious!</p>

  <p>The bathroom doors were pretty neat, too.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-mural.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-bathroom.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Bathroom door</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">I can see us returning to this place for its relaxed atmosphere, neat interior, and reasonably-priced decent drinks. It seemed like a nice place to call your local.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">7.0</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zinc Lounge, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/21/zinc-lounge-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-21T11:52:10+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/21/zinc-lounge-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>After the underwhelming experience at <a href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/19/cloud-9-prague">Cloud 9</a>, I wanted to try out the bar at the other Prague-based Hilton: <a href="http://www.hiltonpragueoldtown.com/loungebar-en.html"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Zinc Lounge and Bar</span></a>, found in the <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Hilton+Prague+Old+Town/@50.088515,14.431864,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x63a407a250359dc7">Hilton Prague Old Town</a>. I wanted to see how it measured up, and in short: it was pretty bad. Please forgive me, Cloud 9, I didn&#8217;t realise your sister bar was so awful. I would have cut you some slack otherwise!</p>

  <p>The Hilton Prague Old Town is pretty easy to find compared with the other Hilton. It&#8217;s just off Náměstí Republiky, one of the main squares in the Old Town. The Zinc Bar and Lounge is just to the right as you come in. &#8220;Zinc&#8221; is also the name of the hotel restaurant, just behind the bar</p>

  <p>Inside, it&#8217;s decorated like a dreary hotel lobby. Leather seats and low, round wooden tables. Holey partitions of wood try to separate the actual hotel lobby from the bar. Despite their best efforts, we were still drinking around a bunch of people loudly chatting on Skype (I assume there&#8217;s free wi-fi in the lobby area) and wheeling their luggage around, waiting for their ride to the airport.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-bar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-bar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Zinc Bar</div>
  </div>

  <p>The menu consisted almost entirely of classic cocktails. There was nothing inventive or fancy like at Cloud 9. We stuck to our staples and got a gimlet and a manhattan. They were both OK – competently done and similar to what you could find at a lot of bars in Prague.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-cocktails.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-cocktails.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Drinks: gimlet and a manhattan</div>
  </div>

  <p>The thing is, these cocktails were 220Kč (~$11) each. And there was me going off on how expensive the Cloud 9 cocktails were, at 185Kč (~$9)! Like I said in the beginning, I&#8217;M SORRY CLOUD 9. The Cloud 9 cocktails were far more reasonably-priced (I still think they&#8217;re expensive, though). At least you get something different, innovative. At Zinc you get a standard cocktail that at another bar (say, Groove Bar) would be 100Kč (~$5).</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-interior.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-interior.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Hampton looking SUPREMELY DISAPPOINTED</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Put together the atmosphere of the hotel lobby with the fact that the drinks were exceedinly expensive for what they were, and you get a disappointing experience. I&#8217;d suggest venturing a little out of the hotel to find a better cocktail bar.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">4.6</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud 9, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/19/cloud-9-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-19T11:39:32+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/19/cloud-9-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.cloud9.cz/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Cloud 9</span></a> (or, in full, Cloud 9 Sky Bar & Lounge) is located in the <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/preview?safe=off&ie=UTF-8&fb=1&cid=4324379790027078551&q=Hilton+Prague+Hotel&ei=BVnGU-X9E-aV7Ab6loCQDQ&ved=0CMQBEPwSMAo">Hilton</a>, just east of the central Old Town district of Prague. It&#8217;s got pretty good reviews, most extolling the views over Prague. So, of course we had to go.</p>

  <p>Firstly: getting to the Hilton is surprisingly tricky. (<strong>NB</strong>: there are two Hiltons in Prague, the more central <a href="http://d1pa4et5htdsls.cloudfront.net/images/vfml/1/1/2/9/6/1/5/709926e0_prgothi_74095_s-original.jpg">Hilton Prague Old Town</a> and the <a href="http://www.hotels-in-czech.com/clfiles/photos/big/29-hilton-budova.jpg">Hilton Prague</a>. This is in the latter.) It&#8217;s strange how much Prague changes between the first and eighth districts. It quickly goes from windy cobblestone streets to broad roads and unfriendly pedestrian crossings. The Hilton itself takes up a whole square block, yet finding the right route to get there – even finding the right entrance to use – was confusing. We just about managed by following the tourists forming a trail on their way to the Old Town.</p>

  <p>Once you&#8217;ve found your way in (use the west entrance to the Hilton, and take a sharp right for the lift to the ninth floor), the views are the first thing that strike you. It was early evening as we came in, and the sun slowly setting gave some nice cloud patterns. However, I guess I was expecting more of a grand view of the <em>centre</em> of Prague. Instead, you get a beautiful view of the Allianz building next door.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-west.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-west.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The view west, towards the centre of Prague</div>
  </div>

  <p>I suppose I&#8217;m being a little harsh – you can just see the top of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_of_Our_Lady_before_T%C3%BDn">Church of Our Lady before Týn</a> on the left. </p>
  
  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-tyn.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-tyn.png">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">I found <span class="strike">Wally</span> the Church!</div>
  </div>

  <p>The north and east views are nicer – but more pastoral than the gothic spires I was imagining.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-north.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-north.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The view north</div>
  </div>

  <p>The bar itself was decorated like a hotel bar. Clean lines, mirrors everywhere, leather-backed chairs. They had a couple of outside seating areas, but these were filled up with hotel guests.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/bar-interior.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/bar-interior.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Interior of the bar.</div>
  </div>

  <p>Speaking of the clientele, I wasn&#8217;t too surprised to find it filled with tourists. It was early (7pm), the bar is tricky to find, and it&#8217;s a <em>hotel bar</em>, so you&#8217;re not going to get an authentic Czech experience. Even so, the groups of English/North American tourists asking the waitress to pronounce &#8220;Na zdraví!&#8221; (&#8220;Cheers!&#8221;) over and over was grating. But onto the cocktails!</p>

  <p>The menu was interesting, and had a good mix of classics plus some that had been made up in the bar. Their inventions all had new-agey, etherial names like SUNSHINE and MYSTIC and DESIRE. Their most famous cocktail (according to them, at least) is the CHARISMA.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Charisma</div>
  </div>

  <p>The Charisma is so famous that it has intricate instructions for drinking.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma-instructions.jpg">
      </a><img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma-instructions
      .jpg">
    <div class="alt">Instructions for drinking</div>
  </div>

  <p>Despite that, you still look like a wally drinking something with a giant chili pepper sticking out of it.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma-drinking.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma-drinking.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Looking suave</div>
  </div>

  <p>My drinks weren&#8217;t nearly as exciting. They didn&#8217;t even have instructions on how to drink them. Sad times.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/mystic.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/mystic.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Mystic</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/desire.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/desire.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Desire (the thumbs up is for size reference, not endorsement)</div>
  </div>

  <p>The Mystic was a vodka-ginger-lime-sugar thing and was delicious. The Desire, on the other hand, tasted like what I imagine pot pourri tastes like (i.e. gross).</p>

  <p>The bar snacks were delicious. We never really found out what they were, due to the language barrier, but it seemed to be some kind of caramel-coated peanut in a crispy shell dusted in salt and dried tomato (? maybe). We scarfed them down in about five minutes.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/bar-snack.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/bar-snack.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Bar snacks</div>
  </div>

  <p>The prices were pretty crazy. I&#8217;m not sure if it&#8217;s because it&#8217;s in a hotel or because it has views (probably a little of both), it ran to about 185Kč (~$9) a drink. That may not sound like much, but they were easily the priciest cocktails we&#8217;ve had in Prague and the previous holder of that title was around 145Kč (~$7).</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">For a hotel bar, Cloud 9 is pretty decent. You have good views of Prague and some tasty cocktails. The hassle of finding it plus the prices mean it&#8217;s not really worthwhile to go unless you&#8217;re staying at the Hilton.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">6.3</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

  <p><strong>UPDATE</strong>: I went to the bar in the other Hilton and turns out, it was <a href="">way worse</a>.</p>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bugsy's Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/17/bugsys-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-17T10:37:25+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/17/bugsys-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">
  <p>We moved to a (slightly) different area of Prague the other day. I was pretty excited because hey, there&#8217;ll be a whole new bunch of cocktail bars to go to! Looking online, it seemed like <a href="http://www.bugsysbar.cz/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Bugsy&#8217;s Bar</span></a> is one of the nicer cocktail bars in Prague. If you like <a href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/20/hemingway-bar-prague">Hemmingway</a>, Foursquare said, you&#8217;d like Bugsy&#8217;s. Their website is very slick – look how dapper the bartenders are, with their bow-ties and braces! Anyway, we gave it a shot. We weaved our way through old town street, went past a scary bouncer and down into a basement where the only lighting seemed to come from neon-pink spotlights pointed at the ceiling.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-interior.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-interior.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Inside Bugsy&#8217;s</div>
  </div>

  <p>The crowd was&#8230; strange. Everyone was dressed as if they were in a club. Short skirts and heels for women, blazers and super-shiny shoes for the guys. When we walked out later that evening, we realised we must be in the &#8220;club&#8221; district, as every other doorway had a bouncer and a line of people waiting to get in. Maybe Bugsy&#8217;s is more of a pre-club venue?</p>

  <p>When we sat down, we were presented with one of the most amazing drink menus I&#8217;ve seen. It&#8217;s a thick book designed as a graphic novel. The cocktails are split into broad categories, and each category has a beautiful double-page spread listing out the cocktails followed by a few pages of a story. We follow a single character through a noir scene (for classic cocktails), a Caribbean adventure (for rum cocktails), a scene with Batman (for &#8220;Gotham Cocktails,&#8221; whatever they are), and so on. There was even a page for mocktails where our hero ended up being pulled over and passing a breathalyser test.</p>

  <p>Anyway, the *range* of cocktails (despite the menu) was pretty disappointing. Nearly all were either classics, or vague variations on rum cocktails. I got a gin fizz and Hampton a vesper.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-vesper.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-vesper.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Vesper</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-ginfizz.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-ginfizz.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Gin fizz. It came with a bunch of&#8230; flowers? Berries? Something on top.</div>
  </div>

  <p>For a bar snack, the server gave us this shot-glass of things that looked like undercooked chips. Turns out they were some kind of string-cheese that had been rolled in spices or something? It was super-weird.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-cheese.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-cheese.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Weird cheese</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Overall, I was pretty disappointed, to be honest. That plus my confusion (or their confusion) of what the bar <em>was</em>. The cocktails were pretty high-end, and not cheap – which suggests an upscale bar. Yet mix that with the disco soundtrack, weird pink lighting everywhere, and about-to-go-clubbing crowd and I didn&#8217;t really want to spend a lot of time there.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">3.4</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black Angel's Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/17/black-angels-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-17T10:35:09+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/17/black-angels-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">
  <p><a href="http://www.blackangelsbar.cz/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Black Angel&#8217;s Bar</span></a> was recomended to us by a number of people – both bartenders and general cocktail-lovers. It&#8217;s in a basement just off the old town square, underneath a hotel. As we were taken down to the bar, we were warned about a long list of &#8220;no nos&#8221;: no cameras, no hats, no speaking too loud. It was a weird way to be introduced to a bar.</p>

  <p>The cocktails were inventive and presented well. They had a broad menu – a bunch of famous bartenders (I can&#8217;t vouch for their renown as I hadn&#8217;t heard of any of them. Saying that, I don&#8217;t know if I <em>could</em> name a famous bartender.) came up with a list of drinks. There&#8217;s a lot of award-winning cocktails in there too. I had a couple of pre-prohibition ones, which were delicious.

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Despite the cocktails being great, there was something a little off about the place. I&#8217;m not sure if it was the number of tourists (it is just off the main square, after all) or the man at the piano playing the theme song to Forrest Gump (?!), but it wasn&#8217;t as enjoyable of an experience as I thought it would be.</span></p>

  <p>Oh, and watch out for the bathrooms. They charge for their use for non-customers. I got confused and paid the person, but turns out that wasn&#8217;t necessary. (There was a sign saying &#8220;No charge for guests,&#8221; but I assumed they meant guests of the hotel.)</p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">6.8</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sansho, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/15/sansho-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-15T13:25:28+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/15/sansho-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>We asked for recommendations for the best retaurant in Prague and were told that <a href="http://www.sansho.cz/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Sansho</span></a> was the place to go. Most of the places I found online described it as Czech-Asian fusion, which sounded too weird to pass up. Plus, it was our <a href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/26/the-anniversary-question">third first-year anniversary</a> so we decided to book a table.</p>

  <p>It&#8217;s in the north of the Old Town, on a <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Sansho/@50.091722,14.43483,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0xe3da7dc930221279">beautiful square</a> right next to this amazing church.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/church.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/church.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Church outside – notice the creepy bird installation on the tower</div>
  </div>

  <p>Apparently you can eat outside during the daytime, but it was a little chilly so we ate in. The interior was pretty sparse, and reminded me of <a href="http://www.suppenkuche.com/">Suppenküche</a> in San Francisco. There were long tables with benches for mixed group dining, as well as a couple of individual tables. The servers could have been from San Francisco, too. They were all in plaid shirts and may have just wandered in off Valencia Street.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/restaurant.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/restaurant.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Interior of the restaurant</div>
  </div>

  <p>For dinner, the only option you have is the set menu, which is fine by us. I love not having to decide what I&#8217;m going to eat. Each course came for the two of us to share. The set menu changes every night. What&#8217;s weird was that other tables didn&#8217;t get the same set menu that we did – some had the same dishes in a different order, some had a much different menu. It didn&#8217;t seem to be dictated by any dietary requirements, so I can&#8217;t quite figure it out. Anyway, onto the food.</p>

  <p>The first two courses were fish. There was a salmon sashimi, which was kinda standard. Then there was a soft-shell crab slider. It was really good. The bun had a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cha_siu_bao">steamed bun</a> texture which went great with the crispy crab. There was a little too much wasabi on it for my taste, but whatever.</p> 

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/salmon.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/salmon.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">One: Salmon sashimi with soy and red peppercorns</div>
  </div>
  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/crab.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/crab.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Two: Soft-shell crab slider with wasabi cream (what&#8217;s up with the doily, amirite?)</div>
  </div>

  <p>Then there was a salad course: asparagus with ginger dressing and a crispy egg. I didn&#8217;t get the egg bit, but the asparagus with ginger was great. I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve ever had asparagus with more Asian-inspired flavours before. I guess this was the only thing that I could identify as really Czech-Asian fusion. Following the salad there were some gyoza, which were tasty but nothing special. (Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I love gyoza, but they&#8217;re like crème brûlée to me: if you&#8217;re competent enough to make it, it&#8217;s gonna be delicious.)</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/asparagus.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/asparagus.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Three: Asparagus and ginger salad with a crispy egg</div>
  </div>
  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/gyoza.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/gyoza.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Four: Pork and shrimp gyoza </div>
  </div>

  <p>Next up were my favourite two dishes. First there was a tender pork belly with chunks of watermelon. The pork belly had a sticky, sweet sauce on the outside which melted perfectly with the watermelon. Then there was a panang-style curry with some chili jam. It was served with some bread, sticky rice and a papaya salad. The curry had a strange texture, and the server explained that it was made up of &#8220;everything else from the pig.&#8221;</p>

  <p>Apparently the restaurant is a &#8220;whole animal&#8221; restaurant. There was a chalk-board sign out front explaining this. Up until this point of the meal – aside from the whole crab slider – there wasn&#8217;t much evidence of the &#8220;whole animal&#8221; philosophy. But I guess getting a curry with &#8220;everything else&#8221; in it counts.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/pork.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/pork.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Five: Pork belly with watermelon</div>
  </div>
  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/panang.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/panang.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Six: Pork panang with chili jam</div>
  </div>

  <p>Here&#8217;s another thing I&#8217;m a sucker for: dessert taster plates. I can never decide if I should get the sticky toffee pudding (it might be too heavy!) or the sorbet (it&#8217;s such a dull option!) or the apple pie (it might be too bland!). Every restaurant should have a dessert taster plate so I can eat all the desserts without feeling guilty.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/dessert.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/dessert.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Seven: Cookie with peanut ice-cream; cheesecake; sticky toffee pudding</div>
  </div>

  <p>The sticky toffee pudding was the favourite, but the cookie/peanut ice-cream came a close second.</p>

  <p>The seven courses and came out at about 1000Kč (~$50) per person, so pretty pricey for Prague. Plus they did this thing that I&#8217;ve noticed a lot of restaurants do here, which is give you something without you asking, then charge you for it. It&#8217;s happened with bread and jugs of water a bunch of times. I kind of assume that if something&#8217;s placed down on the table and I haven&#8217;t specifically asked for it, it&#8217;s going to be free. I don&#8217;t know if this is just a traditional thing or what, but I haven&#8217;t noticed it elsewhere in Europe really.</p>

  <p>All in all, <span itemprop="summary">Sansho is a great place for a special meal, with some inventive twists on Asian cuisine.</span> If you&#8217;re here for a special occasion and want something a little out of the ordinary, I&#8217;d recommend it. Just make sure you&#8217;re prepared for the bill.</p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">7.8</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Absinthe Tasting in Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/11/absinthe-tasting-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-11T14:38:26+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/11/absinthe-tasting-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>I&#8217;d read recently about how <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Absinthe">absinthe</a> was having a resurgence in popularity, especially in Prague. While we&#8217;re here, we decided to book a tasting with <a href="http://absinthe-prague.com"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Absinthe Prague</span></a>.</p>

  <p>I&#8217;d had absinthe before in London, and I remembered enjoying it despite not liking anise-flavoured things. I was looking forward to tasting a range of absinthes to see if I could taste any differences.</p>

  <p>The tasting itself is in the basement of <a href="http://groovebar.cz/">Groove Bar</a>, a trendy cocktail bar <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Groove+Bar/@50.080446,14.416966,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x470b94f1c418d2a1:0xe8a4fa7d2309d51f">just off the river</a>. The host is Aaron Johns, an ex-pat living in Prague who definitely knows his stuff – both about absinthe and beer (he runs a <a href="http://tastelocalbeer.com/">local beer tour</a>, too). He gave a lot of interesting history on absinthe, most of which I had no clue about. He explained in detail all about how it&#8217;s made, why it&#8217;s made that way, and even about the ban. He was great at answering questions, too.</p>

  <p>The ritual of drinking absinthe was enjoyable to learn about and even more fun to do – the sugar cube, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ouzo_effect">louche</a>, the absinthe spoon all came together to produce a great experience. You get a little absinthe in a glass, then balance the spoon over the top. Then you place a sugar cube on the spoon and drip ice-cold water onto the sugar until there&#8217;s a ratio of about five parts water to one part absinthe. As you drip the water in, the absinthe goes from clear to cloudy (the &#8220;louche&#8221;). At that point it&#8217;s ready to drink.</p>

  <p>The tasting covered six absinthes – two each from France, Switzerland and the Czech Republic. They all had unique characters and it was a lot of fun comparing notes with what others thought.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/absinthe.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/absinthe.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The absinthes we tasted</div>
  </div>

  <p>We started out with a Swiss &#8220;le bleu&#8221; style – it was colourless rather than the vivid green usually associated with absinthe. During the louche it had a slight blue tint to it. The anise flavour was pretty strong, and that put me off a little.</p>

  <p>We then moved onto two &#8220;classic&#8221; absinthes – one French and one Swiss. They were both heavier on the wormwood, and less on the anise flavour. The French one, made by Pernod, was quite nice. The <a href="http://absinthe-prague.com/products/absinthe-roquette-1797/">Roqeutte 1797</a> was apparently based on a recipe from the original inventor of absinthe. It had a really complex palate, having hints of citrus as well as the other anise/wormwood flavours. It was a little intense for me.</p>

  <p>My two favourites were the unconventional absinthes. Both produced in the Czech Republic, one was based on a honey liquor and one was from an American recipe. The honey one didn&#8217;t even need sugar added, and it went down really smoothly. It almost tasted like a cocktail. The American-recipe absinthe, <a href="http://absinthe-prague.com/products/absinthe-butterfly/">Butterfly</a>, had almost a gin-like flavour. Perhaps I enjoyed it so much because it had flavours more like a liquor I was used to?</p>

  <p>The last absinthe was French: <a href="http://absinthe-prague.com/products/la-grenouille-by-zufanek/">La Grenouille</a>. I was glad it was saved to the end, cause it had a very intense flavour.</p>

  <p>We ended up learning a lot about absinthe (such as what absinthe actually means, and the difference between absinthe and absinth) – it was a super-entertaining evening. The pours weren&#8217;t too heavy, so we weren&#8217;t blasted by the time we finished. It also gave both Hampton and me a deeper appreciation (and understanding) of the drink. In fact, the next night, we both ordered absinthe off the menu.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Absinthe Prague is great, and something you should definitely do if you&#8217;re seeking out a unique, informative evening with some tasty spirits.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">8.8</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day Trip to Kutná Hora]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/07/day-trip-to-kutna-hora/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-07T17:44:03+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/07/day-trip-to-kutna-hora</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Prague has excellent rail connections to many smaller cities and towns in the Czech Republic. Taking day (or weekend) trips, especially if you&rsquo;re staying in Prague for an extended time, is pretty easy. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kutn%C3%A1_Hora">Kutná Hora</a> was our first destination.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://www.cd.cz/en/">website for the Czech rail system</a> is great – it gave detailed times and information on the trains, all in English. From Prague, there were direct trains to Kutná Hora every two hours or so. As our timing didn&rsquo;t line up, we took a train to Kolín, then transferred. Pro tip: jot down the final destination of your planned train. It won&rsquo;t be Kutná Hora! We ended up just following the other tourists. The journey took about an hour total, and ended up at Kutná Hora hl. n., the main train station in the town. (The journey back was a bit worse, but more on that later.)</p>

<p>Kutná Hora hl. n is close (about a 10 minute walk) to the Sedlec end of the town. In Sedlec (a small suburb of Kutná Hora) are two famous sites: the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sedlec_Ossuary">Sedlec Ossuary</a> and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_of_the_Assumption_of_Our_Lady_and_Saint_John_the_Baptist">Church of the Assumption of Our Lady</a>. I&rsquo;d heard of the Ossuary before, and that was the main reason we were in the town.</p>

<p>Getting to the ossuary was pretty simple – there were some signs pointing in the right direction (follow those labelled &ldquo;Kostnice&rdquo;). When you get to the ossuary, you can buy a ticket for up to four attractions: the ossuary and the Church of Our Lady (both in Sedlec), and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._Barbara%27s_Church,_Kutn%C3%A1_Hora">Church of St Barbara</a> and the Jesuit College (in the Kutná Hora town centre). The Jesuit College was closed on Mondays so we didn&rsquo;t go. The admission was 160Kč (~$8) for the three attractions.</p>

<p>The ossuary was neat. It was a lot smaller than I was expecting – basically one room, with a tonne of bones. It was creepy, but the number of tourists taking photos in there made it feel more like a room in the <a href="http://dedicatedtodlp.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/potc-queue1.jpg">Pirates of the Caribbean queue</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/bones.png">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/bones.png">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Bones, skull and crossbones, bone chandelier, bone signature.</div>
</div>


<p>They hand out laminated sheets with some information on them, so you get a little historical information. However, I&rsquo;d recommend either loading up Wikipedia or having it on your phone for more detail.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/bone-arms.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/bone-arms.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Coat of Arms in bones, cause, y&#8217;know, why not?</div>
</div>


<p>After the ossuary, we went to the Church of the Assumption of Our Lady. We were the only people in there. It was a little strange – I&rsquo;ve not really been in a Gothic-looking cathedral where all the walls are painted beige/yellow.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/church-of-our-lady.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/church-of-our-lady.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Church of the Assumption of Our Lady</div>
</div>


<p>Aside from a couple of <a href="http://www.onestepinto.com/gallery/Kutna%20Hora/DSC_4303_Kutna_OSI.jpg">garishly-dressed relics</a> it was pretty dull. I wouldn&rsquo;t recommend going but it&rsquo;s a bit of a waste as you walk right by it heading into town from the ossuary.</p>

<p>There are supposedly a number of buses that go from the ossuary into the centre, but we decided we&rsquo;d walk it. The best thing I can say about <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/dir/Sedlec+Ossuary,+Z%C3%A1meck%C3%A1,+284+03+Kutn%C3%A1+Hora,+Czech+Republic/St+Barbara's+Church,+Barborsk%C3%A1,+284+01+Kutn%C3%A1+Hora,+Czech+Republic/@49.9533462,15.2670308,15z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m14!4m13!1m5!1m1!1s0x470c40fc635ac54f:0x320cc9caa5f1508e!2m2!1d15.288043!2d49.961782!1m5!1m1!1s0x470c41a6cd710ae9:0xa19ced0f3eeca1db!2m2!1d15.26362!2d49.944911!3e2">the walk from Sedlec into Kutná Hora proper</a> is that it was about 40 minutes and got us a fair few steps on our fitbits. The walk is mainly through industrial and suburban parts of the town, and for the most part there&rsquo;s not much to look at. However, once you get into the centre itself, Kutná Hora is gorgeous.</p>

<p>There are a number of winding cobblestone back-streets with beautiful buildings. I think we could have spent a few hours just wandering around the town. We had a quick lunch at <a href="http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g274701-d1570760-Reviews-Restaurant_Cafe_Harmonia-Kutna_Hora_Central_Bohemian_Region_Bohemia.html">Café Harmonia</a>, which had amazing gnocchi. Then we headed for the next church on our list: St Barbara&rsquo;s.</p>

<p>The walk up to the cathedral was beautiful – there&rsquo;s a promenade-type thing with statues along it that reminded us of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Bridge">Charles Bridge</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/walk-to-cathedral.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/walk-to-cathedral.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Walking towards St Barbara&#8217;s</div>
</div>


<p>From the promenade you get a great view looking over Kutná Hora.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/view.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/view.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">View over Kutná Hora</div>
</div>


<p>Inside, St Barbara&rsquo;s was amazing. Much better than the Church of the Assumption of Our Lady.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/st-barbaras.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/st-barbaras.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Beautiful gothic interior.</div>
</div>


<p>There were murals all along the apse and the sides of the nave.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/apse-mural.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/apse-mural.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Mural in the apse</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/nave-mural.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/nave-mural.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">14th century mural at the back of the nave</div>
</div>


<p>There were a few stained glass windows from the 1910s, which were neat. The one which I found interesting was from 2013. I find modern stained glass intriguiging as it&rsquo;s not really a standard modern art form (aside from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gilbert_%26_George">Gilbert and George</a>).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/stained-window.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/stained-window.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Stained glass window from 2013</div>
</div>


<p>After we had explored the cathedral, we started our journey back to Prague. Rather than walk the 40 minutes back to Kutná Hora hl. n., we went to the station in the centre of town – Kutná Hora město. It&rsquo;s tiny and rural, without any real platforms. There&rsquo;s a shuttle train that runs between this station and the main station. When we arrived, the next train was in 40 minutes(!), and we didn&rsquo;t have much choice but to wait for it. We changed at the main station to a train to Kolín. From Kolín to Prague we ended up on the Berlin train, an EC-class train. It was slightly nicer than the R-class we took on the way there, but not by much. It ended up taking us about two hours for the return journey. I&rsquo;d recommend timing your trip back carefully.</p>

<p>All in all it was a pretty nice day trip. If you&rsquo;re travelling around the Czech Republic, or you&rsquo;re staying in Prague for a while and want to get out of the city, it&rsquo;s a fun thing to do.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/01/prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-01T14:43:53+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/01/prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve heard many people say how much they like Prague. I&rsquo;ve also heard many people say how much charm Prague has lost since the mid-90s, how it&rsquo;s now filled with tourists. I wasn&rsquo;t quite sure what to expect. Would it be inviting and elegant, or a tourist-trap nightmare?</p>

<p>Well, we&rsquo;ve been here for three weeks, and I can safely say we both love the city. We love it so much we&rsquo;re planning on extending our time here until the end of July. It&rsquo;s got a mix of many things we enjoy about other European cities: the architectural beauty of Paris, the efficient transit of Berlin, the edginess (and cheapness) of Gdańsk. Plus, as I <a href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/20/hemingway-bar-prague">mentioned previously</a>, it has great cocktails.</p>

<p>The first seven days we were here, four nights had fireworks displays. There was a <a href="http://unitedislands.cz/">free music festival</a> the other weekend. There was <a href="http://www.prazskamuzejninoc.cz/">Prague Museum Night</a>, where museums stayed open until late at night. There&rsquo;s usually an open-air concert on <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/St%C5%99eleck%C3%BD+ostrov/@50.08048,14.410501,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x20fab08b45c47614">this island in the Vltava</a>. It seems like there&rsquo;s always something happening, and I think that&rsquo;s one of the main reasons we&rsquo;ve been drawn to Prague as a livable city.</p>

<p>Having said all of that&hellip; there are a tonne of tourists in certain areas – and this is where I maybe see why some people say Prague has lost its charm. We are (thankfully) staying about 10 minutes&#8217; walk from the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Town_Square_(Prague)">Old Town Square</a>. We can easily get there if we want to see the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prague_Orloj">Astronomical Clock</a> chime, but we&rsquo;re not trapped by the tourists.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/oldtownsq.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/oldtownsq.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">All the tourists, ever</div>
</div>


<p>It&rsquo;s overwhelming, for sure. Cross into the Old Town and you pretty much hear only English being spoken. If you&rsquo;re thinking of staying in Prague, I&rsquo;d try and avoid that area if possible. The city is extremely walkable, so staying a little outside the centre shouldn&rsquo;t be a problem. We&rsquo;re just south of Národní, which is perfect.</p>

<p>Anyway, I&rsquo;ve jotted down some thoughts on the tourist-type stuff we&rsquo;ve done.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The first thing we did, and the first thing I&rsquo;d suggest doing, is a self-guided walking tour. I&rsquo;ve been thoroughly impressed with the Rick Steves walking tours we&rsquo;ve done in previous cities, and his <a href="https://www.ricksteves.com/watch-read-listen/audio/audio-tours/eastern-europe">Prague city walk tour</a> was no different. The tour is available as a free podcast and takes about two or three hours. The recording itself is just over one hour, but we stopped in museums and cafés as we went.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/ourladyoftyn.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/ourladyoftyn.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Listening to Rick in the Old Town Square</div>
</div>


<p>The tour covers a lot of the history of not just Prague, but the Czech Republic as a whole. I was completely ignorant of the recent history of the country and found the descriptions of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jan_Palach">Jan Palach&rsquo;s suicide</a> and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Velvet_Revolution">Velvet Revolution</a> quite stirring. You end up seeing all the main sights of Prague, which is great to orientate yourself. You can then go back and check out places that you find interesting on a different day (or stop along the way, as we did).</p>

<p>Another pretty common tourist thing to visit is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prague_castle">Prague Castle</a>, which you can see from most places in Prague. We decided to foolishly climb up. I would not recommend it – it&rsquo;s a pretty steep climb. Take transit there instead!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/viewfromcastle.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/viewfromcastle.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Those are the steps we had to climb up</div>
</div>


<p>The castle itself is apparently one of the largest castle complexes in the world. It&rsquo;s the seat of the President of the Czech Republic and has a bunch of government offices too. It&rsquo;s pretty cool, but&hellip; I wouldn&rsquo;t necessarily recommend it if you&rsquo;re only here for a couple of days.</p>

<p>There are a couple of ticket options – one has four of the major sights, the other has all ten of them. We went for the four-sight option, which was plenty. The audioguides were all out of battery (?!) when we went on a Monday, so that meant we didn&rsquo;t get quite as much information out of our visit. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._Vitus_Cathedral">St Vitus&#8217; Cathedral</a> was the highlight by a long shot. It had some gorgeous art nouveau stained glass windows.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/stvitusstainedglass.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/stvitusstainedglass.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Stained glass windows by Alphonse Mucha</div>
</div>


<p>The other attractions (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._George%27s_Basilica,_Prague">St George&rsquo;s Basilica</a>, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Royal_Palace_(Prague)">Old Royal Palace</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golden_Lane">Golden Lane</a>) were&hellip; not as impressive. The Basilica had some interesting old murals, the Old Royal Palace had the infamous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Defenestrations_of_Prague">defenestration</a> window. Golden Lane was just a bunch of tourist shops, so I&rsquo;m not sure why it was included as an &ldquo;attraction&rdquo; in the ticket price.</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pet%C5%99%C3%ADn">Petřín Hill</a> is another imposing feature on the Prague skyline. We took the funicular to the top, which Hampton enjoyed because he loves funiculars. Apart from that, there wasn&rsquo;t much up there. Looking at the hill, it&rsquo;s covered in trees. We didn&rsquo;t quite realise that that meant there&rsquo;d be no view from the top of the hill. All you can see from up there is forest, pretty much. You could pay 100Kč or so (~$5) to go up a replica of the Eiffel Tower, which I&rsquo;m sure had better views, but we decided to spend our money instead on an old mirror maze.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/houseofmirrors.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/houseofmirrors.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">19th century mirror maze</div>
</div>


<p>The walk down is pleasant, so if it&rsquo;s a nice day I&rsquo;d recommend taking a trip.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s about all the tourist stuff we have done. Like I said, we&rsquo;ve mostly enjoyed the non-tourist stuff here. It&rsquo;s a great city to explore, especially with the number of parks for lazing and the random outdoor concerts we&rsquo;ve experienced. A great site we&rsquo;ve been using is <a href="http://www.expats.cz/">Expats.cz</a>, which has a list of events going on every day.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Anniversary Question: Civil Unions and Same-Sex Marriage]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/26/the-anniversary-question/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-26T12:02:36+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/26/the-anniversary-question</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is the one-year anniversary of two historic decisions by the Supreme Court. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_v._Windsor">United States v. Windsor</a> permitted federal recognition of same-sex marriages, and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hollingsworth_v._Perry">Hollingsworth v. Perry</a> allowed same-sex marriages in California to resume. Here&rsquo;s us on the front page of the New York Times website one year ago today:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/marriage/nytimes.png">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/marriage/nytimes.png">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">26th June 2013 – that&#8217;s us in the top left!</div>
</div>


<p>It was a great moment, and soon afterwards we got married in San Francisco city hall. This caused some confusion around our friends, as up to that point we introduced ourselves as a married couple. Weren&rsquo;t we already married? Why did we need to get married a second time?</p>

<p>Even now, when we are asked, &ldquo;how long have you been together?&rdquo; or &ldquo;when&rsquo;s your anniversary?&rdquo; there are a number of different answers we could give. We&rsquo;re always eager to educate people about our situation, and so I thought I&rsquo;d write some of it down to reach a wider audience. Hopefully it will help people understand why the issue of same-sex marriage is important, the stuggles we&rsquo;ve been through as a couple, and what an unprecedented legal case we are.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Anniversary One: Civil Partnership</h2>

<p>On 24th October, 2009, we entered into a civil partnership in Cambridge, England. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Civil_partnership_in_the_United_Kingdom">Civil partnerships</a> (also known as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Civil_union">civil unions</a> elsewhere) were introduced in the UK in 2004. They offered all the same rights as a civil marriage, but just called something different.</p>

<p>(Hampton once snarkily asked &ldquo;Oh, so it&rsquo;s like they&rsquo;re <em>separate but equal</em>, right?&rdquo; and I eagerly agreed, not being familiar with the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Separate_but_equal">US legal term</a>.)</p>

<p>Civil partnerships are often the first step a country takes in offering rights to same-sex couples who would like to commit to each other – a <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/27/ginsburg-doma_n_2966548.html">skim milk marriage</a>. A number of countries introduced them before then proceeding to same-sex marriage, and today in many places (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Same-sex_unions_in_the_United_States#States_with_Civil_unions_.28table.29">certain states in the US</a>, for example) they are the only way a same-sex couple can be recognised by the government. They range from offering a few cohabitation rights to all the rights an opposite-sex couple would expect when they become married. Thankfully, the UK had one of the more encompassing civil partnerships.</p>

<p>In the UK you can only get a civil partnership in a council office (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cambridgeshire_County_Council#mediaviewer/File:Shire_Hall,_Cambridge_-_geograph.org.uk_-_84489.jpg">this is Cambridge&rsquo;s</a>). It&rsquo;s not a pretty building, so we decided to do it with just us and our witnesses (my dad and my brother). It was in tiny office and was over in about five minutes. We read out the legally-required pre-written lines, signed some paper, and we were set.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/marriage/civilpartnership.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/marriage/civilpartnership.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Our Civil Partnership certificate</div>
</div>


<p>This then became an important date for Hampton&rsquo;s immigration paperwork, so one we have to remember (or at least look up) whenever we&rsquo;re entering the UK.</p>

<h2>Anniversary Two: A Celebration</h2>

<p>Soon after our civil partnership ceremony, on 11th November 2009, we had a gathering of our friends and family for a celebration. We went to <a href="http://www.midsummerhouse.co.uk/">Midsummer House</a>, a fancy restaurant in Cambridge. Twelve people attended (including us) – both of our immediate families, and some of our closest friends.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/marriage/uk-couple.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/marriage/uk-couple.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">I should have got a hair cut</div>
</div>


<p>We had written some short vows to say to each other. Before the meal we had Hampton&rsquo;s dad do a little ceremony where we read them out in front of our families.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/marriage/uk-vows.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/marriage/uk-vows.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Saying our vows</div>
</div>


<p>To us, this is our most important anniversary. We stood up in front of everyone and made a new, joined family by committing ourselves to each other. 11/11 is when we celebrate our anniversary by going out for a meal or whatever. If you ask how long we&rsquo;ve been married – we&rsquo;ll probably count from this date. Which is strange, as it&rsquo;s the least legally-binding of our anniversaries.</p>

<h2>Anniversary Three: Full Marriage</h2>

<p>Jump to 2013 – three and a half years into our partnership and things get much better for same-sex couples, but also a little more complex for us.</p>

<p>For those three and a half years, although we had been introducing ourselves as &ldquo;married,&rdquo; that wasn&rsquo;t strictly true. We were &ldquo;civil partnershipped&rdquo;&hellip; but that doesn&rsquo;t have quite the same ring to it. Socially, it&rsquo;s a lot easier (and less of a mouthful) to say &ldquo;married.&rdquo; Legally, however, the distinction between the two is pretty important. Despite civil partnerships offering all the same rights to same-sex couples <em>in the UK</em>, internationally it&rsquo;s a different story.</p>

<p>The United States federal government did not recognise civil partnerships from other countries. As immigration is federal, I couldn&rsquo;t base my US visa off my partnership with Hampton. This was a key point that a lot of people didn&rsquo;t quite realise. They would often ask why we didn&rsquo;t just get married in, say, Massachusetts and apply off that – well, the federal immigration service didn&rsquo;t care about what a random state decided to legalise, so it wouldn&rsquo;t have made any difference to us.</p>

<p>Instead of being on a marriage-based visa, I was in the US on a work-based visa (the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/H-1B_visa">H1B</a> for visa nerds), and if I left my job I would have had to leave the US.</p>

<p>In early Summer 2013, a few things happened at the same time. Firstly, in the UK there was a vote in Parliament and it became clear that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marriage_(Same_Sex_Couples)_Act_2013">same-sex marriage would become a reality in the near future</a>. Part of this would mean that couples who were in civil partnerships (like us) would be able to &ldquo;upgrade&rdquo; to marriage.</p>

<p>Then, in the US, the Supreme Court struck down <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Defense_of_Marriage_Act">DOMA</a> as unconstitutional. This meant that the federal government <em>could</em> recognise same-sex marriages – which was exactly what we needed for immigration purposes. I could switch from a work-based visa to a marriage-based visa. We had a reason to get &ldquo;fully&rdquo; married!</p>

<p>The next step was figuring out <em>how</em> we should marry. Should we wait to &ldquo;upgrade&rdquo; in the UK? That may take some time, but would mean our first anniversary would be valid.</p>

<p>Or, we could marry in the next few days, now possible in California due to the Prop 8 ruling. This would let us start the immigration process sooner – but would potentially give us more hurdles as we would only have been married a short time. To the immigration process, it would seem like we got married and immediately applied for my green card. That could raise some concerns and delay the visa process.</p>

<p>As if that decision wasn&rsquo;t tough enough, there was another thing to consider. International law prohibits getting married two times in separate countries (without divorcing) – even to the same person. As countries recognise marriages from other countries (i.e. a valid civil marriage in one country is valid in another country), this could count as getting married a second time.</p>

<p>Would we be inadvertantly breaking the law if we got married in California? This legal situation hasn&rsquo;t really existed before. We had a number of debates over whether our civil partnership from the UK would count as marriage in countries with same-sex marriage but without a civil union. Confused yet? We certianly were (and still are).</p>

<p>We went to see an immigration lawyer. She said it would be fine for the immigration process to marry in the US, and she didn&rsquo;t really think it would be illegal for us to obtain a marriage certificate here.</p>

<p>So, we booked an appointment at San Francisco City Hall and on 10th July 2013 we got married. Again.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/marriage/us-cityhall.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/marriage/us-cityhall.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">In San Francisco City Hall</div>
</div>


<p>Afterwards, we started the immigration process and I successsfully got a green card. As I mentioned previously, it&rsquo;s a little frustrating that the US government only sees us as being married for just under a year. My green card is only valid for two years because of this. If we&rsquo;d been married for more than two years, it would have been valid for ten years. Obviously, to us, we&rsquo;ve been married about four and a half years, so it&rsquo;s a little incongruous.</p>

<p>This, now, is our third anniversary. I doubt it will be anything other than a date I have to remember from time to time when filling out immigration paperwork.</p>

<p>Three anniversaries does give you an excuse for three times as many anniversary dinners, so that&rsquo;s nice. Plus I got to marry a guy I love three times (and I&rsquo;d do it at least three times more! Any more than that, though, I&rsquo;d probably be wondering why we needed all these extra commitment ceremonies).</p>

<p>The legal stuff, though? That&rsquo;s been a headache. Most people are surprised when we explain all of the above. They don&rsquo;t realise how difficult it&rsquo;s been and how many loopholes we&rsquo;ve had to jump through.</p>

<p>For us, in our home state, we hope the worst is over. But there are many places – countries and states – where things are still inequal for same-sex couples. Take the bridge below, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arlington_Memorial_Bridge">Arlington Memorial Bridge</a>. We walked along it this winter. It crosses between the District of Columbia and the state of Virginia. We realised that in DC, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Same-sex_marriage_in_the_District_of_Columbia">we have full rights as a married couple</a>. The state we were walking towards, Virginia, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Same-sex_marriage_in_Virginia">does not recognise our marriage</a>. In the process of walking across that bridge, we were giving up our rights. If Hampton needed to go to the hospital and we were in Virginia, we would be treated as strangers (this <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/05/19/health/19well.html">actually happens</a>).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/2/25/Arlington_Memorial_Bridge_DC_12_2011_00091.JPG">
    <img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/2/25/Arlington_Memorial_Bridge_DC_12_2011_00091.JPG">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Arlington Memorial Bridge (photo credit: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arlington_Memorial_Bridge#mediaviewer/File:Arlington_Memorial_Bridge_DC_12_2011_00091.JPG">Wikipedia</a>)</div>
</div>


<p>In many ways, we still have a long journey ahead.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hemingway Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/20/hemingway-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-20T11:38:18+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/20/hemingway-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">
  <p>We&#8217;ve been in Prague for just over a quarter of our month-long stay. So far, it&#8217;s treated us well. I&#8217;ll write a longer post about thoughts on Prague (and the Czech Republic) later on, but first to more important things: cocktails.</p>

  <p>Due to other European cities lacking decent cocktail bars, we didn&#8217;t have high hopes for Prague. Although we eventually found some in Paris, that was after a fair bit of research and travelling to the other side of the city. Would Prague be any different? Additionally, the first thing anyone says about the Czech Republic is that you&#8217;ll never want for beer – it&#8217;s cheap, good quality, and plentiful. Was there any room for a good whiskey sour?</p>

  <p>In short: yes. There are a surprising number of decent cocktail bars within five minutes&#8217; walk of our just-out-of-centre apartment. Most of them do standard cocktails as well as some of their own invention. So far, <a href="http://www.hemingwaybar.cz/bar-prague/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Hemingway Bar</span></a> is probably my favourite.</p>

  <p>It&#8217;s on one of the <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/preview?ie=UTF-8&fb=1&cid=2095651347638903815&q=Hemingway+Bar&ei=cQSkU-TBPMrsO6zsgJAH&ved=0CKkBEPwSMA4">narrow winding streets of Old Town</a>, just off the river – so it makes for a nice walk, especially at dusk with the lights of the castle just coming on.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/castle_dusk.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/castle_dusk.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Sunset over the Vltava</div>
  </div>

  <p>The bar itself is cosy, with three or four small rooms spread over two floors. Pictures of Hemingway line all the walls, as do various drinking vessels – most of which seem to be actually used for drinks.</p>

  <p>The best cocktail (and the one Hampton keeps going back to) is the Red Carpet. It&#8217;s like an old fashioned/whiskey sour/manhattan mix-up. It&#8217;s delicious and refreshing, especially on a hot day. Oh, and it comes served on a little square of red carpet. Cute.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/hemingway/redcarpet.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/hemingway/redcarpet.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Red Carpet</div>
  </div>

 <p> I had a gin-lillet cocktail that was also pretty refreshing (maybe it was just because it was 32ºC outside?). With a name like &#8220;Corpse Reviver,&#8221; I thought I&#8217;d be getting something throat-burning, but it was really smooth.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/hemingway/corpsereviver2.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/hemingway/corpsereviver2.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Corpse Reviver Nº2</div>
  </div>

  <p>Next adorable drink: a martinez using Earl Grey-infused gin. It came in a teacup with a biscuit to nibble on. Perfect!</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/hemingway/marteanez.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/hemingway/marteanez.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Mar-tea-nez</div>
  </div>

  <p>Hampton got the Nick Adams Penicilin, named after <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nick_Adams_(character)">a character in a number of Hemingway&#8217;s short stories</a>. It came on a tray with a glass of ice, a small aspirin-shaped sweet, a bottle of lemon/honey/whisky, and an Erlenmeyer flask of 10-year malt whisky. We were instructed to pour the bottle over the ice, then float the 10-year malt over the top. It was fun! Also get the Hemingway&#8217;s New Fashioned if you&#8217;re into process-heavy drinks with multiple components.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/hemingway/nickadamspenicillin.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/hemingway/nickadamspenicillin.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Nick Adams Penicillin (with everything poured)</div>
  </div>

  <p>Onto one strange thing that happened. Have you ever ordered an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Irish_Car_Bomb">Irish Car Bomb</a>? I&#8217;m assuming that most people reading this aren&#8217;t frat boys, so I&#8217;m going to guess most said &#8220;no.&#8221; Anyway, the first time I heard someone talk about it I was shocked. Needless to say, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Troubles">The Troubles</a> are a very recent, violent, and real part of my country&#8217;s history. Having a drink named after such a thing is hideous and offensive.</p>

  <p>What&#8217;s this rant got to do with the bar? Well, as part of Gin Fest, occuring this week in Prague, they had a special cocktail. It was called &#8220;The Bronx.&#8221; I was recommended it by the bartender, so I got it. It came on a graffiti coaster and a pipette filled with a dark liquid. The bartender squirted the liquid on top of the drink and explained with a cheeky grin that it represented blood.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/hemingway/thebronx.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/hemingway/thebronx.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The Bronx</div>
  </div>

  <p>Was this a drink facetiously referencing gang violence? The bartender seemed to think it was pretty clever. I was just bewildered. For what it&#8217;s worth, though, it didn&#8217;t taste bad.</p>

  <p>There were a number of other cocktails I didn&#8217;t take photos of, but were delicious. Their Lavender Martini was great, and they had the first whiskey sour to rival my favourite (from the Dogpatch Saloon or 83 Proof in San Francisco). In fact, they have a fair few drinks on the menu with egg whites, which I&#8217;m a sucker for.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Hemingway is an inventive cocktail bar that wouldn&#8217;t be out of place in any of the more &#8220;traditional&#8221; cocktail cities like San Francisco, New York or London.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">8.6</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

  <p><strong>EDIT</strong>: I had a couple more absolutely delicious cocktails, and had to append this post with two more recommendations. Both had <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Falernum">home-made Falernum</a> in them. The Save this Moment came on a floppy disk, and had a great gin/citrus base with a white chocolate syrup that gave it a really great flavour.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/hemingway/savemoment.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/hemingway/savemoment.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Save this Moment</div>
  </div>

  <p>Le Swizzle Provençal was a rum-based version along the same lines. It was presented in a little metal bucket with a scoop of almonds. Très jolie!</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/hemingway/swizzleprovencal.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/hemingway/swizzleprovencal.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Le Swizzle Provençal</div>
  </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Map of Flights]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/10/map-of-flights/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-10T11:35:59+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/10/map-of-flights</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here&rsquo;s a geographically inaccurate map I made to show the flights* we have taken and will be taking over the next few months. The future ones aren&rsquo;t set in stone, so there might be some changes towards the end of the trip.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/flight-map.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/flight-map.jpg">
  </a>
</div>


<p>Current airport list: SFO-IAD-JAX-PHL-CDG-VIE-CDG-AGP-LPL-STN-PRG-TXL-AMS-ARN-CDG-PHL-YYZ-JFK-MCO-JAX-SFO. In a couple of hours, we&rsquo;ll be on the STN-PRG leg.</p>

<p>*There&rsquo;s a couple of car/rail journeys in there too.</p>

<p>(Made with <a href="https://www.fiftythree.com/paper">Paper</a>.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nightjar]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/04/nightjar/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-04T13:49:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/04/nightjar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">
  <p>We are in London for a few nights and squeezing in as many activities as possible. Obviously, a major focus of this was drinking. Finding cocktails here is pretty easy compared with continental Europe – within a few blocks of where we&#8217;re staying there&#8217;s <a href="http://www.happinessforgets.com/">Happiness Forgets</a> and <a href="http://www.calloohcallaybar.com/">Callooh Callay</a>, both excellent cocktail bars. </p>

  <p>However, I was most excited about visiting <a href="http://barnightjar.com"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Nightjar</span></a>. We were recommended it by a friend in San Francisco. The menu online looked interesting, so I booked a table. There&#8217;s no standing in the bar, and you have to have a table to get service. I booked about four days before, on a Tuesday, and could only get a table at 6pm.</p>

  <p>It&#8217;s behind an unassuming door <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/preview?q=nightjar&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;ei=3FyPU4TXOsXhPPGVgKAI&amp;ved=0CAoQ_AUoAw">just near Old Street underground station</a>. The bouncer checks your name against a list, and sends you downstairs. After being in the daylight, heading down a candle-lit staircase was a little disorienting. At the bottom of the stairs, the maitre d&#8217; (is that even what they&#8217;re called in a cocktail bar?) welcomed us and sat us down at a small table next to a cabinet of old liqueuers.</p>


  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/mat.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/mat.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Nightjar coaster</div>
  </div>

  <p>The menu had an incredible cover, with the Nightjar appearing on it multiple times. Throughout the night the silhouette of the bird was a recurring theme – punched into lemon-rinds or branded on the side of a mug.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/menu.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/menu.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Menu</div>
  </div>

  <p>The menu was extensive, sorted by pre-prohibition, prohibition, post-war and signature drinks. Most of the cocktails had at least one ingredient I&#8217;d never heard of. It took us a while to decide what to go for, but the bartender was helpful in pointing you towards certain things. With her help, I chose the <a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/new-orleans-daisy">New Orleans Daisy</a> as it had chartreuse in it – but the bartender suggested I take it with gin. Turns out it comes in an owl-shaped container with a candied hibiscus flower and a peacock feather.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/new-orleans-daisy.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/new-orleans-daisy.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">New Orleans Daisy</div>
  </div>

  <p>It was really quite incredible. It had an almost buttery flavour with a nectar aftertaste.</p>

  <p>Our friend went for the <a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/london-mule">London Mule</a>. The picture below doesn&#8217;t quite convey the size of the mug: it was probably about 12 inches high. Most of that was packed ice. It was a great interpretation of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moscow_mule">mule</a>-style of drink.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/london-mule.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/london-mule.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">London Mule</div>
  </div>

  <p>Hampton got a <a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/toronto">Toronto</a>, which was similar to an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Fashioned">Old Fashioned</a> but with maple syrup as the sweetener. Its garnish was a candy-floss nest with some mini-eggs in it.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/toronto.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/toronto.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Toronto</div>
  </div>

  <p>I noticed another table received a cocktail in some sort of two-neck condensing flask. I asked what it was, and it&#8217;s called the <a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/foragers-shrub">Forager&#8217;s Shrub</a>. Of course I went for that next.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/foragers-shrub1.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/foragers-shrub1.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Forager&#8217;s Shrub in flask</div>
  </div>

  <p>The cocktail itself was in the bigger bulb. In the internal, smaller bulb was an oil with some dry ice (I think). It produced a vapour which I was instructed to smell. It smelt of pine and nettles, like a forest after some rain.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/foragers-shrub2.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/foragers-shrub2.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Must-smell item</div>
  </div>

  <p>The bartender then poured the drink out – the fragrant oil into a chalice and the drink itself into a tumbler with ice. I was instructed to smell the oils before drinking. Sure, it was fairly pretentious but here&#8217;s the thing – the smell really did make it taste different. And the cocktail was amazing, so I didn&#8217;t care if I looked like a wally taking a big huff before every sip.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/foragers-shrub3.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/foragers-shrub3.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The final cocktail (yes that&#8217;s a mini corn on the cob)</div>
  </div>

  <p>My last drink was a <a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/marmalade-no-2">Marmalade Nº 2</a>. It tasted exactly like a Seville orange marmalade – acidic, bitter, bursting with orange flavour. I loved it.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/marmalade-2.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/marmalade-2.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Marmalade Nº 2</div>
  </div>

  <p>Other drinks we had but I didn&#8217;t take pictures of:</p>

  <ul>
    <li><a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/bloody-mary">Bloody Mary</a> – served in a hollowed-out squash (you can almost see it behind the Marmalade Nº 2 above)</li>
    <li><a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/name-samurai">Name of the Samurai</a> - served in an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sake_set">ochoko</a> set inside a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Masu_(Japanese)">masu</a> which had burnt herbs inside</li>
    <li><a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/secret-cocktail">Secret Cocktail</a> – a gin/egg white combination that was pretty tasty, but had icing sugar around the whole glass so was impossible to drink without getting sticky</li>
    <li><a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/deep-sea">Deep Sea</a> - had squid ink in it, and had nori around the rim of the glass</li>
    <li><a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/prairie-flip">Prarie Flip</a> – had a garnish of a boiled quail&#8217;s egg and had a weird garlicky taste&#8230; not sure I&#8217;d recommend this one</li>
  </ul>

  <p>The cocktails weren&#8217;t too expensive – between £8 and £12 was the average. Considering that such care went into not only the flavours, but also the decoration and presentation, I found it to be a worthwhile treat.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Nightjar serves innovative cocktails in both taste and presentation.</span> I can see Hampton and I coming back here whenever we&#8217;re in London. </p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">9.6</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drinking in the Costa Del Sol]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/29/drinking-costa-del-sol/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-29T11:37:41+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/29/drinking-costa-del-sol</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The next stage of our trip took us to the south of Spain – the &ldquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Costa_del_Sol">Costa del Sol</a>,&rdquo; a clichéd destination for sun-starved Brits. My family were meeting us there and spending a few days in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mijas">Mijas</a> – a small village scattered on mountains overlooking the Mediterranean.</p>

<p>Our fruitful cocktail hunt in Paris was great. However, we didn&rsquo;t want to push our luck, so we decided to try some more traditional drinks while in a less cosmopolitan area.</p>

<p>First up: fino. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fino">Fino</a> is a dry sherry served very cold. It&rsquo;s taken as an apéretif, and apparently it&rsquo;s what all the locals drink. I&rsquo;m a fan of sherry, so I thought I&rsquo;d try it out.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/fino.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/fino.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Glass of fino</div>
</div>


<p>With regular sherry, the sweetness cuts through some of the flavour of the alcohol, which makes it palatable to me. With fino, you could definitely taste the alcohol compared with &ldquo;sweet&rdquo; sherry. The fino started with a sharp acidity, then followed with a fresher aftertaste. If I lived in Spain, I&rsquo;d probably get used to it, but I wouldn&rsquo;t necessarily order it again.</p>

<p>Next up, at <a href="http://www.tripadvisor.co.uk/Restaurant_Review-g580271-d2413104-Reviews-Pampa_Tablas_y_Tapas-Mijas_Costa_del_Sol_Province_of_Malaga_Andalucia.html">a local tapas bar called Pampa</a>, we tried the stereotypical Spanish alcoholic drink: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sangria">sangria</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/sangria.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/sangria.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Glass and pitcher of sangria</div>
</div>


<p>Sangria is awesome and I presume everyone has had it. If not, you should try it. It&rsquo;s traditionally made with red wine, brandy, and some kind of sweetener. You also put in pieces of chopped fruit. However, I believe this one had some rum in it as well. I&rsquo;ll try adding rum when I next make sangria at home, cause it added a nice kick.</p>

<p>On our final night, we went to a &ldquo;gin bar.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s a slight misnomer: for one, it&rsquo;s more of a tapas place, and for two it served other alcohol as well. But gin is where this place shone. <a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/graphicdetail/2013/06/daily-chart-9">Spain is one of the highest per capita consumers of gin</a> (other fun facts from the linked infographic: India is the largest consumer of rum, and France is the largest consumer of Scotch). So, despite being a traditionally British drink, we had some Spanish-style gin and tonics.</p>

<p>The bar we were at, <a href="http://www.bodegaelplacer.com/">Bodega El Placer</a>, had about thirty gins on offer. There were five of us and we asked for five different gins, so we could sample them all. Each gin came in a big glass with ice and individually-prepared garnishes.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/just-gin.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/just-gin.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Gin with garnishes</div>
</div>


<p>The garnishes ranged from juniper berries, cinnamon sticks and cardamom seeds to a simple lemon slice. The gins were all pretty different. Luckily, I liked a deep-flavoured sour gin that no one else enjoyed, so I didn&rsquo;t have to fight to finish that one off. I believe it was <a href="http://www.bulldoggin.com/">Bulldog gin</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/tonic-regular.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/tonic-regular.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Gin and tonic</div>
</div>


<p>Fun fact: in most of Europe, when you want a gin and tonic, you just say &ldquo;gintonic.&rdquo; All one word.</p>

<p>They also had a blue tonic, but I&rsquo;m not really sure what the difference between regular tonic and the blue stuff was. I was a bad scientist and didn&rsquo;t do a same-gin, different-tonic experiment.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/tonic-blue.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/tonic-blue.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Blue tonic?!</div>
</div>


<p>I should also mention the tapas: it was really good. It was more inventive than I was expecting – they had tempura aubergine with a honey sauce, and a melt-in-your-mouth tuna sashimi plate. My favourite, of course, was the jamón. It was one of the better jamón ibérico we had while in Spain.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/jamon.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/jamon.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Jamón ibérico</div>
</div>


<p>We were only in Spain a few days. Despite that, we managed to do two excellent day trips: one to Granada to see the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alhambra">Alhambra</a> (check out some photos <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/malrase/sets/72157644507980879/">on Flickr</a>), and one to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gibraltar">Gibraltar</a> (<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/malrase/sets/72157644507822700/">Flickr photos</a>). If you&rsquo;re ever in the south of Spain, I highly recommend taking a trip to those. I also hear Seville is great, but we didn&rsquo;t make it there.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re now on our way to the UK, which I&rsquo;m worried will be a bit of a shock. We&rsquo;re leaving sunny, 24ºC weather and heading towards a rainy 10ºC.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
