<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-20T17:51:17-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bar Chef]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/20/bar-chef/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-20T12:10:44-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/20/bar-chef</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>We&#8217;ve been using <a href="http://www.worldsbestbars.com/">World&#8217;s Best Bars</a> to find bars when we&#8217;ve been travelling. It&#8217;s a little hit-and-miss, and you need to do some extra research before you randomly pick one. But it&#8217;s great if you&#8217;re in a place that doesn&#8217;t really use Yelp or FourSquare. We showed it to Mike and Melissa, and they laughed at a lot of the choices for Toronto. One, however, they recommended: <a href="http://www.barcheftoronto.com/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Bar Chef</span></a>.</p>

  <p>It&#8217;s in the second-coolest neighbourhood in the world (according to <a href="http://www.vogue.com/slideshow/1080625/fifteen-coolest-street-style-neighborhoods/">Vogue</a>) – Queen Street West. They serve fancy cocktails and want to &#8220;challenge the [&#8230;] cocktail experience.&#8221; SOUNDS FUN!</p>

  <p>Oh, it was dark inside, so most of my photos are a little grainy. Sorry.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/barchef.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/barchef.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Bar Chef placemat</div>
  </div>

  <p>We started out with two normal-ish cocktails. The Symphony No 5 was a gin/vanilla thing that was OK. The Basil Daiquiri was tasty – super-drinkable.

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/symphony-daiquiri.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/symphony-daiquiri.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Symphony No. 5 and the Basil Daiquiri</div>
  </div>

  <p>These two cocktails were pretty good. However, we noticed there was a &#8220;modernist&#8221; section that had more expensive ones – some with some weird ingredients (&#8220;spring fog&#8221;? &#8220;beach essence&#8221;?).</p>

  <p>Hampton got a $45 (!) Manhattan. It came under a giant cloche filled with smoke.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/manhattan-cloche.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/manhattan-cloche.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Cloche full of smoke</div>
  </div>

  <p>It rested on the table for a minute or two before the bartender came over and slowly swirled the cloche off the top of the pedestal. Underneath was the smokey Manhattan!</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/manhattan.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/manhattan.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Manhattan</div>
  </div>

  <p>It was seriously smokey. Even though I was only sat next to Hampton, my clothes smelt like a wood fire for the next day.</p>

  <p>The next modernist cocktail we got was the Black Truffle. It came with six tiny spoons. The spoons had a coconut foam/lime dust mixture on them. You were supposed to eat one of those, then drink the gin-based concoction. Those spoons were amazing, and they went well with the drink. The drink had elderflower in it, too, so I loved it.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/black-truffle.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/black-truffle.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Black Truffle</div>
  </div>

  <p>Next up, there was a Cedar. It came on a wood platter set up like a zen garden. There was a sprig of cedar in one corner, some cacao &#8220;soil&#8221; and chunks of pear. You dip the pear in the &#8220;soil,&#8221; and eat that before you drink. I didn&#8217;t get much from the food bit, but the drink (a gin-chamomile-pear thing) was clean and fresh.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/cedar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/cedar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Cedar</div>
  </div>

  <p>I think the weirdest drink of the night was the Spring Thaw. It came in a tiny glass surrounded by moss. The bartender came over and poured water (?) over the moss, and it started misting. I&#8217;m guessing there was perfumed dry ice in there somewhere – it smelled just like a spring forest.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/spring-thaw-mist.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/spring-thaw-mist.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Spring thawing all over the table</div>
  </div>

  <p>The cocktail itself was a gin-campari thing. It had a campari sorbet of some kind, and as you were drinking the sorbet melted into the rest. It&#8217;s a neat concept, but it was strange that the drink got more and more bitter as you went on.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/spring-thaw.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/spring-thaw.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The Spring Thaw cocktail itself</div>
  </div>

  <p>We also got a punch bowl, which I&#8217;d recommend if you&#8217;re tired of the pomp around the other cocktails.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">I love any kind of ceremony or ostentation around food and drink. There&#8217;s something fun about the process – in these cases, eating something special before you drink, or smelling a fog that surrounds your glass. So I&#8217;m already inclined to like a place like this – and I did. A lot. It&#8217;s definitely not cheap, though, and certainly not a casual after-work-drinks kinda place.</span></p>


  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">9.0</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Momofuku and Other Toronto Eats]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/16/daisho/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-16T10:15:28-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/16/daisho</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve enjoyed watching <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Chang">David Chang&rsquo;s</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Momofuku_(restaurants)">Momofuku</a> empire grow, but I&rsquo;ve never had the opportunity to eat at one of his restaurants. As he hasn&rsquo;t opened a restaurant in San Francisco, the closest I&rsquo;ve got is reading <a href="http://lky.ph/">Lucky Peach</a>. I was super excited to go to one of his restaurants in Toronto.</p>

<p>There are four Momofuku properties in Toronto – all housed in the same building. In order of increasing fanciness, they are Noodle Bar, Nikai (a cocktail bar), Daishō and Shōtō. The building is pretty cool – it almost looks like an Apple store with its glass exterior and giant Momofuku sign.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/momofuku.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/momofuku.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Momofuku sign</div>
</div>


<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toronto_International_Film_Festival">Toronto International Film Festival</a> is going on, and right next to the Momofuku building is the Shangri-la hotel. On its third-floor deck, there was a pre-premiere party for a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wild_(film)">new Reese Witherspoon film</a>. From our table we could see right into the pre-party and had a lot of fun figuring out what it was for. We saw <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Evans_(actor)">Chris Evans</a> there! But we didn&rsquo;t see Reese Witherspoon.</p>

<p>Anyway, onto the food. We were eating at Daishō, which has a bunch of smaller dishes plus some larger, 4-10 person plates if you want to do that. They also have a small, but interesting, cocktail list. I got a bijou and it was nicely done (although you couldn&rsquo;t really taste the Chartreuse).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/cocktail.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/cocktail.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Bijou and menu</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/whiskey-flight.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/whiskey-flight.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hampton got a whiskey flight</div>
</div>


<p>Momofuku is known for its buns, so we got some duck and shrimp versions. It was strange seeing the duck come in patty form – but it tasted absolutely amazing, so I didn&rsquo;t care.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/duck-bun.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/duck-bun.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Duck bun</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/shrimp-bun.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/shrimp-bun.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Shrimp bun</div>
</div>


<p>The steak tartare was made with such tender beef. They added enough yolk to keep it glossy, without it being too sloppy. Plus it has sunflower seeds in it which added some nice texture. One of the best tartares I&rsquo;ve had.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/tartare.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/tartare.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Steak tartare</div>
</div>


<p>The other popular thing on the menu is the ssäm (pronounced with a long &ldquo;a&rdquo;, like psalm). <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ssam">Ssäm</a> is a Korean dish whereby you wrap meat inside a large lettuce leaf. It&rsquo;s a make-your-own lettuce wrap kinda thing. We decided to go for the secreto ssäm, mainly because we didn&rsquo;t know what secreto was (turns out it&rsquo;s a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Iberian_pig">cut of pork</a>). It was really delicious!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/ssam.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/ssam.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Secreto Ssäm</div>
</div>


<p>We also ordered some crab cakes, which came out looking a lot more different than I thought. Turns out Korean-style crab cakes aren&rsquo;t patty-shaped. They&rsquo;re long tube-like things that aren&rsquo;t totally unlike crab sticks. They came in a spicy sauce, too.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crab-cakes.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crab-cakes.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Korean-style crab cakes</div>
</div>


<p>Despite being fit to burst at this point, we were recommended the crack pie. IT WAS AMAZING. That&rsquo;s about all I can say. If you have an opportunity, get it.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crack-pie.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crack-pie.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Crack pie</div>
</div>


<p>As well as Daishō, there were a bunch of other awesome places we ate at.</p>

<p><a href="http://guu-izakaya.com/sakabar">Guu Sakabar</a> is an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Izakaya">izakaya</a>-style bar/restaurant. They have a bunch of smaller dishes on the <a href="http://guu-izakaya.com/docs/sakabar_menu1.pdf">menu</a>, and you order a few each and share. They have a wide range of stuff, from standard (like takoyaki) to weird (udon carbonara?). My favourite was kabocha korokke – a pumpkin croquette thing with a boiled egg in the middle, served with a sauce that was kinda like thousand island dressing.</p>

<p>They had an Ontario-produced sake which I can&rsquo;t find on the menu but it was delicious.</p>

<p><a href="http://416snackbar.wordpress.com/">416 Snack Bar</a> is a hipster tapas-style place. They had chalkboard on the walls and don&rsquo;t offer you any cutlery. The best thing here was either the foie torchon or the steak tartare.</p>

<p>The other place I enjoyed was <a href="http://patriatoronto.com/">Patria</a>, a Spanish tapas restaurant (all the places we went to were tapas, it seems). They had great authentic Spanish-style food (even jamón Ibérico!) plus some tasty sangria. We got a cornish hen paella, which was weird but worked pretty well.</p>

<p>These restaurants barely scratch the surface of Toronto, I&rsquo;m sure. We&rsquo;ve eaten really well here, no doubt due to the excellent choices of our friends <a href="http://twitter.com/mferrier">Mike</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/melissaiscool">Melissa</a> who pretty much recommended/chose all of these places to eat at.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Niagara]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/15/niagara/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-15T16:05:23-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/15/niagara</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Flying to Toronto, I saw the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niagara_Falls">Niagara Falls</a> as a misty interruption of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niagara_River">Niagara River</a>. Turns out they&rsquo;re only about a 1.5hr drive from Toronto, so we decided to head there for an overnight trip. Extra bonus: to get there you travel through <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ontario_wine">Ontario wine country</a>, so we stopped off at a winery on the way back.</p>

<p>Niagara Falls (the town) is very&hellip; commercial. It&rsquo;s almost like a damp Las Vegas. The Canada side (with the better views) has a bunch of casinos, super-tall hotels, chain restaurants. It&rsquo;s a little overwhelming, especially if you imagined it would just be a beautiful waterfall surrounded by nature.</p>

<p>We stayed at the Hilton, which had pretty neat views of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_Falls">American Falls</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/hotel-view.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/hotel-view.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">View from our room. That&#8217;s the U.S.A. across that bridge!</div>
</div>


<p>We arrived at 6pm, and headed straight for the <a href="http://www.niagaracruises.com/">Hornblower</a>. It&rsquo;s the Canadian version of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maid_of_the_Mist">Maid of the Mist</a> boat.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/panorama.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/panorama.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Panorama on the Hornblower</div>
</div>


<p>You take a route up the river, past the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_Falls">American Falls</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bridal_Veil_Falls_(Niagara_Falls)">Bridal Veil Falls</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/american-bridal.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/american-bridal.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">American Falls and Bridal Veil Falls</div>
</div>


<p>After that, the boat goes right into the mist spray of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horseshoe_Falls">Horseshoe Falls</a>. <strong>Pro-tip</strong>: if you have contact lenses, wear them. I was running out of dry bits of T-shirt to wipe my glasses with.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Horseshoe Falls</div>
</div>


<p>This next photo adequately captures what it feels like in the middle: it&rsquo;s windy and there&rsquo;s mist everywhere and it&rsquo;s loud.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/in-horseshoe.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/in-horseshoe.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">In the middle of the falls</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Posing</div>
</div>


<p>After we got off the boat (thankfully it was pretty warm, so we dried quickly), we headed to our evening meal at <a href="http://www.weinkeller.ca/">Weinkeller</a>. But on the way, we passed a haunted house: Dracula&rsquo;s Haunted Castle <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/@43.0912213,-79.0744428,3a,75y,21.98h,80.75t/data=!3m4!1e1!3m2!1siKb9ZlIUyOeNtBlIvdj2Tg!2e0">on Clifton Hill</a>. We like that sort of thing, so went inside. It was $10 each, and you can choose your scare level – we chose medium.</p>

<p>We were the only ones in there, and after paying headed up some stairs in pitch-black darkness. The first few rooms are dull – mostly poorly-done wa figures. However, towards the latter half the scare actor(s?) come in. He was amazing – he growled and chased us through the maze. It was pretty terrifying, I have to admit. I&rsquo;ve never been more relieved than seeing those stairs leading to the exit.</p>

<p>Anyway, we continued up Clifton Hill to the restaurant. Turns out haunted houses are a big deal in Niagara Falls. We counted three more on the walk. There was one next door/above Weinkeller, too!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/weinkeller-nextdoor.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/weinkeller-nextdoor.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Next door to Weinkeller</div>
</div>


<p>Weinkeller is the <a href="http://www.tripadvisor.ca/Restaurants-g154998-Niagara_Falls_Ontario.html">top-rated TripAdvisor restaurant for Niagara Falls</a>. If you use TripAdvisor, I probably don&rsquo;t need to describe the atmosphere – keen service, slightly older clientele, great value, and delicious food. It amuses Hampton and me to compare ratings on TripAdvisor, Yelp, and FourSquare. Each site&rsquo;s audience has subtley different things they look for in a restaurant.</p>

<p>I think the restaurant space used to be a cheap Italian restaurant. The decor was a little&hellip; lacking. Who puts colour-changing lights in a restaurant? But the wait staff were incredible – making jokes, smiling all the time. One of the menu options is a five-course meal but (get this) you can replace up to two of the courses with a glass of wine. Perfect!</p>

<p>Speaking of wine, they make their own. You can see the casks in the back. It was really quite good. The food was amazing. I had some incredible steak tartare, and my main was a super-juicy pork chop. Hampton had a great seared-tuna thing.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/weinkeller-starter.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/weinkeller-starter.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Tuna</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/weinkeller-main.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/weinkeller-main.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Main course at Weinkeller</div>
</div>


<p>After the meal, we walked back to our hotel and grabbed a drink at Myst, the top-floor bar. The drinks were OK. The view was good – but at night Niagara Falls isn&rsquo;t nearly as impressive. They light the falls with a dim rainbow of colours. Super-tacky. You can&rsquo;t really get a good photo, so you&rsquo;ll have to imagine it.</p>

<p>The next morning we did the other Niagara Falls tourist trap: going behind the Horseshoe Falls. Walking close to the edge of the falls was pretty spectacular. The water is much clearer than I thought it was going to be.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-edge.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-edge.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The edge of Horseshoe Falls</div>
</div>


<p>You take a lift down to the bottom of the falls, and it opens up into these dank tunnels.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-tunnel.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-tunnel.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Tunnels underneath Horseshoe Falls</div>
</div>


<p>You can go outside to just where the falls hit the water, which is extremely loud and incredibly close.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-behind.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-behind.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Where Horseshoe Falls meets the river</div>
</div>


<p>I was always fascinated by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waterfall#mediaviewer/File:WaterfallCreationDiagram.svg">waterfall geography</a> (I was a cool kid). It&rsquo;s so strange to think that Niagara Falls started way downstream and has been slowly moving since then.</p>

<p>You walk down some more tunnels to get behind the actual falls. They have a couple of holes cut in the rock and you can look out. But you can&rsquo;t see much – it&rsquo;s mostly a white mist. It&rsquo;s really loud, too.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-back.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/horseshoe-back.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Behind Horseshoe Falls</div>
</div>


<p>After that, we left Niagara Falls. It was fun going there, but I&rsquo;m not sure I&rsquo;d do it again any time soon. A day there was enough to see and do most things, I think.</p>

<p>The drive back to Toronto goes through wine country, so we stopped off at one of Hampton&rsquo;s favourite wineries: <a href="http://www.fieldingestatewinery.ca/">Fielding Estate</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-entrance.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-entrance.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Entrance to Fielding Estate</div>
</div>


<p>Californian wines aren&rsquo;t really our thing. It&rsquo;s nice going to Napa or Sonoma and doing a wine tour, but we prefer whites grown in colder regions. We like whites from the Alsace, Austria, Ontario or Washington. Fielding Estate Winery has some great wines – aromatic and floral, but not too sweet.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside the tasting room/shop</div>
</div>


<p>We tried about six wines in total, and bought four bottles. The gewurztraminer, the viogner, and the Rock Pile Pinot Gris were the best.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-vats.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-vats.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Casks of wine</div>
</div>


<p>There&rsquo;s an awesome view over the vineyards, too. If we had more time, we would have definitely had a glass outside.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-view.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/niagara/fielding-view.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">View over the vinyards</div>
</div>


<p>You should definitely visit Fielding Estate if you&rsquo;re in the Niagara area. Or keep an eye out for their wines. They&rsquo;re super-tasty!</p>

<p>Next up, I&rsquo;ll be posting about delicious food and drink we&rsquo;ve had since we&rsquo;ve been in Toronto.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Life Gives You Paekrosul: Making a North Korean Cocktail]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/10/north-korean-brandy-cocktail/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-10T11:24:50-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/10/north-korean-brandy-cocktail</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We made it to Toronto! But more on that later. What&rsquo;s more important is drinking unusual alcohol. While in Toronto, we&rsquo;ve been hanging out with two of our awesome friends, <a href="http://twitter.com/mferrier">Mike</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/melissaiscool">Melissa</a>. Last year, they visited the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Korean_Demilitarized_Zone">DMZ</a>, and <a href="http://melissadreamsofsushi.com/?p=6587">bought a bottle of North Korean brandy</a> known as Paekrosul.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/paekrosul.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/paekrosul.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Paekrosul</div>
</div>


<p>Apparently its name translates as <a href="http://www.physics.uq.edu.au/people/nieminen/chiew.html">&ldquo;Hundred-Years Liquour&rdquo;</a>, which is certainly promising.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/made-in-dprk.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/made-in-dprk.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">For realz made in DPR Korea</div>
</div>


<p>The bottle was a little tatty, and it was stoppered with a plastic cork. Inside, there was a bit of sandy sediment. Feeling the risk of going blind was one worth taking, we opened the bottle and poured ourselves a (small) glass.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/glass.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/glass.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Paekrosul, neat</div>
</div>


<p>I thought it smelled a lot like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baijiu">baiju</a>, a Chinese liquour that my Dad always gets as a business gift. Others described it as having more of a turpentine aroma.</p>

<p>Despite its nose-burning smell, it tasted fine. Harsh at first, it quickly becomes sweeter and it didn&rsquo;t have a burning aftertaste that you get with a lot of high-proof drinks. No one really wanted to drink much more than a sip, though. What do you do when you have alcohol that no one&rsquo;s going to drink neat? You make a cocktail of course!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/cocktail-time.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/cocktail-time.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Time to make a cocktail</div>
</div>


<p>Mike and Melissa have a well-stocked bar, so I had a lot of stuff to work with. But where to begin? I looked online for some brandy cocktails to see if I could modify them. One suggestion was the <a href="http://cocktails.about.com/od/atozcocktailrecipes/r/mtropltn_cktl.htm">metropolitan</a> – like a manhattan but with brandy instead of whiskey. I used one part sweet vermouth to three parts Paekrosul, plus some Angostura for good measure. It didn&rsquo;t taste that great, though. As the Paekrosul was sweet already, the vermouth didn&rsquo;t contribute much. Plus the main off-putting thing about Paekrosul was the smell. Neither the vermouth nor the bitters covered that up. Time to try a different route.</p>

<p>My favourite cocktails are all citrus-based. Citrus fruits also tend to have pretty strong aromas, so I thought using lemon or lime might be good.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/citrus.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/citrus.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Adding citrus makes everything better</div>
</div>


<p>I mixed in some lemon juice and it tasted pretty good. It tasted even better if you used a lemon peel as a garnish. Twisting the peel to spray the citrus oil over the drink covered up the turpentine smell pretty well.</p>

<p>I tried it with lime but it didn&rsquo;t work as well – the lime flavour wasn&rsquo;t strong enough.</p>

<p>I also ended up adding some <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cointreau">Cointreau triple sec</a> to the mix to add a little more citrus and sweetness.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/cocktail.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/cocktail.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The final drink</div>
</div>


<p>Ta-da! It wasn&rsquo;t the best cocktail I&rsquo;ve ever made, but I think I did a good job of mostly masking the worst flavours of the Paekrosul while keeping its more distinctive flavours. I&rsquo;m pretty sure by next summer it will be on every speakeasy menu from Brooklyn to the Mission.</p>

<p>I haven&rsquo;t come up with a witty name yet, so suggestions are welcome.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/ingredients.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/ingredients.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Final ingredients</div>
</div>


<p>If you have some Paekrosul , is as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li>3 parts Paekrosul</li>
<li>1 part Triple Sec</li>
<li>1 part lemon juice</li>
<li>Stir over ice, serve with an ice cube and lemon peel garnish.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[North Paris]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/04/north-paris/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-04T15:36:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/04/north-paris</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before we do the North American stint of our journey, we had one final week in our favourite European city: Paris. It&rsquo;s amazing how quickly all anxieties about travel or business evaporate when we&rsquo;re sat in a café drinking some wine.</p>

<p>We were staying in an area new to us: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Montmartre">Montmartre</a>. We were situated on the north side of the hill, behind the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basilique_du_Sacr%C3%A9-C%C5%93ur,_Paris">Sacré-Cœur</a>. It was a little tricky (but by no means impossible) to get to other areas that we usually hang out in (mostly <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint-Germain-des-Pr%C3%A9s">St Germain</a> and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latin_Quarter,_Paris">Latin Quarter</a>) – so we spent a lot of time in the neighbourhood.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/cafe.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/cafe.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Chilling in a café</div>
</div>


<p>One of the first things we did was walk to the Sacré-Cœur. It&rsquo;s something you can see from most of Paris, perched on the top of Montmartre like a wedding cake topper. Neither of us had been before, so we trekked up the few hundred steps to the top.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/sc.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/sc.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">In front of the Sacré-Cœur</div>
</div>


<p></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s certainly a beautiful church, but the view over Paris? It&rsquo;s&hellip; OK.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/view-sc.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/view-sc.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">View from the Sacré-Cœur</div>
</div>


<p>Sure, any vista over a city is kinda nice. But there just isn&rsquo;t much variation to make this one that interesting. It&rsquo;s just roofs – and you can maybe pick out the Centre Pompidou or Notre Dame in the distance if you&rsquo;re lucky.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/view-sc-annotated.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/view-sc-annotated.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">View from the Sacré-Cœur, with annotations!</div>
</div>


<p>The view from the top floor of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Centre_Georges_Pompidou">Centre Pompidou</a> is much better, because you can see the stereotypical Parisian apartment buildings right there, but also see the Eiffel Tower, Notre Dame, the Sacré-Cœur, etc. in the background. It&rsquo;s a more satisfying view.</p>

<p>In short, the Sacré-Cœur looks perfectly fine from far away and I wouldn&rsquo;t bother climbing up all those steps unless you&rsquo;re really into churches.</p>

<p>Another touristy thing we did was the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mus%C3%A9e_d%27Orsay">Musée d&#8217;Orsay</a>. Housed in an old train station, it&rsquo;s renowned as one of the best collections of impressionist and post-impressionist art in the world. I&rsquo;d visited the museum before, and didn&rsquo;t really enjoy it. I was in a rush and (post-)impressionism isn&rsquo;t really my thing. Plus the queues for tickets are notorious – I&rsquo;ve heard stories of 2+ hours in line.</p>

<p>We were wandering past on a Thursday at 2pm and there was no line whatsoever for tickets. Apparently that&rsquo;s the time to go! On a whim, we went inside.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/orsay.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/orsay.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Musée d&#8217;Orsay</div>
</div>


<p>It&rsquo;s a gorgeous building, and the layout is innovative. The central aisle has sculptures and off the sides are the paintings. I must admit, I enjoyed the museum a lot more this time around. There was still a lot of stuff I didn&rsquo;t enjoy, but I found an appreciation for the &ldquo;greats&rdquo; – Monet, Cézanne, Degas, Van Gogh.</p>

<p>It was funny seeing the Orsay&rsquo;s Van Gogh collection – which completely blew away the collection of the Van Gogh Museum we visited in Amsterdam. Every classic painting is here – <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vincent_van_Gogh#mediaviewer/File:Vincent_van_Gogh_-_Self-Portrait_-_Google_Art_Project.jpg"><strong>the</strong> self-portrait</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Starry_Night_Over_the_Rhone">Starry Night over the Rhone</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Church_at_Auvers">The Church at Auvers</a>, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portrait_of_Dr._Gachet">less-expensive Portrait of Dr Gachet</a>. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Gates_of_Hell">plaster original of the Gates of Hell</a> by Rodin is also there, which is probably my favourite piece in the museum. During the visit, I went from completely hating the museum to thinking it&rsquo;s one of my favourites in Paris.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;d never toured <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Les_Invalides">Les Invalides</a>, the building complex which houses the military history museum and home of Napoleon&rsquo;s tomb. We did that mostly to check off Parisian tourist things I hadn&rsquo;t yet done.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/tomb.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/tomb.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Tomb of Napoleon, Les Invalides</div>
</div>


<p>If you&rsquo;re super into military history, you should go. I&rsquo;m&hellip; not, so the museum left me a little bored. The tomb of Napoleon was kinda cool, but that&rsquo;s about it. Oh, there was a sub-museum dedicated to the life of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_de_Gaulle">Charles de Gaulle</a>. It gushed about him, which was creepy enough, but both Hampton and I thought it left a negative impression of him by the end of it. He came across as a little dictatorial, to be honest. I need to read more about his time in politics to get a better grasp of what he did.</p>

<p>Anyway, we mostly spent our days drinking wine and coffee in cafés, which is a fine way to spend a week. Off to Toronto (by way of one night in Philadelphia) next!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halfway-ish: Thoughts So Far on Our Travels]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/29/halfway-ish-thoughts-so-far/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-29T06:28:24-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/29/halfway-ish-thoughts-so-far</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;re about to head back to North America. That&rsquo;s right, the European leg of our 2014 journey is almost over. In a lot of ways, I&rsquo;m sad to be leaving. I feel a little short-changed – we only had <em>one day</em> in Vienna? Why didn&rsquo;t we make it to Budapest? Should we have spent time in a random British city, too?</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also looking forward to the next leg of our trip: the East Coast. I&rsquo;m excited to learn more about Toronto and New York. I can&rsquo;t wait to drive down the East Coast as autumn descends and the leaves change. I&rsquo;m looking foward to using a more familiar currency, and for things to be not so expensive.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also thinking ahead to being back in San Francisco – being <em>home</em>. Travel is a lot of fun, and we&rsquo;re extremely aware of how lucky we are to be doing it, but it&rsquo;s quite exhausting and has a lot of anxiety associated with it. I&rsquo;ll probably write another post about that, though.</p>

<p>But now, we&rsquo;re at a half-way point in our travels. It&rsquo;s not literally a half-way point – we&rsquo;ve spent more time in Europe than we will on the East Coast – but it&rsquo;s close enough and is, if anything, almost a thematic half-way point. So I decided to do a bit of reflection on the packing aspect of travelling – whether I&rsquo;m regretting bringing that electric toothbrush, or how I feel about living out of a carry-on bag.</p>

<h3>Living from a carry-on</h3>

<p>It&rsquo;s not that bad, to be honest. I&rsquo;m getting a little tired of the clothes I have, and some of them are a little bit worse-for-wear, but all in all it&rsquo;s fine. So far I&rsquo;ve not had the Fight Club-esque &ldquo;I want to get rid of more stuff&rdquo; epiphany, but I have thought about slimming down on some clothes at home, and definitely getting rid of some of our stuff in storage (do we <em>really</em> need all those wires?).</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s kind of funny that we&rsquo;ve been checking our bags for most of our European flights. It started because we were mainly flying with EasyJet, which has a strict one-bag-only policy. There was no way we could fit our laptop bags in our carry-ons, so we checked them.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve also been buying liquids in bigger quantities than we could take on the flight. Things like travel-sized shaving foam aren&rsquo;t always easy to come by, and it feels wasteful buying a whole can of foam just to throw it away after a couple of uses.</p>

<p>Having said that, using the carry-on as a &ldquo;way-of-mind,&rdquo; if you will, has been great. I definitely wouldn&rsquo;t pack a larger suitcase if I did this again. It&rsquo;s far more convenient to have a smaller bag when navigating small hotel rooms or getting on a train.</p>

<h3>Things I wish I&rsquo;d brought</h3>

<p>There&rsquo;s a couple of things I wish I&rsquo;d brought – but to be honest, they&rsquo;ve been fairly easy to find abroad.</p>

<p><strong>Cups/re-useable bottle</strong> – in some AirBnB places we&rsquo;ve stayed in, they only had tiny water glasses. Most of the time, we&rsquo;ve ended up buying big bottles and refilling them. We bought two medium-sized plastic tumblers to take around in case we needed a mixed drink or something to pour into. They come in handy in hotel rooms, too!</p>

<p><strong>More bad shirts</strong> – I brought all my favourite shirts. Maybe this is just me, but I feel weird wearing my favourite stuff every day. They&rsquo;re already starting to get a little tatty. I wish I had some more simple shirts that I could easily throw away at the end of this trip.</p>

<h3>Things I wish I&rsquo;d left</h3>

<p><strong>Some contact lenses</strong> – I really overpacked for contact lenses. I brought enough to wear every other day, and I&rsquo;ve barely used them. I guess I thought I&rsquo;d be wearing my sunglasses more often.</p>

<p><strong>Running shorts</strong> – yeah, that was wishful thinking.</p>

<p><strong>Three shirts</strong> – (a.k.a. dress shirts or button-downs) I just don&rsquo;t wear these as much as I thought I would. I brought one ironable shirt and two non. I just don&rsquo;t wear the ironable one because it&rsquo;s too much hassle. I think one shirt would be plenty.</p>

<p>Summer is wrapping up in Europe and I&rsquo;m starting to wear my heavier clothes again. But for a while, when it was 30ºC-plus every day in Prague, I cursed myself for bringing a woolen jumper and a heavy cardigan. Much like in a few months, I will probably be wondering why I brought shorts (although I did wear them a bunch!).</p>

<h3>Things I&rsquo;m <em>so</em> glad I brought</h3>

<p><strong>T-Mobile SIM card</strong> – I can&rsquo;t sing the praises of (the USA company) T-Mobile enough; we switched to them just before we left the USA.  They have unlimited 3G data and texts for a large number of countries, including every country we&rsquo;ve visited. Being able to use Google Maps, or check your e-mail, without having to worry about paying through the nose for every single megabyte is incredibly relieving.</p>

<p><strong>iPad</strong> – this might be obvious for people who have and love their iPads. I was never that into my iPad, but waiting in airports, taking train journeys, and other such times have made be really appreciate it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stockholm]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/23/stockholm/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-23T07:55:14-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/23/stockholm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We spent a few days in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stockholm">Stockholm</a> for this year&rsquo;s <a href="http://hybridconf.net/">HybridConf</a>. It&rsquo;s been a lot of fun, and I really recommend checking the conference out. Although I&rsquo;ve been to Sweden once before, I&rsquo;ve never been to Stockholm so I was pretty excited to check out this new city.</p>

<p>Stereotypes about Sweden that are true:</p>

<ul>
<li>it&rsquo;s cold – it was summer but it was 18ºC most days</li>
<li>everything is expensive</li>
<li>people wear brightly-coloured trousers (was that just a stereotype I had?)</li>
</ul>


<p>I like Sweden a lot. It&rsquo;s far more multicultural than I first expected (I had images of streets and streets filled with blonde-haired, blue-eyed Scandanavians). Stockholm isn&rsquo;t as tourist-y as the last few places we&rsquo;ve been, either. It was refreshing at dinner to hear people around you speaking Swedish rather than English.</p>

<p>We only really had time for one day of touring, and when Hampton and I tour a city, we take it seriously. We looked up the top three things to do in Stockholm and made it a priority to check them off.</p>

<p>Stockholm is built on a bunch of islands – an archipelago, really. The centralmost island is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gamla_stan">Gamla Stan</a>, &ldquo;Old Town&rdquo;. It has winding cobbled streets and alleyways and it&rsquo;s also the home of the royal palace. That&rsquo;s where we started our walking tour.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/gamla-stan.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/gamla-stan.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hampton looking over Gamla Stan</div>
</div>


<p></p>

<p>It was pretty, but full of tourist shops. We quickly headed over to the neighbouring island to check out the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moderna_Museet">Moderna Museet</a>. Although not as big as, say, MoMA or the Tate Modern, the collection is really good. It&rsquo;s manageable in size but also offers a great narrative over 20th century art.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/moderna-calder.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/moderna-calder.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Calder sculptures outside the museum</div>
</div>


<p>After that, we island hopped again – this time taking a ferry to visit the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vasa_museum">Vasa Museum</a>. There&rsquo;s also a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gr%C3%B6na_Lund">theme park</a> on the island – but it wasn&rsquo;t open. Sad times!</p>

<p>Anyway, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vasa_(ship)">Vasa</a> was a ship built in 1620s in preparation for a war against Poland. On its maiden voyage, it sank about 20 minutes after setting sail. It lay in the Stockholm bay for over 300 years, until it was recovered in the 1960s. It&rsquo;s still undergoing restoration and preservation, and it&rsquo;s housed in its own museum.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s one of the largest intact boats on display from the 1600s, and it&rsquo;s in great shape.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/vasa-front.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/vasa-front.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Front of the Vasa</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/vasa-back.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/vasa-back.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Intricate carvings on the back of the Vasa</div>
</div>


<p>You&rsquo;ll notice there&rsquo;s some areas of slightly lighter wood on the image above (the post on the top-left, and the cherub mid-right). Those are where the original carvings fell off and they re-carved them from new wood. It&rsquo;s kind of crazy to think that the rest of the carvings remained like that from when they were made in 1628.</p>

<p>Finally we headed back to the city centre (just north of gamla stan) for some food. We ate at a great Scandinavian restaurant called <a href="http://www.rolfskok.se/?lang=en">Rolf&rsquo;s Kök</a>. I had a super-rich ox cheek dish, and Hampton had a creamy fish stew. Both were delicious!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/rolfs-bread.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/rolfs-bread.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Bread on a skewer (?) with homemade butter</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/rolfs-oxcheek.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/rolfs-oxcheek.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Ox cheek</div>
</div>


<p>After that, we realised that there was a <a href="http://mikkeller.dk/mikkeller-stockholm/">Mikkeller Bar</a> nearby. A Mikkeller Bar recently opened in San Francisco, but we never went. Why not go now, when we&rsquo;re half-way around the world?! So we went. I had a tasty IPA. Hampton tried asking the bartender if they had a British-style ale, but got a sassy reply, so had some wine instead.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/mikkeller-ipa.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/mikkeller-ipa.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Viking 25 IPA</div>
</div>


<p>As if to remind me how silly it was going to a bar that&rsquo;s in my home city, they had the <a href="http://insidescoopsf.sfgate.com/blog/2014/01/13/mikkeller-introduces-mission-chinese-food-beer/">Mission Chinese</a> lager on the board, too.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/mikkeller-mission.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/stockholm/mikkeller-mission.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Mission Chinese beer</div>
</div>


<p>After that, we tried to find a decent, reasonably-priced cocktail. Pro-tip: don&rsquo;t try to find a decent, reasonably-priced cocktail in Stockholm. Cocktails are extremely expensive (think $20 up). We ended up in a hotel bar and got an overly-sweet Manhattan that barely covered the bottom of the glass it was served in.</p>

<p><em>Having said that</em>, we did get a list of cocktail bar recommendations from someone in Stockholm. We&rsquo;ll have to go back, if only to do a local&rsquo;s tour. Most of them seemed to be in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S%C3%B6dermalm">Södermalm</a>, which is apparently the hipster area of Stockholm.</p>

<p>Anyway, we had a lot of fun in the city and I&rsquo;m sad to be leaving so soon. Like Vienna, I want to make a point of visiting again, and staying longer next time.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m writing this on a flight back to England, where we&rsquo;ll be spending the late August bank holiday weekend. After that, it&rsquo;s Paris for a week then back to the USA! It&rsquo;s strange how quickly this time has gone – it seems like no time has passed since we left San Francisco. However, there&rsquo;s still a big chunk of travel left – our trip moving south along the East Coast.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Markhalle Neun and Sage]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/20/markhalle-neun-and-sage/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-20T08:43:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/20/markhalle-neun-and-sage</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s a great indoor market called <a href="http://www.markthalleneun.de/">Markthalle Neun</a> that&rsquo;s about <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/preview?ie=UTF-8&amp;fb=1&amp;cid=10953314371184579858&amp;q=Markthalle+Neun+GmbH&amp;ei=3sHwU4q8BLDQ7Aa4tYDgCg&amp;ved=0CL0BEPwSMA4">a block away from where we&rsquo;re staying</a>. It&rsquo;s not a traditional market in that there are people selling stuff every day. On a normal day there&rsquo;s a handful of stands or mini-kitchens selling locally-made food, wine, and other stuff.</p>

<p>On Thursdays, however, there&rsquo;s a &ldquo;street food&rdquo; gathering where a lot more people show up. All the booths are filled with people selling their food – everything from pancakes to samosas to steamed buns. There&rsquo;s also a couple of food trucks outside, too. It gets incredibly packed, but it&rsquo;s a lot of fun.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Street food Thursdays</div>
</div>


<p>There&rsquo;s also a Sunday morning &ldquo;breakfast market,&rdquo; which has more of a focus on breakfast foods.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve been to a couple of these events, but mostly we go on weekdays for lunch. There&rsquo;s such a wide variety of food there it&rsquo;s difficult to go wrong. Anyway, I&rsquo;ve taken pictures of pretty much everything I&rsquo;ve eaten there, so this will mainly be a bunch of pictures of delicious food.</p>

<p>The best thing I&rsquo;ve had so far has been the barbeque from <a href="http://www.bigstuff.de/">Big Stuff Smoked BBQ</a>. It blew away most of the BBQ I&rsquo;ve had in the USA.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bbq-ribs.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bbq-ribs.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">BBQ rib sandwich</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bbq-pork.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bbq-pork.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">BBQ pork belly sandwich</div>
</div>


<p>There was a Vietnamese stall that did rice-stuffed rolls and some steamed buns.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bun.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bun.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Steamed bun with pretty much EVERYTHING inside</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-rolls.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-rolls.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Delicious rolls with rice and meat inside</div>
</div>


<p>There was a great vegetarian burger place. We accidentally went there because it had the shortest queue. Then we found out it was vegetarian, almost left, but stuck with it. The burger was so good! I think it was tofu or something, but it was mainly tasty cause they slathered it in peanut sauce.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-veggie-burger.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-veggie-burger.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The best veggie-burger I&#8217;ve ever had</div>
</div>


<p>The next place I went to, I had their veggie-burger but it sucked, so I went back to eating all meat all the time.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m English so I love savoury pies. What luck! There was a pie place in the market. I got a cheese and mince one and it was SO GOOD. I would eat ten more right now.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-pie.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-pie.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Cheese and mince pie (note: not <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mince_pie">that kind of mince pie</a>, which would probably be gross with cheese in it)</div>
</div>


<p>If you don&rsquo;t like pies (like Hampton), you can get a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reuben_sandwich">reuben sandwich</a>! It had pastrami on it. Apparently this guy from Portland moved to Berlin and was upset he couldn&rsquo;t get decent pastrami&hellip; so he opened a deli!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-reuben.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-reuben.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Reuben sandwich</div>
</div>


<p>Don&rsquo;t fancy savoury items? Well there&rsquo;s a tonne of sweet stuff, too. There&rsquo;s a great waffle place.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-waffles.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-waffles.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Making waffles</div>
</div>


<p>Usually I&rsquo;m not the biggest fan of waffles, but these were so good. Crisp on the outside and moist on the inside. Oh, and covered in caramel sauce.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-waffle-caramel.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-waffle-caramel.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">My waffle</div>
</div>


<p>The waffle place also did some crazy ice-creams&hellip;</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-icecream.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-icecream.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Raspberry and basil</div>
</div>


<p>And there was a lady selling ice-lollies (or &ldquo;popsicles&rdquo;).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-lollipop.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-lollipop.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Buttermilk and lemon</div>
</div>


<p>OK, that&rsquo;s all my Markthalle photos. We did eat some fancy food as well – at <a href="http://www.sage-restaurant.de/cms/">Sage</a>. I really like the interior of this place. It&rsquo;s in a warehouse and has lots of industrial touches – like giant chains hanging from the ceiling. But it&rsquo;s also bright due to the large windows and white canvases on the walls.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Sage interior</div>
</div>


<p>We went for a four-course Chef&rsquo;s surprise menu. It was a great choice – full of interesting flavours and ingredients that I&rsquo;d never come across before. Here&rsquo;s some pictures:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-octopus.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-octopus.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Octopus, potato foam, chorizo</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-monkfish.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-monkfish.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Monkfish, black potato purée</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-beef.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-beef.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Beef, spinach polenta, mushrooms, spiced pumpkin</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-icecream.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-icecream.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Lemon sorbet, chocolate-covered marscapone ice-cream</div>
</div>


<p>It was super-tasty and you should definitely go if you&rsquo;re in the area. Get an apéritif on the beach beforehand!</p>

<p>Our time in Berlin is almost over, and next we&rsquo;ll be heading off to Stockholm for <a href="http://hybridconf.net/">HybridConf</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drinking Around Kreuzberg]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/17/drinking-around-kreuzberg/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-17T09:39:07-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/17/drinking-around-kreuzberg</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I say &ldquo;around Kreuzberg,&rdquo; that&rsquo;s a little misleading as we haven&rsquo;t really managed to explore the whole area. Berlin is pretty massive – more like London than Paris or New York. It&rsquo;s not that easy to walk to other areas (although we did take a nice stroll over to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friedrichshain">Friedrichshain</a> a couple of times).</p>

<p>As you are probably aware, Hampton and I scouted out as many cocktail bars as we could as soon as we arrived. For the past two weeks, we&rsquo;ve been slowly venturing further from our apartment to test out other places. Here&rsquo;s our list (and <a href="https://mapsengine.google.com/map/edit?mid=zSa_dTkSRnX0.kH2Fqz02A-M4">a handy map</a>).</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not sure why, but there&rsquo;s a cocktail bar named after a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Muir">noted American environmentalist</a>: <a href="http://johnmuirberlin.com/">John Muir</a>. To be honest, I only knew about him because I&rsquo;ve made a couple of day trips up to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muir_Woods_National_Monument">Muir Woods</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-outside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-outside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Entrance to John Muir</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Bar area – it&#8217;s a little dark as it&#8217;s in a half-cellar</div>
</div>


<p>The inside is all exposed brick, with a couple of naturalist touches (like some stuffed animals). It&rsquo;s nice and cosy (but the bathrooms are disco-themed??). They have a regularly-rotating drinks menu and their custom drinks are <em>really</em> good. I got the Lightning Bug, which was a citrus-gin thing with some other delicious extras (honey and lillet, I think?).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-drinks.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-drinks.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Lightning bug and a manhattan</div>
</div>


<p>I tried a couple of other cocktails on offer, and they were also excellent. It was strange that it never seemed to get too busy. Most people ordered beer or wine, and I wanted to shout at them because the cocktails were so tasty. Overall: 8.0/10</p>

<p>Not far from John Muir is <a href="">Kirk Bar</a>. Again, not really sure why it&rsquo;s named that. Star Trek reference, maybe? Nerds.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/kirk-bar.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/kirk-bar.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside Kirk Bar</div>
</div>


<p>The inside is pretty bad-ass. It has a real crumbling old-timey feel, with a patina most bars wish they could get. Beautiful cornicing and high ceilings. The first time we went, I was pretty drunk so I&rsquo;m not sure what I ordered. I think it was a gin sour – but I remember thinking it was good.</p>

<p>When we came back, I was more sober and remembered my drink order – a Hemingway sour. It was the same as a regular gin sour, but with grenadine added. (I thought Hemingway liked rum?)</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/kirk-sours.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/kirk-sours.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">On the left, a gin sour (?), on the right, Hemingway Sour</div>
</div>


<p>Overall: 7.6/10</p>

<p>I talked briefly about <a href="http://www.sage-restaurant.de/cms/">Sage</a> <a href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/13/berlin-how-do-you-think-it-feels/">in my previous post</a> – it&rsquo;s the bar on the water. Well, there&rsquo;s also a restaurant in a warehouse building just inland from the beach area. I&rsquo;ll talk about the food in another post, but I had a pretty amazing cocktail there. It was called the London garden and looked like a juice drink I&rsquo;d find in San Francisco.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/sage-london.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/sage-london.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">London Garden</div>
</div>


<p>It wasn&rsquo;t too sweet or too savoury, and it had the right amount of texture to it. It was so much more drinkable than those juices you find. Maybe it&rsquo;s the fact that it had alcohol in it or maybe it&rsquo;s&hellip; no, it was definitely the alcohol. Overall: 7.2/10</p>

<p><a href="http://www.homes-berlin.de/">Homes</a> was a little further away from our place, but we&rsquo;d read good reviews so we made the trek. It was decorated more like a casual coffee shop than a bar – it was very open, with low seating and &ldquo;cool&rdquo; murals on the walls.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/homes-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/homes-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside Homes</div>
</div>


<p>I guess it&rsquo;s a little unfair for me to be that dismissive – we were there pretty early for Berlin drinking time. Berlin is a very late city – people only consider going to a bar or club at midnight. I&rsquo;m happy to be in bed by then. It also means that bars are pretty empty around 7pm which means (yay) there&rsquo;s usually little wait but (boo) we&rsquo;re usually the only people in there.</p>

<p>Anyway, the drinks at Homes were passable. I got a gin-cacao-lillet thing that tasted way better than the ingredients list suggested.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/homes-chocolate.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/homes-chocolate.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Gin-cacao-lillet</div>
</div>


<p>I was a little underwhelmed. Overall: 6.5/10</p>

<p><a href="http://www.yelp.de/biz/schwarze-traube-berlin">Schwarze Traube</a> (&ldquo;black grape&rdquo;) was our first cocktail bar when we arrived. It&rsquo;s less than a block away from where we&rsquo;re staying and it had really good reviews. I was pretty excited.</p>

<p>The door has a sign saying you have to &ldquo;knock and smile&rdquo; to enter, which I did. The bartender was <em>not</em> happy to see us. She kind of pointed at some seats before going back behind the bar. The place is pretty small – two or three tiny rooms. The decor is great, though, with lots of fraying antique chairs and side-tables.</p>

<p>The bartender came over and told us they had a gin-based special drink. I ordered that one, and Hampton ordered a manhattan (which elicited a big sigh from the bartender). I like the idea of a no-menu, bartender-curated drinks list but only if the bartender is nice. Anyway, the drinks came after about fifteen minutes (which was weird, as we were the only people in there). They were really bloody good, and served in equisite, delicate glassware.</p>

<p>After we&rsquo;d finished our drinks, we had to wait another twenty minutes of the bartender disappearing and/or ignoring our requests for the bill. Great cocktails, but not really worth the lacklustre service. Overall: 5.6</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Berlin: How Do You Think It Feels]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/13/berlin-how-do-you-think-it-feels/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-13T08:17:16-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/13/berlin-how-do-you-think-it-feels</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aIofRTmTYVc">Title from Lou Reed&rsquo;s album, Berlin</a>)</p>

<p>Berlin doesn&rsquo;t feel European, and it&rsquo;s not quite like anywhere else Hampton and I have visited. It doesn&rsquo;t really seem to fit any classification, there&rsquo;s so much about it that&rsquo;s unique. I get that other cities have unique qualities. Paris has&hellip; <em>Parisian</em> things about it that make it unique – but it still feels European. Berlin does not. Maybe it&rsquo;s because  of its recent tumultuous history. Maybe it&rsquo;s because the idea of &ldquo;Europeanness&rdquo; includes Paris, and London, and Rome, but somehow left out Berlin. For whatever reason, it&rsquo;s an alluring city that we made a point of returning to.</p>

<p>Last time we visited Berlin, we stayed in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prenzlauer_Berg">Prenzlauer Berg</a>, a hip ex-East Berlin neighbourhood in the north of the city. This time, we chose to stay in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kreuzberg">Kreuzberg</a>.</p>

<p>Along with Prenzlauer Berg and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friedrichshain">Friedrichshain</a>, Kreuzberg is considered to be the trendier, less-polished side of the city. Although technically in West Berlin during the separation of Germany, Kreuzberg was on the eastern edge of the city, so was relatively underdeveloped. Since the fall of the Berlin Wall, all three neighbourhoods have undergone varying levels of gentrification.</p>

<p>Coming from the obvious beauty of Prague or Amsterdam, Berlin was a little brutal. On our block, there are multiple featureless, indistinguishable mid-1970s apartment complexes. They&rsquo;re covered in graffiti and look pretty drab.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/kreuzberg-apartment.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/kreuzberg-apartment.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Typical Kreuzberg apartment building</div>
</div>


<p>So far, I&rsquo;m probably not painting a great picture of Berlin, am I? The thing that really draws Hampton and me to the city is the people and the atmosphere. I&rsquo;d call it artistic or care-free; I&rsquo;m sure an American could equally describe it as entrepreneurial. Confused? Let me try and describe an example.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re staying just off the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spree">Spree</a>. It&rsquo;s a little industrial along our side of the river, with brick warehouses and lots of gates. We saw some place recommended on FourSquare along the river, but weren&rsquo;t that sure where it was. After walking through what looked like a gate to an industrial estate, we saw a couple of shipping containers stacked on top of each other with a 1970s car on top.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar-entry.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar-entry.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Shipping container garden</div>
</div>


<p>As you continue walking towards the bank of the river, you see a makeshift beach.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Sage Bar – a beach</div>
</div>


<p>And there&rsquo;s this wonderful bar, hidden away, popular at all times of the day. Kids are running around playing in their sand as their tattooed, mid-thirties parents sip an Aperol and soda. There&rsquo;s grey-haired couples drinking tall beers, reading books. And right across the river is one of the longest <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Side_Gallery">still-standing stretches of the Berlin Wall</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar-view.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar-view.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">View over the Spree and the Berlin Wall</div>
</div>


<p>Berlin is such a strange mixture of rule-following, energy, and laissez-faireness. People are frenetic and excited on the streets, playing loud music and drinking and rushing to the next bar&hellip; before languishing the next morning over a three-hour brunch. It takes a while to get used to, but it&rsquo;s something that I find very energising and disruptive.</p>

<p>One of the strangest moments so far was going for karaoke with the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Travis_CI">Travis CI</a> folks. The karaoke bar was just across the river from Kreuzberg, in Friedrichshain. To get there, we walked along the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oberbaum_Bridge">Oberbaum bridge</a>, which used to be an East-West border crossing.</p>

<p>We then walked past a stretch of the Berlin Wall, which was turned into an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Side_Gallery">open-air gallery</a> soon after the unification of Germany.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/east-side-gallery.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/east-side-gallery.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The East Side Gallery</div>
</div>


<p>The gallery itself is really neat, and on a separate occasion we took a longer stroll along it.</p>

<p>Anyway, we got to karaoke, sang a few songs, drank a few beers. Then someone put on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%22Heroes%22_(David_Bowie_song)">&ldquo;Heroes&rdquo;</a> by David Bowie. Recorded in the 1970s in Berlin, it&rsquo;s about two lovers who can&rsquo;t be together: one is from East Berlin, and one is from West Berlin.</p>

<p>And there we were, singing about the horror of the wall, in a karaoke bar about 500ft away, having just crossed an ex-border crossing.</p>

<p>Above all, Berlin is wonderful and strange.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Food and Drink in Amsterdam]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/09/amsterdam-food/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-09T07:20:31-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/09/amsterdam-food</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We visited a couple of great cocktail bars while in Amsterdam. The first was <a href="http://www.door-74.com/">Door 74</a>. You need to phone up to get a reservation, but we did that literally minutes before knocking on the door, and they had a table.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Unassuming door</div>
</div>


<p>The menu was neat. I got the impression it was seasonal, as it was heavily themed on 60s sci-fi despite the bar not having anything remotely about that. They had a few drinks from every planet. Each drink had a ray-gun indicator next to it showing how strong the drink was.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-menu.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-menu.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Menu</div>
</div>


<p>Our friend got the special, some blend of vodka and fruit juice that was served in a tiki container. It was poured at the table, which was neat.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-kettle.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-kettle.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The special – poured out of a dry-ice kettle</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-gin.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-gin.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Tezuka&#8217;s Lost World</div>
</div>


<p>The other place we enjoyed was <a href="http://njoycocktails.com/">NJoy</a>. It&rsquo;s slightly odd – there&rsquo;s lots of neon lighting and trying-hard-to-be-hip furniture, like a scene out of Sex and the City.</p>

<p>The menu was arranged into pretentious categories – each a supposed personality type. Are you an Alchemist or a Trendsetter? A Dreamer or a Connoisseur? The drinks were all novel and had some really interesting combinations of flavours. The bartenders were really friendly and the drinks were well-made and delicious – and that&rsquo;s why we kept coming back.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-chartreuse.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-chartreuse.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Something with Chartreuse that I ordered</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-monkey.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-monkey.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Monkey&#8217;s Martini</div>
</div>


<p>A word of warning: NJoy is located on &ldquo;restaurant row&rdquo; (Leidsedwarsstraat). It&rsquo;s full of possibly the most pushy restaurants I&rsquo;ve ever walked past. In super-touristy areas, I&rsquo;m used to people asking, &ldquo;You looking for a place to eat? We have delicious steak!&rdquo; and me ignoring them. This was a whole other level. People hold menus in your face, they block your way, they won&rsquo;t let you past unless you&rsquo;ve responded to them. Our tactic to avoid this as best as we could was to appear to be in a heated debate as we rapidly walked the gauntlet.</p>

<p>Anyway, onto food. When travelling, I enjoy eating the local food. <a href="https://twitter.com/roy">Roy</a>, our Dutch friend who met us on our first night in Amsterdam, explained that there&rsquo;s not much that&rsquo;s considered Dutch cuisine. It&rsquo;s mostly French food or German. Anyway, we tried our best and visited <a href="http://www.thepantry.nl/">The Pantry</a>. They called themselves Dutch cuisine, so hey, let&rsquo;s give it a go.</p>

<p>I got a trio of what were essentially mashed potatoes with other stuff in them. In the picture below, starting from the top and going clockwise, there&rsquo;s:</p>

<ul>
<li>Zuurkoolstamppot (sauerkraut)</li>
<li>Hustpot (beef, carrots, onions)</li>
<li>Boerenkoolstamppot (kale)</li>
</ul>


<p>(with a meatball in the middle)</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/potatoes.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/potatoes.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Mashed potatoes</div>
</div>


<p>The sauerkraut one was the best. Nom nom.</p>

<p>The other thing that seemed to be everywhere was pancakes. We went to a pancake place and saw they had <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poffertjes">poffertjes</a> – a kind of cross between beignets and American-style pancakes. They were served with butter and icing sugar. Very healthy.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/poffertjes.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/poffertjes.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Poffertjes</div>
</div>


<p>We went for a memorable meal at a steak and ribs place – <a href="http://www.castellamsterdam.nl/en/">Castell</a>. We made a reservation, showed up on time, and the waiter showed us to our table. We were a little confused. Rather than a regular dining table, it was coffee table-height, and our seats were leather benches surrounding one end (another group was at the other end).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-table.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-table.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Our table (we ordered some escargot)</div>
</div>


<p>We weren&rsquo;t quite sure whether this was a pre-dinner drink table or what. But soon we received some wicker trays, one per person, on which to eat our steaks.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-lap.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-lap.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hampton with his tray</div>
</div>


<p>I got the ribs, and Hampton got a steak. They came on wooden blocks with little copper pans of sauce, and were delivered onto our trays. Eating was challenging, to say the least. There was no real space to put your tray if you needed to get up. I couldn&rsquo;t really reach my drink without my shirt getting ribs all over it. It was <em>not</em> easy.</p>

<p><strong>But</strong> (and it&rsquo;s a big one) – those ribs were amazing. No, seriously – possibly the best ribs I&rsquo;ve ever had (and I&rsquo;ve spent time in the South). The meat was tender, falling off the bone, and had a crisp char. The rub they used had just the right balance of vinegar, spice, and sugar. I&rsquo;d <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aYsLh4QjBPc#t=16">step over my own mother</a> for those ribs.</p>

<p>Something we noticed in Amsterdam – the service is slow. Exceptionally slow. Even taking into account European-style service (which we&rsquo;re both fine with!), Amsterdam added an extra level to that. Not sure why, but there you go.</p>

<p>Anyway, now we&rsquo;re in Berlin for a couple of weeks. We&rsquo;re staying in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kreuzberg">Kreuzberg</a> district, so stay tuned for posts about that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Museums in Amsterdam]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/04/amsterdam-museums/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-04T10:36:21-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/04/amsterdam-museums</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We toured the four main museums in Amsterdam: the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rijksmuseum">Rijksmuseum</a>, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Van_Gogh_Museum">Van Gogh Museum</a>, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anne_Frank_House">Anne Frank House</a> and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stedelijk_Museum_Amsterdam">Stedelijk Museum</a>. For the first three Hampton&rsquo;s Dad bought tickets beforehand – which I&rsquo;d highly recommend doing as the lines looked hellish. For the last one, Hampton and I rolled up at 4pm on a Sunday (with closing time at 6pm) and waltzed right in.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/rijksmuseum.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/rijksmuseum.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Rijksmuseum, canal-side</div>
</div>


<p>The Rijksmuseum has recently undergone a huge rennovation, re-opening in April 2013. It certainly shows – the internal atrium is beautiful and the layout is intuitive. <strong>Pro-tip</strong>: don&rsquo;t pay €5 for the museum audio guide! The museum has a free app for iPhone/iPod – with all the same information on it. Use that instead! They even have free wi-fi in the museum if you forget to download it before you get there.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/rijksmuseum-atrium.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/rijksmuseum-atrium.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Rijksmuseum atrium</div>
</div>


<p>The app offers a 90-minute &ldquo;highlights&rdquo; tour, which we did. I could have spent more time in the Dutch masters area (on the second floor) – the highlights tour only looked at a couple of paintings there. The impressionist and romantic areas were a little less exciting.</p>

<p>The museum itself is <em>packed</em>. Admittedly, we are in the middle of tourist season, but I expected it to be slightly quieter on a Monday. It was difficult to get a peaceful moment with any painting – but I guess that&rsquo;s what happens when a museum is closed for a while and it&rsquo;s also the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_most_visited_art_museums_in_the_world">19th most visited museum in the world</a>.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a couple of super-famous paintings on the tour, the most famous being the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Night_Watch">Night Watch</a> by Rembrandt. Of course, it was in an insanely-crowded room. It was pretty easy to get close, though.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/rijksmuseum-nightwatch.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/rijksmuseum-nightwatch.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Who watches the Night Watch?</div>
</div>


<p>The information cards they had were really useful. They circle particular elements of the painting, drawing out background figures or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Night_Watch#Acts_of_vandalism">where someone slashed the painting</a>.</p>

<p>I also really liked <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Milkmaid_(Vermeer)">The Milkmaid</a> by Vermeer. I could have spent a while looking at that painting. The rest of the museum was a little repetetive, especially the ground floor, which had a lot of medieval carvings.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/rijksmuseum-carcosa.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/rijksmuseum-carcosa.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Please show me to Carcosa, creepy chandelier lady</div>
</div>


<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Van_Gogh_Museum">Van Gogh Museum</a> was quite different from what I was expecting. There was a heavy emphasis on his development as an artist and his interaction with contemporaries.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/van-gogh-museum.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/van-gogh-museum.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The Van Gogh Museum</div>
</div>


<p>I was prepared to see gallery after gallery of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sunflowers_(Van_Gogh_series)">sunflowers</a> or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Olive_Trees_(Van_Gogh_series)">olive trees</a>, but in fact there was a lot more range in his style than I had previously thought. There were a number of Japanese-influenced paintings which had some aspect of the Van Gogh style I knew, but in a completely different context. There were also a lot of muted paintings, absent of his usually vivid palette – one of a bird&rsquo;s nest in particular stood out.</p>

<p>Being fans of contemporary art, it&rsquo;s probably no surprise that the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stedelijk_Museum_Amsterdam">Stedelijk Museum</a> was our favourite. The building has a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stedelijk_Museum_Amsterdam#mediaviewer/File:Stedelijk_Museum_1.jpg">giant bathtub-shaped</a> entrance, which is awesome. All the walls inside are painted white, and going from the ground floor to the first floor is a mesmerising experience – there&rsquo;s neon art all around the upstairs atrium, so you walk into a glowing otherworld.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/stede-atrium.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/stede-atrium.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Going up to the first floor</div>
</div>


<p>On some of the columns downstairs, there&rsquo;s a cool set of porcelain plates by John Knight. They&rsquo;re from the Autotypes series. Each one has a blueprint of an extension to a city&rsquo;s modern art museum. They reduce the buildings to nothing but floor plans, and we both loved them. I want some for our house.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/stede-knight.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/stede-knight.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Autotypes, John Knight</div>
</div>


<p>Downstairs traces modern art from 1900-1950, whereas upstairs does 1950-present day. The art is mostly displayed chronologically, and they had some great unfamiliar pieces by famous artists. I love seeing new works by great artists (maybe that&rsquo;s why I don&rsquo;t like the &ldquo;greatest hits&rdquo; style of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Museum_of_Modern_Art">MoMA</a>?).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/stede-lichtenstein.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/stede-lichtenstein.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Stunning and bold <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roy_Lichtenstein">Lichtenstein</a></div>
</div>


<p>As well as contemporary art, there was a large section of the museum devoted to design. There were lots of fun household items from the 1960s and 1970s.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/stede-tv.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/stede-tv.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Futuristic TV</div>
</div>


<p>There was also <a href="http://www.stedelijk.nl/en/exhibitions/the-gijsemmy-spectacle">a special exhibition/retrospective on Gijs+Emmy</a>, a couple who revolutionised jewelry in the 1960s. One of their first exhibitions was in the museum, and it was neat seeing videos of their models back then. Their necklaces were more like cowls than dainty chains, obscuring most of the model&rsquo;s face.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/stede-gijs+emmy.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/stede-gijs+emmy.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Gijs + Emmy necklace</div>
</div>


<p>The museum had a lot of works that seemed to be crafted for them specifically. It was nice catching glimpses of how the museum itself had fitted into the history of modern art – a self-awareness that&rsquo;s lacking in a lot of museums.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anne_Frank_House">Anne Frank House</a> is in the west of Amsterdam, and you should definitely pre-purchase tickets. The line to get in was about an hour long, even at night. We had timed tickets and didn&rsquo;t have to wait at all for our 8pm slot.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/anne-frank-house.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/anne-frank-house.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The house itself</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/anne-frank-door.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/anne-frank-door.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Main door (you enter the museum a couple of doors down)</div>
</div>


<p>I&rsquo;d never read <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Diary_of_a_Young_Girl">The Diary of a Young Girl</a> before, so I started it in preparation for visiting the house. I&rsquo;m certainly glad I did – it made the house much more atmospheric. It was strange reading the diary and later on that day seeing quotes on the walls from the diary itself, or reading the actual page on which she wrote that entry.</p>

<p>Inside the house, you can&rsquo;t take photos. But it was incredibly well-preserved. You walk through the old warehouse and offices in the front of the building, through a secret bookcase (the <em>actual bookcase</em> that was built in 1942 for the purpose of obscuring the hiding place) and into the annex. I was expecting an attic, but the living space was split over two floors and certainly more of an &ldquo;annex&rdquo; to the main house.</p>

<p>In Anne&rsquo;s room, she had glued pictures onto the wall from a magazine she used to have. The pictures were still there – it looked like a normal child&rsquo;s room. There were marks on the wall measuring how tall Anne and her sister had become over their two years in hiding. It was incredibly moving seeing remnants of a life that you knew didn&rsquo;t end well.</p>

<p>There were also exhibits on the diary itself (the <em>actual</em> diary she wrote in) and her father&rsquo;s role in getting it published. Both <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Otto_Frank">Anne&rsquo;s father</a> and the people who helped keep the annex a secret lived long after the war, and helped to put together the museum. There are video clips of them talking about their experiences, which adds an extra level to the museum.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not sure I can say I <em>enjoyed</em> the museum, but it was deeply humbling and emotional. Definitely a must-do if you&rsquo;re in Amsterdam.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Touring Amsterdam]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/02/amsterdam/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-02T10:57:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/02/amsterdam</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was always a little ashamed that I&rsquo;d never visited Amsterdam. It&rsquo;s only a short flight from London and people always list it as a highlight of Europe. Hampton&rsquo;s parents were in Amsterdam for a week, so we decided to join them and find out what all the fuss was about.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/canal.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/canal.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Houses along the canal, a bridge, and cyclists</div>
</div>


<p>In a lot of ways, Amsterdam was exactly what I was expecting. Canals criss-crossed with beautiful bridges, cyclists going far too fast.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/touring.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/touring.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hampton and his Dad as we wandered around the canals</div>
</div>


<p>We decided to do a walking tour on foot. We stayed near the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leidseplein">Leidseplein</a>, and walking all the way to the center took about 40 minutes. We walked to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dam_Square">Dam Square</a>, the centre of the city. It was nice, but touristy. You had to pay to go in the church or the palace, and we skipped both of them.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/dam-palace.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/dam-palace.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Royal Palace in Dam</div>
</div>


<p>What I would recommend is taking a canal boat around the city. We used the <a href="https://www.canal.nl/en/canal-bus">Canal Bus</a>, which is advertised as a hop-on/hop-off tour. However we just used it to see the city from another angle.</p>

<p>It stopped at most of the standard things – Dam Square, the Anne Frank House, Rembrandt&rsquo;s House, etc. – but it was nice to see some other bits of the city. In particular, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EYE_Film_Institute_Netherlands">Eye Film Institute</a> had a beautiful building.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/eyefilm.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/eyefilm.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Eye Film Institute</div>
</div>


<p>It&rsquo;s across the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IJ_(Amsterdam)">IJ</a> (the main waterfront of Amsterdam) from most of the city, and it&rsquo;s something we wouldn&rsquo;t have seen by just walking.</p>

<p>Another pro-tip: walk around at dusk. Especially in the summer, it&rsquo;s so relaxed and the houses look inviting. There are often people having parties on boats and people dining along the canals.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/dusk.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/dusk.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Dusk over houses</div>
</div>


<p>There&rsquo;s definitely a lot more to the city than hookers and weed (although you can find those in certain areas if you must).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AnonymouS Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/30/anonymous-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-30T04:10:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/30/anonymous-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>Our time in Prague is almost at an end – today, we&#8217;re taking a flight to Amsterdam. We saved an intriguing bar for our last new experience in the cocktail world of Prague. <a href="http://www.anonymousbar.cz/cs"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">AnonymouS Bar</span></a> (their weird capitalisation, not mine) is off a small alley in the old town, and it is themed around the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gunpowder_Plot">gunpowder plot</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/V_for_Vendetta">V for Vendetta</a>, and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anonymous_(group)">Anonymous</a> movement.</p>

  <p>Inside, the bar is styled like the interior of V&#8217;s hideout in the comic book/film. It allows the use of comfortable chairs, but also brick-showing-through-plaster murals and classic portraits with faces replaced by the Guy Fawkes mask. It kind of reminded us (in the best way possible, as we&#8217;re theme park nerds) of a Universal Studios or Disney experience.</p>

  <p>The menu has a really great concept: a list of standard drinks on one page, paired up with an AnonymouS-bar twist on the classics. It was a goodway to quickly pick out a drink you&#8217;d be sure to like. I went for the St Marry&#8217;s Virus – again, that&#8217;s their weird spelling, and I&#8217;m not sure if it&#8217;s deliberate or not. It was a twist on the Piccadilly martini. The bartender came over with a biohazard box, which opened to reveal a giant syringe containing the cocktial.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-st-marrys.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-st-marrys.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">St Marry&#8217;s Virus</div>
  </div>

  <p>Hampton went for a take on a gimlet, and it was really delicious! I think they added cucumber and some other stuff.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-butterfly.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-butterfly.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">M. Butterfly</div>
  </div>

  <p>The menu, aside from the drink and liquor list, was pretty entertaining. They had neat explanation of their thought process behind the concept. As I was flicking through, I noticed there was a cocktail set apart from the rest, alone on the very first page. It didn&#8217;t have a description, aside from the old rhyme: &#8220;Remember, remember the fifth of November&#8230;&#8221; It was too puzzling not to get.</p>

  <p>Hampton got it after me, so I have photos of what it entailed. The bartender handed you a Guy Fawkes mask and took your photo.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-photo.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-photo.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">They had to find more film</div>
  </div>

  <p>After that, they make the drink. It involved lining a brandy snifter with liquor and setting it on fire. Once the fire had died down, they poured in a whisky-based old-fashioned-esque cocktail. They placed the photo on top to stop the smoke from the flames coming out.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-remember.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-remember.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Remember</div>
  </div>

  <p>Here are the photos of our night. It&#8217;s nice to have something to keep after a night out. Especially once you&#8217;ve had a few cocktails.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-polaroid.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-polaroid.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Ahh, memories!</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">The themeing theatricality of AnonymouS bar is great, but it&#8217;s really backed up by the delicious cocktails on offer.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">8.5</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[La Degustation]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/27/la-degustation/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-27T05:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/27/la-degustation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.ladegustation.cz/en/#index"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">La Degustation</span></a>, one of two restaurants in Prague to have <a href="http://www.viamichelin.com/web/Restaurants/Restaurants-Prague-_-Praha_hlavni_mesto-Czech_Republic?strLocid=31MzhkeDEwY05UQXVNRGczT0RFPWNNVFF1TkRJd05EWT0=">a Michelin star</a>, was our special treat as our time in Prague is coming to an end. Its slogan is &#8220;bohême bourgeoise,&#8221; which I found amusing.</p>

  <p>Inside, I don&#8217;t know if anything can be gothic minimalist, but I think that&#8217;s an accurate description. Arches ribbed the ceiling, and artfully-placed dim spotlights created wonderful shadows. The walls were bare and painted a light grey, and the furniture was all low-backed and dark wood. The windows onto the street had the restaurant&#8217;s signature checkered pattern.</p>

  <p>As we sat down, the waiter came over and gave us an envelope.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/envelope.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/envelope.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">We were handed an envelope</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/back-envelope.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/back-envelope.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The back of the envelope</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/contents.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/contents.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Open it to find the checkered pattern</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/menu.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/menu.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Two menu options</div>
  </div>

  <p>We went for the eleven-course menu, with wine pairings. It was definitely a lot of food, and I wish I hadn&#8217;t eaten so much of the delicious bread they brought. The menu focussed on Czech ingredients and dishes, but with modern, vaguely molecular-gastronomic twists. Apparently a lot of the inspiration for their dishes comes from a late-19th century Czech cookbook.</p>

  <p>I didn&#8217;t take pictures and I won&#8217;t bore you with a course-by-course detailing of everything. A couple of stand-out dishes, though: dijon mustard ice-cream with hot tomato sauce. The sauce was the perfect distillation of tomato flavour. Add that to the mustard (which wasn&#8217;t too spicy), plus the mixing of the hot sauce with the cold ice-cream and you get an incredible dish that&#8217;s not quite like anything I&#8217;ve had before.</p>

  <p>There was a foie gras course where the liver had been finely grated over wine jelly and pistachio. I&#8217;d never eaten foie gras grated before, and it really helped take away the heaviness you sometimes get. Then there was the beef tongue &#8220;signature dish.&#8221; </p>

  <p>I really enjoyed the wine pairings. They used mostly Czech wines, and it was nice to see the variety in types they produce here. There was also a great unfiltered Slovenian wine called <a href="http://www.scurek.com/www/index.php/en/wines/white-wines">Kontra</a>. The cheese course came with a delicious IPA from the <a href="http://www.beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/23493/">Matuška Brewery</a>.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">If you&#8217;re willing to splash out, this place is definitely worth it. It&#8217;s a modern take on Czech flavours and ingredients, and the courses are presented beautifully.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">9.3</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Touring the Jewish Quarter of Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/25/jewish-quarter-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-25T06:58:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/25/jewish-quarter-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Josefov">Jewish Quarter</a> (or Josefov) of Prague is in the Old Town, just north of the Old Town Square. We&rsquo;d been told that the <a href="http://www.jewishmuseum.cz/en/apinkas.htm">Pinkas Synagogue</a> was a must-see, so we set off on a visit without learning much about it. All I knew was that it&rsquo;s now a memorial to victims of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Holocaust">Holocaust</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Pinkas Synagogue from the outside</div>
</div>


<p>We arrived at lunchtime and the queue was really long and slow-moving. Not good.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-queue.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-queue.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Long queue waiting for tickets</div>
</div>


<p>However! We found an EXPERT WORK-AROUND for buying tickets without having to wait in line. Head slightly east on the same road and take the first left. You&rsquo;ll find <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Maiselova+38%2F15,+110+00+Praha-Praha+1,+Czech+Republic/@50.089592,14.4181715,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x470b94e8669ff2a5:0xb73abb80fc435169">a ticketing office</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ticket-office.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ticket-office.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Just around the corner – under 2 mins walk.</div>
</div>


<p>There was no queue and we got our tickets immediately. You can&rsquo;t buy a single ticket to see the synagogues/museums of Josefov individually – you have to buy a multi-attraction ticket. The most basic ticket was 300Kč (~$15) for four attractions: the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Jewish_Cemetery,_Prague">Old Jewish Cemetery</a>, the <a href="http://www.jewishmuseum.cz/en/aklaus.htm">Klausen Synagogue</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jewish_Ceremonial_Hall,_Prague">Ceremonial Hall</a>, and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_Synagogue_(Prague)">Spanish Synagogue</a>. You could pay 100Kč more if you wanted to see the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_New_Synagogue,_Prague">Old New Synagogue</a>, but we gave that one a miss. The ticket is valid over seven days, though, which is good if you don&rsquo;t have enough time to visit all the places in one day.</p>

<p>After we bought our tickets we went back to the Pinkas Synagogue and sailed past the line there to buy tickets.</p>

<p>The inside of the Pinkas Synagogue serves as a memorial to the 80,000 Bohemian and Moravian Jews that were victims of the Holocaust.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-room.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-room.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside the synagogue</div>
</div>


<p>There were about five rooms like the one above – and see those red and black, floor-to-ceiling patches that line the walls? Those are the victims&#8217; names, birth-dates and death-dates. Across the rooms they&rsquo;re written out like that, in letters maybe a centimetre high.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-names.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-names.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Names, births and deaths of victims</div>
</div>


<p>At first, you don&rsquo;t quite understand it. Then as you start reading, seeing the families grouped together, it&rsquo;s a little overwhelming. Especially when you see room after room of them. It was powerful stuff, and something I&rsquo;d recommend everyone do while they&rsquo;re in Prague.</p>

<p>After exiting the synagogue, you walk through the Old Jewish Cemetery. While not that large geographically, it apparently contains over 12,000 tombstones.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Old Jewish Cemetery</div>
</div>


<p>Needless to say, it was crowded with graves. The tombstones stuck out at all kinds of angles, and many were only just sticking out of the soil.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery2.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery2.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Another view of the cemetery</div>
</div>


<p>The cemetary exit leaves you just outside of Ceremonial Hall and the Klausen Synagogue. As we already had the multi-ticket, we decided to give them a visit.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Ceremonial Hall outside</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall-floor.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall-floor.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Ceremonial Hall tiled floor</div>
</div>


<p>The Ceremonial Hall used to be a kind of mortuary, so had a bunch of exhibits on the rituals surrounding death in Judaism. It was kind of interesting, but mostly just items in display cases.</p>

<p>The Klausen Synagogue was similar. Apart from the Pinkas Synagogue earlier on, I&rsquo;d never been inside a synagogue before. I&rsquo;m not quite sure what I was expecting from the inside of a synagogue, but I was kind of disappointed that it looked just like a Christian church.</p>

<p>Inside the main area of the Klausen Synagogue, there were display cases showing items relating to Judaism. I found it a little strange. I almost wanted the museum part and the religious-building part to be more separate. Maybe it&rsquo;s just because I wasn&rsquo;t expecting it to be so much of a museum.</p>

<p>After leaving the Klausen Synagogue, the route to the next stop on our ticket took us past the Old New Synagogue. I only learnt afterwards that it&rsquo;s Europe&rsquo;s oldest active synagogue. Apparently, its attic is also the storage place for the infamous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golem#The_classic_narrative:_The_Golem_of_Prague">Golem of Prague</a> (<em>spooky noises</em>).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/old-new.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/old-new.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Old New Synagogue</div>
</div>


<p>We continued walking, made a couple of quick turns, and found ourselves at the Spanish Synagogue. Not much to look at from the outside, inside it&rsquo;s absolutely stunning.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Spanish Synagogue interior</div>
</div>


<p>The walls are covered in intricate patterns, mostly using reds and golds. The Star of David appears in motifs everywhere, and I spent ages just following the patterns and their interplay across the walls. The central dome is beautiful and has a Star of David-shaped chandelier in the centre.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish-dome.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish-dome.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Dome of the Spanish Synagogue</div>
</div>


<p>Fun fact: it doesn&rsquo;t seem to be clear why it&rsquo;s called the Spanish Synagogue. One theory is that the interior design reminded people of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golden_age_of_Jewish_culture_in_Spain">&ldquo;Golden Age&rdquo;</a> of Judaism in Spain. Another theory is that it used to be a location for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romaniotes">Byzantine Jewish</a> worship, and that led to legends of the Iberian <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sephardi_Jews">Sephardi Jews</a> once worshipping there.</p>

<p>Like the Klausen Synagogue, the Spanish Synagogue is a museum as well as a religious building. I was mostly distracted by the detailing on the walls, but I did look at a couple of the display cases in the upper balconies. They were pretty interesting, detailing the history of Josefov across the centuries. If it hadn&rsquo;t been over 30ºC in there, I would have stayed longer.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m glad we ended up seeing more of the Jewish Quarter than just the Pinkas Synagogue, but I&rsquo;m not sure I&rsquo;d see the Klausen Synagogu and the Ceremonial Hall if I were pushed for time. I definitely found it more rewarding than most of Prague Castle, though. I made a <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/dir/Maiselova+38%2F15,+110+00+Praha,+Czech+Republic/Pinkas+Synagogue,+%C5%A0irok%C3%A1+23%2F3,+110+00+Praha,+Czech+Republic/Klausov%C3%A1+synagoga,+U+star%C3%A9ho+h%C5%99bitova+3a,+110+00+Praha-Josefov,+Czech+Republic/The+Old-New+Synagogue,+Maiselova+18,+110+01+Praha+1,+Czech+Republic/50.0900973,14.4211259/@50.090032,14.4178231,18z/data=!4m32!4m31!1m5!1m1!1s0x470b94e8669ff2a5:0xb73abb80fc435169!2m2!1d14.4181715!2d50.089592!1m5!1m1!1s0x470b94e85e9af185:0x294f2ae19539722d!2m2!1d14.416972!2d50.089277!1m5!1m1!1s0x470b94e877e558db:0xdd1a2cc59bf35380!2m2!1d14.417069!2d50.09002!1m10!1m1!1s0x470b94e868e5c8c9:0x94be0e2fdb884bfa!2m2!1d14.418567!2d50.090051!3m4!1m2!1d14.4190562!2d50.0899754!3s0x470b94e844b3b4d3:0x32c184f0e15a1660!1m0!3e2">map of the route we took</a> – but note that the bit from the Pinkas to Klausen is through the cemetery rather than around Maiselova.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orange Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/orange-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-23T04:33:48-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/orange-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.orangebar.cz/en/homepage.html"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Orange Bar</span></a> is pretty close by to us and has decent reviews. It&#8217;s a little tricky to find, down a couple of side-streets, but there&#8217;s a nice orange-shaped sign outside to let you know when you&#8217;re there.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/outside.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/outside.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">From the street</div>
  </div>

  <p>From the outside, it looks pretty normal, right? Inside, though, it reminded me of a bar in Dune or something. The only lights had orange filters, and all the walls were molded to give the appearance of being dug out of a cave.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/bar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/bar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The bar (I think the spice is kept on the top shelf)</div>
  </div>

  <p>The bar shelves were all integrated into the back wall. The other walls had fake columns with cubbies for desert plants.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/plants.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/plants.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Walls with plants</div>
  </div>

  <p>The cocktail list leaned heavily towards rum-based beach drinks – mai tais, piña coladas, zombies etc. There&#8217;s also a good list of classics, too. Hampton went for (of course) a manhattan. I tried out the mai tai but it was a little too sweet for me.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/cocktails.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/cocktails.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Manhattan and a mai tai</div>
  </div>

  <p>We were there during a massive thunderstorm and didn&#8217;t have umbrellas, so we stayed for another round (or two). The moscow mule was <em>much</em> better. Get that! It had a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physalis_peruviana">physalis</a> garnish too, which is awesome.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/moscow-mule.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/moscow-mule.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Moscow mule</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Orange bar has a neighbourhood feel and a fun theme. The drinks are sweet, but tasty, so I&#8217;d stick to non-tiki drinks (unless you&#8217;re a particular fan).</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">7.1</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hoffa, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/hoffa-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-23T04:32:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/hoffa-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>For some reason, there&#8217;s a bar in Prague named after <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jimmy_Hoffa">Jimmy Hoffa</a>, the American union leader who went missing in the 70s. Unfortunately, my lack of Czech skills (and poor Google translating) don&#8217;t help much with the &#8220;About&#8221; page on the <a href="http://hoffa.cz"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Hoffa</span></a> website.</p>

  <p>First and foremost: this is a non-smoking bar! Yay! That automatically gets you points in my book. Most bars have smoking and non-smoking areas, but that&#8217;s not quite the same. Location-wise, it&#8217;s on a little intersection near the main train station (so great for people-watching), and has big windows. The decor is neat – they have a massive trompe-l&#8217;œil mural on one side so it looks like you&#8217;re in a warehouse.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-mural.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-mural.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Mural in Hoffa</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-bar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-bar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The bar</div>
  </div>

  <p>They have mostly traditional drinks, with some specials on a chalkboard. The drink I had was pretty good, but nothing amazing. I went for a glass of Pimm&#8217;s as it was ridiculously hot outside.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-pimms.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-pimms.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Pimm&#8217;s!</div>
  </div>

  <p>They offer decent bar snacks, too. We got some tortilla chips with salsa and sour cream.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-tortillas.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-tortillas.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Tortilla chips with salsa and sour cream</div>
  </div>

  <p>We also got some hamburgers, which were amazing. They were juicy, cooked medium-rare, and had spicy-sweet secret sauce on them. Delicious!</p>

  <p>The bathroom doors were pretty neat, too.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-mural.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-bathroom.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Bathroom door</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">I can see us returning to this place for its relaxed atmosphere, neat interior, and reasonably-priced decent drinks. It seemed like a nice place to call your local.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">7.0</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zinc Lounge, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/21/zinc-lounge-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-21T05:52:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/21/zinc-lounge-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>After the underwhelming experience at <a href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/19/cloud-9-prague">Cloud 9</a>, I wanted to try out the bar at the other Prague-based Hilton: <a href="http://www.hiltonpragueoldtown.com/loungebar-en.html"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Zinc Lounge and Bar</span></a>, found in the <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Hilton+Prague+Old+Town/@50.088515,14.431864,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x63a407a250359dc7">Hilton Prague Old Town</a>. I wanted to see how it measured up, and in short: it was pretty bad. Please forgive me, Cloud 9, I didn&#8217;t realise your sister bar was so awful. I would have cut you some slack otherwise!</p>

  <p>The Hilton Prague Old Town is pretty easy to find compared with the other Hilton. It&#8217;s just off Náměstí Republiky, one of the main squares in the Old Town. The Zinc Bar and Lounge is just to the right as you come in. &#8220;Zinc&#8221; is also the name of the hotel restaurant, just behind the bar</p>

  <p>Inside, it&#8217;s decorated like a dreary hotel lobby. Leather seats and low, round wooden tables. Holey partitions of wood try to separate the actual hotel lobby from the bar. Despite their best efforts, we were still drinking around a bunch of people loudly chatting on Skype (I assume there&#8217;s free wi-fi in the lobby area) and wheeling their luggage around, waiting for their ride to the airport.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-bar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-bar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Zinc Bar</div>
  </div>

  <p>The menu consisted almost entirely of classic cocktails. There was nothing inventive or fancy like at Cloud 9. We stuck to our staples and got a gimlet and a manhattan. They were both OK – competently done and similar to what you could find at a lot of bars in Prague.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-cocktails.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-cocktails.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Drinks: gimlet and a manhattan</div>
  </div>

  <p>The thing is, these cocktails were 220Kč (~$11) each. And there was me going off on how expensive the Cloud 9 cocktails were, at 185Kč (~$9)! Like I said in the beginning, I&#8217;M SORRY CLOUD 9. The Cloud 9 cocktails were far more reasonably-priced (I still think they&#8217;re expensive, though). At least you get something different, innovative. At Zinc you get a standard cocktail that at another bar (say, Groove Bar) would be 100Kč (~$5).</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-interior.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-interior.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Hampton looking SUPREMELY DISAPPOINTED</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Put together the atmosphere of the hotel lobby with the fact that the drinks were exceedinly expensive for what they were, and you get a disappointing experience. I&#8217;d suggest venturing a little out of the hotel to find a better cocktail bar.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">4.6</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud 9, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/19/cloud-9-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-19T05:39:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/19/cloud-9-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.cloud9.cz/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Cloud 9</span></a> (or, in full, Cloud 9 Sky Bar & Lounge) is located in the <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/preview?safe=off&ie=UTF-8&fb=1&cid=4324379790027078551&q=Hilton+Prague+Hotel&ei=BVnGU-X9E-aV7Ab6loCQDQ&ved=0CMQBEPwSMAo">Hilton</a>, just east of the central Old Town district of Prague. It&#8217;s got pretty good reviews, most extolling the views over Prague. So, of course we had to go.</p>

  <p>Firstly: getting to the Hilton is surprisingly tricky. (<strong>NB</strong>: there are two Hiltons in Prague, the more central <a href="http://d1pa4et5htdsls.cloudfront.net/images/vfml/1/1/2/9/6/1/5/709926e0_prgothi_74095_s-original.jpg">Hilton Prague Old Town</a> and the <a href="http://www.hotels-in-czech.com/clfiles/photos/big/29-hilton-budova.jpg">Hilton Prague</a>. This is in the latter.) It&#8217;s strange how much Prague changes between the first and eighth districts. It quickly goes from windy cobblestone streets to broad roads and unfriendly pedestrian crossings. The Hilton itself takes up a whole square block, yet finding the right route to get there – even finding the right entrance to use – was confusing. We just about managed by following the tourists forming a trail on their way to the Old Town.</p>

  <p>Once you&#8217;ve found your way in (use the west entrance to the Hilton, and take a sharp right for the lift to the ninth floor), the views are the first thing that strike you. It was early evening as we came in, and the sun slowly setting gave some nice cloud patterns. However, I guess I was expecting more of a grand view of the <em>centre</em> of Prague. Instead, you get a beautiful view of the Allianz building next door.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-west.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-west.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The view west, towards the centre of Prague</div>
  </div>

  <p>I suppose I&#8217;m being a little harsh – you can just see the top of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_of_Our_Lady_before_T%C3%BDn">Church of Our Lady before Týn</a> on the left. </p>
  
  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-tyn.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-tyn.png">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">I found <span class="strike">Wally</span> the Church!</div>
  </div>

  <p>The north and east views are nicer – but more pastoral than the gothic spires I was imagining.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-north.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-north.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The view north</div>
  </div>

  <p>The bar itself was decorated like a hotel bar. Clean lines, mirrors everywhere, leather-backed chairs. They had a couple of outside seating areas, but these were filled up with hotel guests.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/bar-interior.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/bar-interior.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Interior of the bar.</div>
  </div>

  <p>Speaking of the clientele, I wasn&#8217;t too surprised to find it filled with tourists. It was early (7pm), the bar is tricky to find, and it&#8217;s a <em>hotel bar</em>, so you&#8217;re not going to get an authentic Czech experience. Even so, the groups of English/North American tourists asking the waitress to pronounce &#8220;Na zdraví!&#8221; (&#8220;Cheers!&#8221;) over and over was grating. But onto the cocktails!</p>

  <p>The menu was interesting, and had a good mix of classics plus some that had been made up in the bar. Their inventions all had new-agey, etherial names like SUNSHINE and MYSTIC and DESIRE. Their most famous cocktail (according to them, at least) is the CHARISMA.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Charisma</div>
  </div>

  <p>The Charisma is so famous that it has intricate instructions for drinking.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma-instructions.jpg">
      </a><img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma-instructions
      .jpg">
    <div class="alt">Instructions for drinking</div>
  </div>

  <p>Despite that, you still look like a wally drinking something with a giant chili pepper sticking out of it.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma-drinking.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma-drinking.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Looking suave</div>
  </div>

  <p>My drinks weren&#8217;t nearly as exciting. They didn&#8217;t even have instructions on how to drink them. Sad times.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/mystic.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/mystic.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Mystic</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/desire.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/desire.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Desire (the thumbs up is for size reference, not endorsement)</div>
  </div>

  <p>The Mystic was a vodka-ginger-lime-sugar thing and was delicious. The Desire, on the other hand, tasted like what I imagine pot pourri tastes like (i.e. gross).</p>

  <p>The bar snacks were delicious. We never really found out what they were, due to the language barrier, but it seemed to be some kind of caramel-coated peanut in a crispy shell dusted in salt and dried tomato (? maybe). We scarfed them down in about five minutes.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/bar-snack.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/bar-snack.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Bar snacks</div>
  </div>

  <p>The prices were pretty crazy. I&#8217;m not sure if it&#8217;s because it&#8217;s in a hotel or because it has views (probably a little of both), it ran to about 185Kč (~$9) a drink. That may not sound like much, but they were easily the priciest cocktails we&#8217;ve had in Prague and the previous holder of that title was around 145Kč (~$7).</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">For a hotel bar, Cloud 9 is pretty decent. You have good views of Prague and some tasty cocktails. The hassle of finding it plus the prices mean it&#8217;s not really worthwhile to go unless you&#8217;re staying at the Hilton.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">6.3</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

  <p><strong>UPDATE</strong>: I went to the bar in the other Hilton and turns out, it was <a href="">way worse</a>.</p>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
