<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: France | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/france/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-29T12:20:51-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[North Paris]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/04/north-paris/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-04T12:36:25-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/04/north-paris</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before we do the North American stint of our journey, we had one final week in our favourite European city: Paris. It&rsquo;s amazing how quickly all anxieties about travel or business evaporate when we&rsquo;re sat in a café drinking some wine.</p>

<p>We were staying in an area new to us: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Montmartre">Montmartre</a>. We were situated on the north side of the hill, behind the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basilique_du_Sacr%C3%A9-C%C5%93ur,_Paris">Sacré-Cœur</a>. It was a little tricky (but by no means impossible) to get to other areas that we usually hang out in (mostly <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint-Germain-des-Pr%C3%A9s">St Germain</a> and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latin_Quarter,_Paris">Latin Quarter</a>) – so we spent a lot of time in the neighbourhood.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/sept/cafe.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/cafe.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Chilling in a café</div>
</div>


<p>One of the first things we did was walk to the Sacré-Cœur. It&rsquo;s something you can see from most of Paris, perched on the top of Montmartre like a wedding cake topper. Neither of us had been before, so we trekked up the few hundred steps to the top.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/sept/sc.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/sc.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">In front of the Sacré-Cœur</div>
</div>


<p></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s certainly a beautiful church, but the view over Paris? It&rsquo;s&hellip; OK.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/sept/view-sc.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/view-sc.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">View from the Sacré-Cœur</div>
</div>


<p>Sure, any vista over a city is kinda nice. But there just isn&rsquo;t much variation to make this one that interesting. It&rsquo;s just roofs – and you can maybe pick out the Centre Pompidou or Notre Dame in the distance if you&rsquo;re lucky.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/sept/view-sc-annotated.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/view-sc-annotated.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">View from the Sacré-Cœur, with annotations!</div>
</div>


<p>The view from the top floor of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Centre_Georges_Pompidou">Centre Pompidou</a> is much better, because you can see the stereotypical Parisian apartment buildings right there, but also see the Eiffel Tower, Notre Dame, the Sacré-Cœur, etc. in the background. It&rsquo;s a more satisfying view.</p>

<p>In short, the Sacré-Cœur looks perfectly fine from far away and I wouldn&rsquo;t bother climbing up all those steps unless you&rsquo;re really into churches.</p>

<p>Another touristy thing we did was the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mus%C3%A9e_d%27Orsay">Musée d&#8217;Orsay</a>. Housed in an old train station, it&rsquo;s renowned as one of the best collections of impressionist and post-impressionist art in the world. I&rsquo;d visited the museum before, and didn&rsquo;t really enjoy it. I was in a rush and (post-)impressionism isn&rsquo;t really my thing. Plus the queues for tickets are notorious – I&rsquo;ve heard stories of 2+ hours in line.</p>

<p>We were wandering past on a Thursday at 2pm and there was no line whatsoever for tickets. Apparently that&rsquo;s the time to go! On a whim, we went inside.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/sept/orsay.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/orsay.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Musée d&#8217;Orsay</div>
</div>


<p>It&rsquo;s a gorgeous building, and the layout is innovative. The central aisle has sculptures and off the sides are the paintings. I must admit, I enjoyed the museum a lot more this time around. There was still a lot of stuff I didn&rsquo;t enjoy, but I found an appreciation for the &ldquo;greats&rdquo; – Monet, Cézanne, Degas, Van Gogh.</p>

<p>It was funny seeing the Orsay&rsquo;s Van Gogh collection – which completely blew away the collection of the Van Gogh Museum we visited in Amsterdam. Every classic painting is here – <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vincent_van_Gogh#mediaviewer/File:Vincent_van_Gogh_-_Self-Portrait_-_Google_Art_Project.jpg"><strong>the</strong> self-portrait</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Starry_Night_Over_the_Rhone">Starry Night over the Rhone</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Church_at_Auvers">The Church at Auvers</a>, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portrait_of_Dr._Gachet">less-expensive Portrait of Dr Gachet</a>. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Gates_of_Hell">plaster original of the Gates of Hell</a> by Rodin is also there, which is probably my favourite piece in the museum. During the visit, I went from completely hating the museum to thinking it&rsquo;s one of my favourites in Paris.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;d never toured <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Les_Invalides">Les Invalides</a>, the building complex which houses the military history museum and home of Napoleon&rsquo;s tomb. We did that mostly to check off Parisian tourist things I hadn&rsquo;t yet done.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/sept/tomb.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/sept/tomb.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Tomb of Napoleon, Les Invalides</div>
</div>


<p>If you&rsquo;re super into military history, you should go. I&rsquo;m&hellip; not, so the museum left me a little bored. The tomb of Napoleon was kinda cool, but that&rsquo;s about it. Oh, there was a sub-museum dedicated to the life of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_de_Gaulle">Charles de Gaulle</a>. It gushed about him, which was creepy enough, but both Hampton and I thought it left a negative impression of him by the end of it. He came across as a little dictatorial, to be honest. I need to read more about his time in politics to get a better grasp of what he did.</p>

<p>Anyway, we mostly spent our days drinking wine and coffee in cafés, which is a fine way to spend a week. Off to Toronto (by way of one night in Philadelphia) next!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Early Morning CDG Flight]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/25/early-morning-cdg-flight/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-25T04:59:34-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/25/early-morning-cdg-flight</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We realised we had booked two early-morning flights from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_de_Gaulle_Airport">Charles de Gaulle</a>, the main airport for Paris. We looked up if the metro/RER was running that early, but from our stop the times didn&rsquo;t work out. So the RER wasn&rsquo;t an option.</p>

<p>We couldn&rsquo;t find much online, bar a few out-of-date forum posts, on alternative methods for getting to CDG that early, so I thought I&rsquo;d write our experiences down.</p>

<h2>Option 1: Shared Taxi</h2>

<p>For our first flight we got a shared taxi, using <a href="http://www.wecab.com">WeCab</a>. It was pretty simple to order online. You decide by what time you want to arrive at the airpot (we chose 6:30am, for a 7:15am flight). Then they give you a window during which they will pick you up. Our window was half an hour wide (5:25am to 5:55am), but as we are staying on the other side of Paris we expected the taxi would show up closer to 5:25am.</p>

<p>The cab showed up at 5:20am (!), and we had to rush a little to get out the door. The service said they would text 5 minutes before the taxi arrived, but they didn&rsquo;t. Thankfully, we were staying in a ground floor flat with a view of the road and I noticed the driver waiting outside.</p>

<p>We only picked up one other couple (the taxi had room for seven people), and we arrived at the airport with plenty of time.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Cost</strong>: €46.30 for two (~$62)</li>
<li><strong>Wake-up time</strong>: 5:05am (for 7:20am flight)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Option 2: Hotel</h2>

<p>For our second flight, we decided to get a room in a hotel airport. We chose the <a href="http://www.ibis.com/gb/hotel-1404-ibis-paris-cdg-airport/index.shtml">ibis CDG Airport</a> – it&rsquo;s pretty much at Terminal 3, and was about a 15-minute trip (CDGVAL terminal shuttle and walking) to our check-in gate.</p>

<p>Our flight was on a Sunday, so we arrived at the hotel on the Saturday. Despite advertising a lot of food options, there was only one buffet for lunch so we ended up going into the airport itself for lunch. That evening, only <em>one</em> of the restaurants was open, with a 30-minute wait time for food and a long line out the door. Pretty poor, to be honest.</p>

<p>We were on an EasyJet flight to Malága, so we had to get to the airport pretty early. On EasyJet, you&rsquo;re only allowed one carry-on (not one suitcase and one laptop bag, <strong>just one</strong> bag). Baggage drop closes 40 mins before departure, and gates close 30 mins before departure. So we had to be there earlier than our previous flight. However, we still managed to get up later.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Cost</strong>: €97 for two (~$132)</li>
<li><strong>Wake-up time</strong>: 5:30am (for 7:00am flight)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Verdict</h2>

<p>Despite the hotel we chose having a number of flaws, I&rsquo;d definitely recommend getting a hotel rather than the early-morning cab.</p>

<p>The peace of mind knowing you&rsquo;re in the airport complex, plus the convenience of a 15-minute automated train and walking journey, far outweigh the difference in price.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finding Good Cocktails in Paris]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/24/cocktails-in-paris/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-24T05:08:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/24/cocktails-in-paris</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Living in San Francisco, we&rsquo;re spoiled when it comes to cocktails. Almost any bar you wander into could make a half-decent manhattan or gimlet. As <a href="/blog/2014/05/13/linz">I&rsquo;ve brought up before</a>, cocktails in Europe are a little lacking. Hampton and I wanted to find some decent mixed drinks, so did some research on the cocktail scene in Paris.</p>

<p>There are a handful of well-rated places, and we learnt that the first high-end cocktail bar to be successful was the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Experimental-Cocktail-Club/129531980432588">Experimental Cocktail Club</a> (&ldquo;ECC&rdquo;), which has been open for about six years. Apparently, a number of trainee bartenders from there have spread across the city, opening their own high-end cocktail bars. We went to three (alas, we didn&rsquo;t make it to the ECC).</p>

<p>We ended up at the similarly-named <a href="http://www.prescriptioncocktailclub.com/">Prescription Cocktail Club</a>, in the <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Prescription+Cocktail+Club/@48.854997,2.337909,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x9d147b310bda215">Saint Germain quarter</a>, as it was close to one of our favourite restaurants in Paris (<a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/fish-la-boissonnerie-paris-2">Fish la Boissonnerie</a>). There was no obvious sign from the street that it was a cocktail bar, but we were pretty sure we had the right address. We peered in a window and saw a bunch of people sipping cocktails, so we went in. Although we showed up at 9pm on a Friday, we were lucky enough to get a table. The service was pretty good (there was table service at every bar we went to), and the cocktails were competent. I ordered something with gin, green Chartreuse, and crème de menthe. It was a little too sweet for my taste, but drinkable nontheless.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.lemaryceleste.com/">Mary Celeste</a> was another bar we went to. It had pretty good cocktails and some tasty-looking tapas – we&rsquo;d just eaten so we&rsquo;ll have to go back for the food.</p>

<p>The bizarrely-named <a href="http://www.sherrybuttparis.com/">Sherry Butt</a>, <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Sherry+Butt/@48.853303,2.364085,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x47e671ffaa10ef7d:0x2b98a01f163bffd1">not far from Bastille</a>, was probably my favourite cocktail bar that we went to. We went on a Thursday night and it was really quiet (being quiet is definitely a bonus for us). The bar was set up like a workshop – unfinished wood tables and odd contraptions on shelves. The menu was inventive and they seemed to produce a lot of their own syrups and flavourings for their drinks. Although they only listed their own concoctions, I asked for a Last Word and the bartender didn&rsquo;t hesitate to make one. The bartender was super-friendly and explained to us the cocktail scene in Paris – about how the &ldquo;ECC&rdquo; started it all, and that most of the high-end bartenders originated there. He was surprised we hadn&rsquo;t been to Candelaria, and strongly recommended we go there next.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.candelariaparis.com/">Candelaria</a>, just <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Candelaria/@48.862981,2.364034,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0xfe5e1d4c40b38ec0">south of République</a>, is a pretty strange place. It reminded me of something you&rsquo;d find in San Francisco. From the street, it&rsquo;s a tiny, bright taqueria. There&rsquo;s one table and a handful of seats at a bar. At 9pm on a Thursday night, it was packed. People were spilling out onto the street, and we were told it would be a 30min wait if we wanted food. However, we were there for the cocktails.</p>

<p>If you squeeze past the people sitting at the diner-style bar, there&rsquo;s an unmarked door. Go through it and you&rsquo;re in a much larger room – although equally busy – lit by candles. The space was decorated with Day-of-the-Dead style skeletons and it really did feel like we were back in the Mission. Unfortunately, the cocktails were mediocre. We hadn&rsquo;t reserved a table ahead, so we were stuck standing elbow-to-elbow with the hipsters of Paris. It was a little clostrophobic in there.</p>

<p>We went to another cocktail bar/tapas restaurant nearby Candelaria: <a href="http://www.lemaryceleste.com/cocktails/">Le Mary Celeste</a>. As far as I know, the bartenders weren&rsquo;t ECC alumni, but they had a neat cocktail menu. The bar had a vaguely nautical theme, and the cocktails were refreshing – both on-menu and classics like a manhattan or a gimlet. If you&rsquo;re in the area, and want to get away from the intensity of Candelaria, I&rsquo;d say it&rsquo;s a good call.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s worth pointing out that cocktails in Paris are expensive. €13 (~US$18) was not unusual. Compare that to cocktails in San Francisco, where anything more than $12 would be considered pricey. It&rsquo;s a trade-off, obviously – the price of a baguette (80¢ or ~US$1.10) or some great cheese is way less in Paris than in San Francisco.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m happy we found these places. Most were a little tricky to track down, but fun to drink at. It&rsquo;s good to know there are decent cocktial bars in Paris – even if you have to walk down a weird side-alley to get to them. I look forward to finding more next time we&rsquo;re in the city.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Street Art in the Butte-aux-Cailles, Paris]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/19/street-art-butte-aux-cailles/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-19T03:43:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/19/street-art-butte-aux-cailles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our first major stop in Europe has been Paris. We&rsquo;re staying in an area new to us: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Butte-aux-Cailles">la Butte-aux-Cailles</a>. It&rsquo;s in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/13th_arrondissement_of_Paris">13th arrondissement</a> of Paris, in the south-east of the city.</p>

<p>The neighbourhood has a small-town feel, and isn&rsquo;t touristy at all. I&rsquo;ve only encountered other English-speakers when I&rsquo;ve left the area. It&rsquo;s fairly easy to get to other places, as the nearby <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Place_d'Italie">Place d&#8217;Italie</a> has a number of lines from its Métro stop.</p>

<p>There are a decent number of bars, cafés and restaurants on <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Rue+de+la+Butte+aux+Cailles/@48.8277143,2.3498739,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x47e67190f05e1315:0x4771112c8d0bf60b">the main street</a>. From about 6pm to midnight, they&rsquo;re packed with people – so much so, that there&rsquo;s often a crowd spilling out onto the street. It&rsquo;s a little strange for a neighbourhood that&rsquo;s fairly quiet the rest of the time.</p>

<p>Anyway, the thing that struck me the most about the area was that it seems to have a large amount of street art (apparently <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-03-26/how-overprotective-paris-became-the-center-of-street-art-.html">Paris is becoming the &ldquo;center of street art&rdquo;</a>). Every wall seems to have something beautiful or provocative on it.</p>

<p>The most famous (as far as I can tell) street art in the area is done by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sampsa_(street_artist)">Sampsa</a>, the &ldquo;Finnish Banksy.&rdquo;</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/hadopi-2.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/hadopi-2.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">HADOPI gang</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/hadopi.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/hadopi.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Close-up of a HADOPI enforcer</div>
</div>


<p>The two pieces by Sampsa were in protest of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HADOPI_law">HADOPI law</a> – a copyright infringement law from around 2009. Amusingly, the first logo for the HADOPI agency used <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/europe/france/6974249/Anti-piracy-agencys-logo-broke-copyright.html">a typeface without appropriate licensing</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/blood-sucking.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/blood-sucking.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The blood sucking HADOPI</div>
</div>


<p>The mosquito art was <a href="http://motherboard.vice.com/blog/paris-censored-anti-copyright-street-art">censored for a while</a> – removing the &ldquo;Blood sucking HADOPI&rdquo; line. But apparently it has been recently restored.</p>

<p>There are a bunch artworks done in mostly muted blues and greys. They&rsquo;re all of children. At first glance, they&rsquo;re kind of peaceful.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/boat.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/boat.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Boat</div>
</div>


<p>However when I started to study them there was something unnerving about them. The children never had faces.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/boy.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/boy.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Painter boy</div>
</div>


<p>As well as the lack of faces, the children are usually disappearing. They&rsquo;re walking through a waterfall or curtain into another world. Or they&rsquo;re being partially submerged. They&rsquo;re a little eerie.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/kneel.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/kneel.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Kneeling</div>
</div>


<p><a href="http://www.missticinparis.com/">Miss.tic</a> is another artist with a lot of works in the area. According to <a href="http://www.missticinparis.com/misstic_biographie.html">her biography page</a>, she&rsquo;s almost 60 years old. She has a bunch of stencils that tend to be of provocatively-posed ladies with humourous or ironic captions.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve done my best to translate the captions, but they&rsquo;ll no doubt be a little off. If anyone wants to correct me, please do!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic1.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic1.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;I have men-ancholy&#8221; (I think it&#8217;s a pun on &#8220;avoir du vague à l&#8217;âme,&#8221; meaning &#8220;to be melancholy&#8221;)</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic2.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic2.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;Abuse of pleasure is great for your health&#8221;</div>
</div>


<p>Miss.tic doesn&rsquo;t only do scantily-clad ladies, though.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic3.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic3.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;In our secret gardens, desire is created&#8221;</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic4.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic4.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;Porn is an error of desire&#8221;</div>
</div>


<p>There are a couple of sculptures by the Italian street art group <a href="http://www.urbansolid.org/">UrbanSolid</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/ears.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/ears.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;Listening Area&#8221;</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/sculpture-prison.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/sculpture-prison.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Out of Eden</div>
</div>


<p>I liked these, although the prisoner is just around a tight corner, and at night I keep thinking there&rsquo;s a person waiting there. It&rsquo;s a little creepy.</p>

<p>There are a few pieces by <a href="http://www.janaundjs.com/">Jana und JS</a>. They have a nice style, and do work in a number of European cities. I like their focus on photography/photographers, who appear in a lot of their works.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/photo.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/photo.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Urban photographer</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/window.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/window.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Window</div>
</div>


<p>You may have noticed a small gecko logo next to a lot of the art. I&rsquo;m not 100% sure what the symbol is for – looking up the <a href="http://www.lezarts-bievre.com/">Lézarts de la Bièvre</a>, it seems to be some kind of art event held in June, with a focus on street artists.</p>

<p>Finally, here&rsquo;s a bunch of other neat stuff I saw that seemed to be one-offs by artists (at least, one-offs for this area).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/moss-bird.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/moss-bird.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;Natural&#8221; street art: bird made of moss</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/skeleton.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/skeleton.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Looks like something for Day of the Dead (by <a href="http://www.bunnym.com/">Bunny M</a>)</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/world.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/world.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Pixelated world</div>
</div>


<p>Anyway, I <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/dir/48.8310625,2.3552585/48.8280933,2.3526657/48.8266199,2.3479307/48.8290213,2.3478663/48.8288321,2.3507471/48.8310907,2.3552156/@48.8292438,2.3512191,17z/data=!4m8!4m7!1m0!1m0!1m0!1m0!1m0!1m0!3e2">google-mapped</a> (Is &ldquo;google-map&rdquo; a verb? It is now, I guess) the route I took. It starts and ends at Place d&#8217;Italie, in case you&rsquo;re arriving by Métro, and takes about 30 minutes. Of course, just wandering around the neighbourhood – especially on a Sunday morning, when it&rsquo;s super-quiet – is nice too.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re leaving this area in the next couple of days to move to a hotel for <a href="http://2014.la-conf.org/">La Conf</a>. After that, it&rsquo;s off to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/M%C3%A1laga">Málaga</a> to meet my family.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lyon: Part Deux (La Cuisine)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/06/30/lyon-part-deux-la-cuisine/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-30T12:46:56-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/06/30/lyon-part-deux-la-cuisine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn&rsquo;t realise that Lyon was the centre for French gastronomy. But apparently it is. Anyway, I thought I&rsquo;d devote a whole post to the food I ate there, in addition to my first post on the city itself.</p>

<p>The first night, we ate at <a href="http://www.brasseriegeorges.com/">Brasserie Georges</a>. It&rsquo;s apparently pretty famous (it has a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brasserie_Georges">Wikipedia article</a> - a sure sign of prominence). They served some traditional Lyon food - including a pistachio sausage thing, which was pretty nice. Also on the list of traditional Lyon foods were a mustard sausage and calf&rsquo;s head. I think I made the right choice with a pistachio sausage.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/georges.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/georges.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    I forgot to take pictures of the food.
  </div>
</div>


<p>The second evening, we went to a place called <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps/place?hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;bav=on.2,or.r_gc.r_pw.&amp;biw=1256&amp;bih=738&amp;um=1&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;q=Les+enfants+terribles+lyon&amp;fb=1&amp;hq=Les+enfants+terribles&amp;hnear=0x47f4ea516ae88797:0x408ab2ae4bb21f0,Lyon,+France&amp;cid=9879979365541420669">Les Enfants Terribles</a>&hellip; it was OK. Nothing too special. The duck salad I had to start had too much mustard dressing on it. The main was beef, coupled with some deeeeelicious dauphinoise potatoes. I think they must have used chicken stock or something. The dessert was pretty good&hellip; but that&rsquo;s not much of a surprise as I love all tartes au citron. The filling had a strange granular texture - I think they might have added ground almonds or something.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/duck-salad.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/duck-salad.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Starter: duck salad with some foie gras.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/beef.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/beef.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Main: beef with dauphinoise potatoes.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/tarte-citron.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/tarte-citron.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Dessert: tarte au citron.
  </div>
</div>


<p>For Sunday lunch, we went to a pretty decent restaurant near the hotel (in the Brotteaux area) - it was called <a href="http://www.nordsudbrasseries.com/">Brasserie de l&#8217;Est</a>. It seems to be part of a chain. The food was pretty good! I&rsquo;d recommend it. I forgot to take pictures, though.</p>

<p>On our final night, we ended up at <a href="http://www.hippopotamus.fr/">Hippopotamus</a>. I&rsquo;ve seen a few in Paris. They&rsquo;re some kind of chain that serves vaguely French food - steaks, etc. It was, as we kinda expected, mediocre. I had an assortment of fried goods. It was very American.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/hippo.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/hippo.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    The fried stuff from Hippopotamus.
  </div>
</div>


<p>One of the better meals I had was (strangely?) at the airport. It was the airport branch of the 2-Michelin-starred <a href="http://www.nicolaslebec.com/">Nicolas Le Bec</a>, which is in the centre of Lyon. It&rsquo;s called <a href="http://www.espace-lebec.com/">Espace Le Bec</a>. We both had a really delicious penne with bolognese. It had the most amazing cheese sliced over it, too. SO GOOD.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/lys-pasta.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/lys-pasta.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Penne with bolognese.
  </div>
</div>


<p>So that&rsquo;s pretty much all the food I ate in Lyon. I wasn&rsquo;t there that long, so I can&rsquo;t really confirm or deny its status as le centre gastronomique of France. I&rsquo;ve had better meals in Paris. (But Espace Le Bec was definitely the best meal I&rsquo;ve had at an airport.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
