<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Paris | mjlcatlin]]></title>
  <link href="http://mjlcatlin.com/blog/categories/paris/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mjlcatlin.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-16T12:31:16-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://mjlcatlin.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paris: April 2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://mjlcatlin.com/blog/2011/04/24/paris-april-2011/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-24T13:45:02-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mjlcatlin.com/blog/2011/04/24/paris-april-2011</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After our trip to Zürich, we went to Paris by train. As with most rail travel in Europe, it was a great way to move between cities. There was a lot of kerfuffle with the hotels when we arrived &ndash; but we ended up in the beautiful <a href="http://www.closmedicis.com/">Hotel de Clos Medicis</a>. We were in the attic, which had amazing exposed beams and an upstairs bathroom.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/paris/medicis.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Our room (in the attic) in the hotel.</div>
</div>


<p>Best of all, we were in the Latin Quarter, which is so much fun. It&rsquo;s the &ldquo;bohemian&rdquo; area of Paris, with lots of cool bars, cafés and restaurants to eat in. Which is what we mainly ended up doing.Hampton and I have done most of the touristy things in Paris before &ndash; and we were there in March, too. When we were there, we discovered our love for the café culture. Seriously, why hasn&rsquo;t it been rolled out across the world yet? We would sit in a café from 3pm until 7pm reading, drinking wine. We&rsquo;d go for a meal somewhere, then return to another café for more wine, leaving at around 2am. It&rsquo;s so refreshing.</p>

<p>Anyway, this time we tried to do the same thing. We ate a lot of good food. My favourite restaurant was <a href="http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g187147-d715085-Reviews-Fish_la_Boissonnerie-Paris_Ile_de_France.html">Fish Le Boissonnerie</a>. Some pictures follow.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/paris/boissonnerie.jpg">
  <div class="alt">The outside of Le Boissonnerie</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/paris/bois-starter.jpg">
  <div class="alt">The starter: smoked eel and marinated carrots.</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/paris/bois-main.jpg">
  <div class="alt">The main: veal, pea risotto, chorizo puree and a parmesan crisp.</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/paris/bois-dessert.jpg">
  <div class="alt">The dessert: crème brûlée.</div>
</div>


<p>I didn&rsquo;t take a picture of the bread, though. The bread (which I think they got from an Italian restaurant across the street) was the most amazing foccacia I have ever tasted. I&rsquo;d go back to that restaurant solely for the bread.</p>

<p>So, other random things we did in Paris. We went on a boat tour along the Seine, which was nice. But it was super hot (a lot warmer than Zürich, that&rsquo;s for sure).</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/paris/pont-neuf.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Pont Neuf from the boat tour we did along the Seine.</div>
</div>


<p>We visited the <a href="http://equipement.paris.fr/marche-aux-fleurs-et-aux-oiseaux-cite-4506">marché des oiseaux</a> on Sunday. Every Sunday, the flower market on the Île de la Cité also has a bunch of guys selling birds. It was bizarre, and unsettling how many birds they can fit into those tiny cages.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/paris/finches.jpg">
  <div class="alt">So many birds in such a small cage.</div>
</div>


<p>As for cafés, my favourite is still <a href="https://plus.google.com/117060472644786113352/about?gl=us&amp;hl=en">Le Contrescarpe</a>, on Rue Mouffetard. However, the best wine was definitely at <a href="http://www.michelrostang.com/">Le Rostand</a>, which was facing the Jardin du Luxembourg.</p>

<p>We didn&rsquo;t really go to that many &ldquo;bars&rdquo;, but we did go to <a href="http://www.bowlingmouffetard.fr/">Le Bowling Mouffetard</a>, a mix of Americana and UV lighting &ndash; in a bowling alley. That was very enjoyable. I remember going when I was in Paris in 2006. I&rsquo;m surprised I managed to find it again.</p>

<p>As the Royal Wedding is coming up, every French magazine seemed to have a cover story about the couple. This one really weirded me out:</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/paris/so-british.jpg">
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
