<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Lyon | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/lyon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-04T14:16:41-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lyon: Part Deux (La Cuisine)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/06/30/lyon-part-deux-la-cuisine/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-30T15:46:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/06/30/lyon-part-deux-la-cuisine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn&rsquo;t realise that Lyon was the centre for French gastronomy. But apparently it is. Anyway, I thought I&rsquo;d devote a whole post to the food I ate there, in addition to my first post on the city itself.</p>

<p>The first night, we ate at <a href="http://www.brasseriegeorges.com/">Brasserie Georges</a>. It&rsquo;s apparently pretty famous (it has a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brasserie_Georges">Wikipedia article</a> - a sure sign of prominence). They served some traditional Lyon food - including a pistachio sausage thing, which was pretty nice. Also on the list of traditional Lyon foods were a mustard sausage and calf&rsquo;s head. I think I made the right choice with a pistachio sausage.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/georges.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/georges.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    I forgot to take pictures of the food.
  </div>
</div>


<p>The second evening, we went to a place called <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps/place?hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;bav=on.2,or.r_gc.r_pw.&amp;biw=1256&amp;bih=738&amp;um=1&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;q=Les+enfants+terribles+lyon&amp;fb=1&amp;hq=Les+enfants+terribles&amp;hnear=0x47f4ea516ae88797:0x408ab2ae4bb21f0,Lyon,+France&amp;cid=9879979365541420669">Les Enfants Terribles</a>&hellip; it was OK. Nothing too special. The duck salad I had to start had too much mustard dressing on it. The main was beef, coupled with some deeeeelicious dauphinoise potatoes. I think they must have used chicken stock or something. The dessert was pretty good&hellip; but that&rsquo;s not much of a surprise as I love all tartes au citron. The filling had a strange granular texture - I think they might have added ground almonds or something.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/duck-salad.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/duck-salad.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Starter: duck salad with some foie gras.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/beef.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/beef.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Main: beef with dauphinoise potatoes.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/tarte-citron.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/tarte-citron.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Dessert: tarte au citron.
  </div>
</div>


<p>For Sunday lunch, we went to a pretty decent restaurant near the hotel (in the Brotteaux area) - it was called <a href="http://www.nordsudbrasseries.com/">Brasserie de l&#8217;Est</a>. It seems to be part of a chain. The food was pretty good! I&rsquo;d recommend it. I forgot to take pictures, though.</p>

<p>On our final night, we ended up at <a href="http://www.hippopotamus.fr/">Hippopotamus</a>. I&rsquo;ve seen a few in Paris. They&rsquo;re some kind of chain that serves vaguely French food - steaks, etc. It was, as we kinda expected, mediocre. I had an assortment of fried goods. It was very American.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/hippo.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/hippo.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    The fried stuff from Hippopotamus.
  </div>
</div>


<p>One of the better meals I had was (strangely?) at the airport. It was the airport branch of the 2-Michelin-starred <a href="http://www.nicolaslebec.com/">Nicolas Le Bec</a>, which is in the centre of Lyon. It&rsquo;s called <a href="http://www.espace-lebec.com/">Espace Le Bec</a>. We both had a really delicious penne with bolognese. It had the most amazing cheese sliced over it, too. SO GOOD.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/lys-pasta.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/lys-pasta.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Penne with bolognese.
  </div>
</div>


<p>So that&rsquo;s pretty much all the food I ate in Lyon. I wasn&rsquo;t there that long, so I can&rsquo;t really confirm or deny its status as le centre gastronomique of France. I&rsquo;ve had better meals in Paris. (But Espace Le Bec was definitely the best meal I&rsquo;ve had at an airport.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lyon: Part Un]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/06/28/lyon-part-un/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-28T15:46:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/06/28/lyon-part-un</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I haven&rsquo;t visited many cities in France. Honestly, I&rsquo;m a bit lazy. I think, &ldquo;Why would you want to go anywhere other than Paris?&rdquo;</p>

<p>However! Hampton was invited to a conference in Lyon (<a href="http://rulu.eu/">Ruby Lugdunum</a>, named after the Roman moniker for the town). As we were mostly either at the conference or eating, I didn&rsquo;t get a chance to look around most of the city. But I&rsquo;m still going to judge it based on what I did see.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/rhone.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/rhone.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hampton on the Rhone</div>
</div>


<p>The hotel was pretty damn good, actually. It was called <a href="http://www.mercure.com/fr/hotel-7236-mercure-lyon-brotteaux/index.shtml">Hotel Mercure</a>. They had a nice French breakfast every morning (mmm, croissants). It was pretty central, and the staff were nice.</p>

<p>Lyon itself was much more of a city-city than Paris. Sometimes when you&rsquo;re in Paris, it&rsquo;s difficult to imagine someone actually living there. Lyon is a bustling place, with very few tourists. It feels like a financial centre.</p>

<p>The architecture was odd. I guess the city had mostly grown in the 60s/70s. There was lots of brutalist stuff - not that I&rsquo;m complaining, as I love the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/B%C3%A9ton_brut">béton</a> look. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Claude_Bernard_University_Lyon_1">The Université Lyon 1</a> (where the conference was held) was made up pretty much exclusively of this stuff.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/college-1.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/college-1.jpg">
  </a>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/college-hut.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/college-hut.jpg">
  </a>
</div>


<p>Although the buildings were interesting, they&rsquo;d been left to a surprising amount of decay. Paint peeling, weeds growing everywhere. It was pretty strange.</p>

<p>Oh, and on the topic of architecture, LYS had an awesome <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gare_de_Lyon_Saint-Exup%C3%A9ry">train station</a>, designed by Santiago Calatrava.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/gare-from-plane.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/gare-from-plane.jpg">
  </a>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/gare-lys.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/gare-lys.jpg">
  </a>
</div>


<p>It was super-easy to use the city&rsquo;s transportation. The metro is neat and seems to go to all the major places in the city.</p>

<p>Next post: food.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
