<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Travel | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-07T15:53:00-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Travelling While LGBT: A Justified Anxiety?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2015/01/10/travelling-while-lgbt-justified-anxiety/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-10T16:34:01-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2015/01/10/travelling-while-lgbt-justified-anxiety</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The New York Times released its list of the <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2015/01/11/travel/52-places-to-go-in-2015.html?hp&amp;action=click&amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;module=photo-spot-region&amp;region=top-news&amp;WT.nav=top-news">top places to go to in 2015</a>. It puts together two of my favourite things: easy-to-digest lists and travel destinations. This year&rsquo;s list was pretty exciting – among some places that we&rsquo;d visited on this past trip (Manhattan, Philadelphia, and, surprisingly, Orlando), there were a lot of places I&rsquo;m interested in visiting.</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Singapore">Singapore</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint_Vincent_and_the_Grenadines">St Vincent and the Grenadines</a> in particular caught my eye. Singapore for its city-state strangeness and St Vincent for its diving. That <a href="http://graphics8.nytimes.com/newsgraphics/2015/01/08/places-to-go/assets/images/stvincent-1254.jpg">coral reef photo</a> looks so inviting! But wait.</p>

<p>Before I can plan any more, before I get too excited about a new travel destination, I go to the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LGBT_rights_by_country_or_territory">Wikipedia page for LGBT rights by country</a>. (Or, I recently found a great site called <a href="http://equaldex.com/">Equaldex</a>. I wanted to build something similar – it has a map and an easily-searchable database of countries showing the status of various LGBT-related laws.)</p>

<p>Does that seem strange? It still does to me, even though I do it fairly regularly. But unfortunately I feel like I have to. For example, checking out <a href="http://equaldex.com/region/saint-vincent-and-the-grenadines">St Vincent and the Grenadines</a> shows me that male homosexuality is punishable by ten years in prison. I guess that takes it off the &ldquo;potential diving spots&rdquo; list.</p>

<p><a href="http://equaldex.com/region/singapore">Singapore</a> has a prison sentence of two years for gay guys. Another one off the list.</p>

<p>Going back to the New York Times list, there&rsquo;s a couple of countries that I know are not LGBT-friendly – Oman (<a href="http://equaldex.com/region/oman">up to three years imprisonment</a>) and Morocco (<a href="http://equaldex.com/region/morocco">six months imprisonment</a>). Checking some more, there&rsquo;s also St Kitts (<a href="http://equaldex.com/region/saint-kitts-and-nevis">ten years imprisonment</a>), Zimbabwe (<a href="http://equaldex.com/region/zimbabwe">up to ten years imprisonment</a>), Sri Lanka (<a href="http://equaldex.com/region/sri-lanka">up to ten years</a>), Papua New Guinea (<a href="http://equaldex.com/region/papua-new-guinea">up to fourteen years</a>), and Tanzania (a <a href="http://equaldex.com/region/tanzania"><em>minimum</em> of twenty years imprisonment</a>). That totals nine countries out of the fifty-two! I guess forty-three remaining travel destinations would still keep you pretty well-occupied.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s just going off countries that ban same-sex activities, mind you. There&rsquo;s even more countries that don&rsquo;t ban LGBT discrimination. When looking at destinations, I&rsquo;m usually more lax with that. I mean heck, we couldn&rsquo;t even <a href="http://equaldex.com/region/united-states/florida">visit Florida</a> if I included places that allow LGBT discrimination in the &ldquo;no-travel&rdquo; list.</p>

<p>What does this serve? Am I just being unnecessarily anxious? Is this narrowing our experience of the world over something quite small? I mean, we&rsquo;re from two globally dominant countries. Surely LGBT travellers aren&rsquo;t arrested that regularly? There&rsquo;s a couple of high-profile cases that spring to mind – a <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/travel/travelnews/11142952/Call-for-boycott-of-Morocco-after-British-tourist-jailed-for-homosexual-acts.html">British gay guy was arrested in Morocco</a>, and <a href="http://www.travelandescape.ca/2013/07/first-tourists-have-been-arrested-under-putins-anti-gay-laws/">four LGBT Dutch people were arrested in Russia</a>. But the number of LGBT travellers far outweighs those, surely. We&rsquo;d probably be &ldquo;unnoticed.&rdquo;</p>

<p>As well as the &ldquo;danger,&rdquo; there&rsquo;s also an aspect of avoiding such countries for economic reasons. We can freely choose to spend our money in, say, <a href="http://equaldex.com/region/spain">Spain</a> – which has far better equal rights for LGBT people – over another country that does not.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s weird having to read through any destination list with the knowledge that you&rsquo;ll maybe have to cut out about ~15% of it. I&rsquo;m interested to hear what anyone reading this – both LGBT and non-LGBT – thinks. Am I being too paranoid? Is it a valid, maybe arbitrary choice (I mean hey, it&rsquo;s a useful way to narrow down <em>all possible countries</em> into a smaller list, right)? Do you have any &ldquo;rules&rdquo; for choosing whether you&rsquo;ll visit a country?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Packing for Seven Months in a Carry-on]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/04/22/carry-on-packing-for-seven-months/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-22T10:09:09-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/04/22/carry-on-packing-for-seven-months</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A <a href="http://twitter.com/melissaiscool">good friend</a> converted us to <a href="http://melissadreamsofsushi.com/?p=7432">always packing carry-ons</a> when going on trips. It&rsquo;s far easier to travel with a carry-on – especially when taking low-cost airlines that charge to check luggage.</p>

<p>The longest we have spent living out of a carry-on has been about three months. The benefits definitely outweighed the negatives. If we ran out of clothes, we could often find laundry facilities. Anything we forgot could usually be bought locally. So, for this trip we took the plunge and aimed to pack only a carry-on for seven months of travel.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s easier to pack for seven months in a carry-on when you&rsquo;re travelling during summer. No hats, scarves, gloves, or bulky coats are necessary. Of course, when we make it back to the East Coast it will be autumn and may be a little chilly. At that point, we can easily buy warmer clothes (as <a href="https://twitter.com/hcatlin/status/458307183470342144">Hampton pointed out</a>, clothes tend to be more expensive in Europe).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Choosing things to pack was pretty simple. I went through T-shirts I liked and grabbed them. One pair of darker jeans (that could work in a nicer restaurant) is useful. Shirts that look good without needing to be ironed are helpful if you need a dressier option and don&rsquo;t have an iron handy.</p>

<p>I also made sure to pack some older clothes, too, so I could throw things out if necessary.</p>

<p>Getting it into the suitcase was simple by rolling everything up. If you&rsquo;re not familiar with <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/slideshow/2010/05/06/business/businessspecial/20100506-pack-ss.html?_r=0">the &ldquo;roll&rdquo; style of packing</a>, it&rsquo;s excellent and allows you to fit a lot more in a suitcase (and keep things mostly wrinkle-free).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/side-one.JPG">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/side-one.JPG">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">First side</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/side-two.JPG">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/side-two.JPG">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Second side</div>
</div>


<p>The two images above contain about two weeks&#8217; worth of clothes. Making sure I wear bulky items when travelling means that the lighter versions (e.g. a lighter jacket, thinner shoes) fit in the suitcase. The contact lenses should be <a href="https://www.tsa.gov/traveler-information/medically-necessary-liquids">allowed as medical liquids</a>.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the full list:</p>

<ul>
<li>15 T-shirts</li>
<li>1 polo shirt</li>
<li>3 shirts</li>
<li>11 regular socks</li>
<li>7 ankle socks</li>
<li>16 pairs of underwear</li>
<li>2 pairs of trousers</li>
<li>1 pair of shorts</li>
<li>1 pair of swimming trunks</li>
<li>2 pairs of shoes (one boot-like, one light and foldable)</li>
<li>2 jackets (one light, one heavy)</li>
<li>1 toothbrush</li>
<li>1 razor</li>
<li>1 pair of sunglasses</li>
<li>90 pairs of contact lenses</li>
<li>1 international adaptor</li>
</ul>


<p>Our laptop bags will have toiletries (shaving cream, toothpaste and deodorant only – everything else we can buy as we need it), our laptops, kindles, and chargers.</p>

<p>And there you go. That&rsquo;s how you pack for seven months in only carry-on.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming Travel]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/04/15/upcoming-travel/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-15T13:40:14-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/04/15/upcoming-travel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the next seven months, Hampton and I will be travelling around Europe and the East Coast. We have few solid plans aside from some conferences (<a href="http://codefront.io/">Codefront.io</a>, <a href="http://2014.la-conf.org/">La Conf</a>, <a href="http://hybridconf.net/">HybridConf</a> and <a href="http://sassconf.com/">SassConf</a>).</p>

<p>A friend gave me the idea to blog as we travel. I&rsquo;ve been lax with this blog recently, and I hope that switching platforms (from WordPress to Octopress) will spur me to write more.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[San Francisco: Part Two]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/12/30/san-francisco-part-two/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-30T11:25:25-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/12/30/san-francisco-part-two</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My first post on SF was a bit tourist-y. This one will be more focused on food and drink. And other funstuff.</p>

<p>We ate at a neat burger place on Union Sq - the aptly-named <a href="http://www.burger-bar.com/">Burger Bar</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/burger-bar-view.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/burger-bar-view.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">View from Burger Bar.</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/burger-bar.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/burger-bar.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The burger I had. I think it was buffalo?</div>
</div>


<p>The milkshakes (picture missing) were amazing. The nutella one was just ice-cream and nutella, pretty much. The burger was good&hellip; but I&rsquo;ve had better (I&rsquo;m looking at you, The Bird in Berlin.)</p>

<p>We went to an awesome beach - China Beach. It was really quiet and had insane views of the Golden Gate and its bridge.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/china-beach.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/china-beach.jpg">
  </a>
</div>


<p>Oh, and something else I&rsquo;d highly recommend is Nightlife at the California Academy of Sciences. It&rsquo;s on every Thursday and has a general theme every week (we went for 80s nostalgia/comedy). They have booze, you can wander around the exhibits, and they play pretty awesome music.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s about all I have to say. If you keep track of my whereabouts, you&rsquo;ll notice we&rsquo;ve now moved to San Francisco to live. It&rsquo;s awesome here!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[San Francisco: Part One]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/11/27/san-francisco-part-one/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-27T11:25:29-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/11/27/san-francisco-part-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After Jacksonville, we headed on to San Francisco. Hampton&rsquo;s company (Moovweb) is based there.</p>

<p>We flew United 2623 from CLT to SFO. They had WIFI!!!!! Zomg. It&rsquo;s still a novelty for me. I don&rsquo;t have many photos of the CLT-SFO flight, just the food pretty much.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/plane/ua2623-pasta.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/plane/ua2623-pasta.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Dinner - some OK pasta thing.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/plane/ua2623-dessert.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/plane/ua2623-dessert.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Dessert – tortoise cheesecake, or something.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/plane/ua2623-wifi.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/plane/ua2623-wifi.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Wi-fi! In the air!
  </div>
</div>


<p>I&rsquo;d never been to San Francisco before, so it was a bit of an adventure. We only spent a couple of days doing touristy things, and the rest of the time was mostly Hampton working at Moovweb and me working on the book. Here&rsquo;s some tourist photos.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/pier-39.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/pier-39.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    I am such a tourist: at Pier 39
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/sea-lions.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/sea-lions.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Sea lions!
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/alcatraz-fog.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/alcatraz-fog.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Gazing over at Alcatraz
  </div>
</div>


<p>(We didn&rsquo;t actually go to Alcatraz, even though I reaaaaally wanted to.)</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/transam.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/transam.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    TransAmerica tower.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/hyatt-view.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/hyatt-view.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    The view from the Grand Hyatt.
  </div>
</div>


<p>One of the best views for the whole two weeks was from the GrandViews lounge in the Grand Hyatt. The cocktails were OK, the food in the neighbouring restaurant the same, but the views&hellip; wow. This was at sunset. You can see the TransAm building and Coit Tower from this angle.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
