<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Travel | mjlcatlin]]></title>
  <link href="http://mjlcatlin.com/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mjlcatlin.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-16T12:31:16-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://mjlcatlin.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming Travel]]></title>
    <link href="http://mjlcatlin.com/blog/2014/04/15/upcoming-travel/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-15T13:40:14-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mjlcatlin.com/blog/2014/04/15/upcoming-travel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the next seven months, Hampton and I will be travelling around Europe and the East Coast. We have few solid plans aside from some conferences (<a href="http://codefront.io/">Codefront.io</a>, <a href="http://2014.la-conf.org/">La Conf</a>, <a href="http://hybridconf.net/">HybridConf</a> and <a href="http://sassconf.com/">SassConf</a>).</p>

<p>A friend gave me the idea to blog as we travel. I&rsquo;ve been lax with this blog recently, and I hope that switching platforms (from WordPress to Octopress) will spur me to write more.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[San Francisco: Part Two]]></title>
    <link href="http://mjlcatlin.com/blog/2011/12/30/san-francisco-part-two/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-30T11:25:25-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mjlcatlin.com/blog/2011/12/30/san-francisco-part-two</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My first post on SF was a bit tourist-y. This one will be more focused on food and drink. And other funstuff.</p>

<p>We ate at a neat burger place on Union Sq &ndash; the aptly-named Burger Bar.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/san-francisco/burger-bar-view.jpg">
  <div class="alt">View from Burger Bar.</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/san-francisco/burger-bar.jpg">
  <div class="alt">The burger I had. I think it was buffalo?</div>
</div>


<p>The milkshakes (picture missing) were amazing. The nutella one was just ice-cream and nutella, pretty much. The burger was good&hellip; but I&rsquo;ve had better (I&rsquo;m looking at you, The Bird in Berlin.)</p>

<p>We went to an awesome beach &ndash; China Beach. It was really quiet and had insane views of the Golden Gate and its bridge.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/san-francisco/china-beach.jpg">
</div>


<p>Oh, and something else I&rsquo;d highly recommend is Nightlife at the California Academy of Sciences. It&rsquo;s on every Thursday and has a general theme every week (we went for 80s nostalgia/comedy). They have booze, you can wander around the exhibits, and they play pretty awesome music.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s about all I have to say. If you keep track of my whereabouts, you&rsquo;ll notice we&rsquo;ve now moved to San Francisco to live. It&rsquo;s awesome here!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[San Francisco: Part One]]></title>
    <link href="http://mjlcatlin.com/blog/2011/11/27/san-francisco-part-one/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-27T11:25:29-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mjlcatlin.com/blog/2011/11/27/san-francisco-part-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After Jacksonville, we headed on to San Francisco. Hampton&rsquo;s company (Moovweb) is based there.</p>

<p>We flew United 2623 from CLT to SFO. They had WIFI!!!!! Zomg. It&rsquo;s still a novelty for me. I don&rsquo;t have many photos of the CLT-SFO flight, just the food pretty much.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/plane/ua2623-pasta.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Dinner - some OK pasta thing.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/plane/ua2623-dessert.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    This dessert was amazing: tortoise cheesecake, or something.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/plane/ua2623-wifi.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Wi-fi! In the air!
  </div>
</div>


<p>I&rsquo;d never been to San Francisco before, so it was a bit of an adventure. We only spent a couple of days doing touristy things, and the rest of the time was mostly Hampton working at Moovweb and me working on the book. Here&rsquo;s some tourist photos.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/san-francisco/pier-39.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    I am such a tourist: at Pier 39
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/san-francisco/sea-lions.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Sea lions!
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/san-francisco/alcatraz-fog.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Gazing over at Alcatraz
  </div>
</div>


<p>(We didn&rsquo;t actually go to Alcatraz, even though I reaaaaally wanted to.)</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/san-francisco/transam.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    TransAmerica tower.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/san-francisco/hyatt-view.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    The view from the Grand Hyatt in San Francisco.
  </div>
</div>


<p>One of the best views for the whole two weeks was from the GrandViews lounge in the Grand Hyatt. The cocktails were OK, the food in the neighbouring restaurant the same, but the views&hellip; wow. This was at sunset. You can see the TransAm building and Coit Tower from this angle.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Amazing Trip]]></title>
    <link href="http://mjlcatlin.com/blog/2011/09/25/the-amazing-trip/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-25T12:44:18-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mjlcatlin.com/blog/2011/09/25/the-amazing-trip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So&hellip; I really need to start blogging about an amazing trip I&rsquo;ve been on. It&rsquo;s been going for about two months now. It started in July, when we moved out of our apartment in Cambridge, England.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/cambridge/boxes.jpg">
  <div class="alt">All our stuff in boxes hours before we left.</div>
</div>


<p>Since then I&rsquo;ve visited seven cities, from Honolulu to Berlin. It&rsquo;ll probably take me a while to blog about them all. Here&rsquo;s a brief itinerary:</p>

<p>LGW &ndash; TPA (25th July 2011)</p>

<p>JAX &ndash; CLT &ndash; SFO (8th August 2011)</p>

<p>SFO &ndash; HNL &ndash; KOA (23rd August 2011)</p>

<p>KOA &ndash; HNL (30th August 2011)</p>

<p>HNL &ndash; LAX &ndash; LHR (1st September 2011)</p>

<p>LTN &ndash; SXF (8th September 2011)</p>

<p>SXF &ndash; FCO (23rd September 2011)</p>

<p>VCE &ndash; LGW (2nd October 2011)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Few Hours in London]]></title>
    <link href="http://mjlcatlin.com/blog/2011/07/18/a-few-hours-in-london/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-18T12:39:25-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mjlcatlin.com/blog/2011/07/18/a-few-hours-in-london</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last weekend, we went to London to see some of our best friends. We only really had an afternoon and evening. We started by heading to South Kensington and wandering around the <a href="http://www.vam.ac.uk/">V&amp;A</a> for a bit. I love the V&amp;A. It&rsquo;s got enough variety to keep things interesting. We visited rooms on architecture,  Islamic history and British design in the late Victorian era in the space of a couple of hours. Awesome stuff.</p>

<p>Anyway, we went to a pub, then to sushi at <a href="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/52/565671/restaurant/London/Kulu-Kulu-Sushi-South-Kensington">Kulu Kulu</a>, a conveyor belt place. Lots of delicious food&hellip; but weirdly lacking on the fish. Still, I&rsquo;m not complaining. Their stewed aubergine thing with soy sauce was amazing. Nom!</p>

<p>One of our friends had heard about an absinthe bar nearby. In fact, it was underneath a restaurant (the <a href="http://www.bromptonbarandgrill.com/">Brompton Bar &amp; Grill</a>). I&rsquo;ve never had absinthe before. Although it&rsquo;d been banned in the USA and France, it was always legal in the UK. I guess no one liked it enough for it to present much of a &ldquo;danger&rdquo; to society. Now the green fairy is being legalised in many countries, drinking absinthe is finding a resurgence.</p>

<p>We decided to skip cocktails with absinthe and go straight to the pure stuff. There was a great theatricality to the process. A water cooler (in 19th century French style, of course) was put on the table with four miniature taps.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://mjlcatlin.com/images/london/absinthe.jpg">
</div>


<p>This was filled with ice-cold water. (Sorry the pictures are so dark. It was underground and mainly lit by candles.)</p>

<p>We got a small glass with some absinthe in. Balanced on top was a special spoon (shaped like a leaf) with holes in it. A brown sugar cube was placed on top. You put the sugar cube underneath the tap and slowly let the water drip onto the cube. The sugar dissolves and drips down into the absinthe, diluting and sweetening it.</p>

<p>Once all that&rsquo;s done, you can drink away. It wasn&rsquo;t as liquorice-y as I thought it might be. Which is good, because I hate liquorice. It was certainly an enjoyable experience, even if I didn&rsquo;t hallucinate.</p>

<p>After that, we made a trek to the north-east of London to the <a href="http://www.whistlingshop.com/">Worship Street Whistling Shop</a>. It&rsquo;s a Victorian-themed bar, with many gin-based drinks. It was too dark to take decent photos inside &ndash; but there were lots of barrels and canvas-covered stools. The waiters were dressed in something akin to what barbers wear.</p>

<p>Anyway, the drinks here were <strong>a-mazing</strong>. Pricey, but still. I got the &ldquo;Panacea&rdquo; (Compass Box Whisky, honey and lavender shrub, lemon juice and sage dust) the first time around, then the Civility Cocktail (Lillet Blanc, Martini Extra Dry, WS2 Exhaustion Tonic and WS2 raspberry syrup). They were super-tasty. I&rsquo;d highly recommend this place. Apparently, this is the second bar this company has opened &ndash; so I desperately want to visit their first, a speakeasy near Marylebone called <a href="http://www.purl-london.com/">Purl</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
