<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mijas | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/mijas/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-04T18:56:35+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drinking in the Costa Del Sol]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/29/drinking-costa-del-sol/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-29T10:37:41+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/29/drinking-costa-del-sol</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The next stage of our trip took us to the south of Spain – the &ldquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Costa_del_Sol">Costa del Sol</a>,&rdquo; a clichéd destination for sun-starved Brits. My family were meeting us there and spending a few days in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mijas">Mijas</a> – a small village scattered on mountains overlooking the Mediterranean.</p>

<p>Our fruitful cocktail hunt in Paris was great. However, we didn&rsquo;t want to push our luck, so we decided to try some more traditional drinks while in a less cosmopolitan area.</p>

<p>First up: fino. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fino">Fino</a> is a dry sherry served very cold. It&rsquo;s taken as an apéretif, and apparently it&rsquo;s what all the locals drink. I&rsquo;m a fan of sherry, so I thought I&rsquo;d try it out.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/fino.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Glass of fino</div>
</div>


<p>With regular sherry, the sweetness cuts through some of the flavour of the alcohol, which makes it palatable to me. With fino, you could definitely taste the alcohol compared with &ldquo;sweet&rdquo; sherry. The fino started with a sharp acidity, then followed with a fresher aftertaste. If I lived in Spain, I&rsquo;d probably get used to it, but I wouldn&rsquo;t necessarily order it again.</p>

<p>Next up, at <a href="http://www.tripadvisor.co.uk/Restaurant_Review-g580271-d2413104-Reviews-Pampa_Tablas_y_Tapas-Mijas_Costa_del_Sol_Province_of_Malaga_Andalucia.html">a local tapas bar called Pampa</a>, we tried the stereotypical Spanish alcoholic drink: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sangria">sangria</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/sangria.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Glass and pitcher of sangria</div>
</div>


<p>Sangria is awesome and I presume everyone has had it. If not, you should try it. It&rsquo;s traditionally made with red wine, brandy, and some kind of sweetener. You also put in pieces of chopped fruit. However, I believe this one had some rum in it as well. I&rsquo;ll try adding rum when I next make sangria at home, cause it added a nice kick.</p>

<p>On our final night, we went to a &ldquo;gin bar.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s a slight misnomer: for one, it&rsquo;s more of a tapas place, and for two it served other alcohol as well. But gin is where this place shone. <a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/graphicdetail/2013/06/daily-chart-9">Spain is one of the highest per capita consumers of gin</a> (other fun facts from the linked infographic: India is the largest consumer of rum, and France is the largest consumer of Scotch). So, despite being a traditionally British drink, we had some Spanish-style gin and tonics.</p>

<p>The bar we were at, <a href="http://www.bodegaelplacer.com/">Bodega El Placer</a>, had about thirty gins on offer. There were five of us and we asked for five different gins, so we could sample them all. Each gin came in a big glass with ice and individually-prepared garnishes.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/just-gin.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Gin with garnishes</div>
</div>


<p>The garnishes ranged from juniper berries, cinnamon sticks and cardamom seeds to a simple lemon slice. The gins were all pretty different. Luckily, I liked a deep-flavoured sour gin that no one else enjoyed, so I didn&rsquo;t have to fight to finish that one off. I believe it was <a href="http://www.bulldoggin.com/">Bulldog gin</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/tonic-regular.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Gin and tonic</div>
</div>


<p>Fun fact: in most of Europe, when you want a gin and tonic, you just say &ldquo;gintonic.&rdquo; All one word.</p>

<p>They also had a blue tonic, but I&rsquo;m not really sure what the difference between regular tonic and the blue stuff was. I was a bad scientist and didn&rsquo;t do a same-gin, different-tonic experiment.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/tonic-blue.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Blue tonic?!</div>
</div>


<p>I should also mention the tapas: it was really good. It was more inventive than I was expecting – they had tempura aubergine with a honey sauce, and a melt-in-your-mouth tuna sashimi plate. My favourite, of course, was the jamón. It was one of the better jamón ibérico we had while in Spain.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/jamon.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Jamón ibérico</div>
</div>


<p>We were only in Spain a few days. Despite that, we managed to do two excellent day trips: one to Granada to see the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alhambra">Alhambra</a> (check out some photos <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/malrase/sets/72157644507980879/">on Flickr</a>), and one to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gibraltar">Gibraltar</a> (<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/malrase/sets/72157644507822700/">Flickr photos</a>). If you&rsquo;re ever in the south of Spain, I highly recommend taking a trip to those. I also hear Seville is great, but we didn&rsquo;t make it there.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re now on our way to the UK, which I&rsquo;m worried will be a bit of a shock. We&rsquo;re leaving sunny, 24ºC weather and heading towards a rainy 10ºC.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
