<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Cocktails | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/cocktails/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-21T14:47:57+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drinking Around Kreuzberg]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/17/drinking-around-kreuzberg/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-17T15:39:07+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/17/drinking-around-kreuzberg</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I say &ldquo;around Kreuzberg,&rdquo; that&rsquo;s a little misleading as we haven&rsquo;t really managed to explore the whole area. Berlin is pretty massive – more like London than Paris or New York. It&rsquo;s not that easy to walk to other areas (although we did take a nice stroll over to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friedrichshain">Friedrichshain</a> a couple of times).</p>

<p>As you are probably aware, Hampton and I scouted out as many cocktail bars as we could as soon as we arrived. For the past two weeks, we&rsquo;ve been slowly venturing further from our apartment to test out other places. Here&rsquo;s our list (and <a href="https://mapsengine.google.com/map/edit?mid=zSa_dTkSRnX0.kH2Fqz02A-M4">a handy map</a>).</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not sure why, but there&rsquo;s a cocktail bar named after a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Muir">noted American environmentalist</a>: <a href="http://johnmuirberlin.com/">John Muir</a>. To be honest, I only knew about him because I&rsquo;ve made a couple of day trips up to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muir_Woods_National_Monument">Muir Woods</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-outside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-outside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Entrance to John Muir</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Bar area – it's a little dark as it's in a half-cellar</div>
</div>


<p>The inside is all exposed brick, with a couple of naturalist touches (like some stuffed animals). It&rsquo;s nice and cosy (but the bathrooms are disco-themed??). They have a regularly-rotating drinks menu and their custom drinks are <em>really</em> good. I got the Lightning Bug, which was a citrus-gin thing with some other delicious extras (honey and lillet, I think?).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-drinks.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-drinks.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Lightning bug and a manhattan</div>
</div>


<p>I tried a couple of other cocktails on offer, and they were also excellent. It was strange that it never seemed to get too busy. Most people ordered beer or wine, and I wanted to shout at them because the cocktails were so tasty. Overall: 8.0/10</p>

<p>Not far from John Muir is <a href="">Kirk Bar</a>. Again, not really sure why it&rsquo;s named that. Star Trek reference, maybe? Nerds.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/kirk-bar.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/kirk-bar.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside Kirk Bar</div>
</div>


<p>The inside is pretty bad-ass. It has a real crumbling old-timey feel, with a patina most bars wish they could get. Beautiful cornicing and high ceilings. The first time we went, I was pretty drunk so I&rsquo;m not sure what I ordered. I think it was a gin sour – but I remember thinking it was good.</p>

<p>When we came back, I was more sober and remembered my drink order – a Hemingway sour. It was the same as a regular gin sour, but with grenadine added. (I thought Hemingway liked rum?)</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/kirk-sours.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/kirk-sours.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">On the left, a gin sour (?), on the right, Hemingway Sour</div>
</div>


<p>Overall: 7.6/10</p>

<p>I talked briefly about <a href="http://www.sage-restaurant.de/cms/">Sage</a> <a href="/blog/2014/08/13/berlin-how-do-you-think-it-feels/">in my previous post</a> – it&rsquo;s the bar on the water. Well, there&rsquo;s also a restaurant in a warehouse building just inland from the beach area. I&rsquo;ll talk about the food in another post, but I had a pretty amazing cocktail there. It was called the London garden and looked like a juice drink I&rsquo;d find in San Francisco.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/sage-london.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/sage-london.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">London Garden</div>
</div>


<p>It wasn&rsquo;t too sweet or too savoury, and it had the right amount of texture to it. It was so much more drinkable than those juices you find. Maybe it&rsquo;s the fact that it had alcohol in it or maybe it&rsquo;s&hellip; no, it was definitely the alcohol. Overall: 7.2/10</p>

<p><a href="http://www.homes-berlin.de/">Homes</a> was a little further away from our place, but we&rsquo;d read good reviews so we made the trek. It was decorated more like a casual coffee shop than a bar – it was very open, with low seating and &ldquo;cool&rdquo; murals on the walls.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/homes-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/homes-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside Homes</div>
</div>


<p>I guess it&rsquo;s a little unfair for me to be that dismissive – we were there pretty early for Berlin drinking time. Berlin is a very late city – people only consider going to a bar or club at midnight. I&rsquo;m happy to be in bed by then. It also means that bars are pretty empty around 7pm which means (yay) there&rsquo;s usually little wait but (boo) we&rsquo;re usually the only people in there.</p>

<p>Anyway, the drinks at Homes were passable. I got a gin-cacao-lillet thing that tasted way better than the ingredients list suggested.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/homes-chocolate.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/homes-chocolate.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Gin-cacao-lillet</div>
</div>


<p>I was a little underwhelmed. Overall: 6.5/10</p>

<p><a href="http://www.yelp.de/biz/schwarze-traube-berlin">Schwarze Traube</a> (&ldquo;black grape&rdquo;) was our first cocktail bar when we arrived. It&rsquo;s less than a block away from where we&rsquo;re staying and it had really good reviews. I was pretty excited.</p>

<p>The door has a sign saying you have to &ldquo;knock and smile&rdquo; to enter, which I did. The bartender was <em>not</em> happy to see us. She kind of pointed at some seats before going back behind the bar. The place is pretty small – two or three tiny rooms. The decor is great, though, with lots of fraying antique chairs and side-tables.</p>

<p>The bartender came over and told us they had a gin-based special drink. I ordered that one, and Hampton ordered a manhattan (which elicited a big sigh from the bartender). I like the idea of a no-menu, bartender-curated drinks list but only if the bartender is nice. Anyway, the drinks came after about fifteen minutes (which was weird, as we were the only people in there). They were really bloody good, and served in equisite, delicate glassware.</p>

<p>After we&rsquo;d finished our drinks, we had to wait another twenty minutes of the bartender disappearing and/or ignoring our requests for the bill. Great cocktails, but not really worth the lacklustre service. Overall: 5.6</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Berlin: How Do You Think It Feels]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/13/berlin-how-do-you-think-it-feels/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-13T14:17:16+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/13/berlin-how-do-you-think-it-feels</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aIofRTmTYVc">Title from Lou Reed&rsquo;s album, Berlin</a>)</p>

<p>Berlin doesn&rsquo;t feel European, and it&rsquo;s not quite like anywhere else Hampton and I have visited. It doesn&rsquo;t really seem to fit any classification, there&rsquo;s so much about it that&rsquo;s unique. I get that other cities have unique qualities. Paris has&hellip; <em>Parisian</em> things about it that make it unique – but it still feels European. Berlin does not. Maybe it&rsquo;s because  of its recent tumultuous history. Maybe it&rsquo;s because the idea of &ldquo;Europeanness&rdquo; includes Paris, and London, and Rome, but somehow left out Berlin. For whatever reason, it&rsquo;s an alluring city that we made a point of returning to.</p>

<p>Last time we visited Berlin, we stayed in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prenzlauer_Berg">Prenzlauer Berg</a>, a hip ex-East Berlin neighbourhood in the north of the city. This time, we chose to stay in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kreuzberg">Kreuzberg</a>.</p>

<p>Along with Prenzlauer Berg and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friedrichshain">Friedrichshain</a>, Kreuzberg is considered to be the trendier, less-polished side of the city. Although technically in West Berlin during the separation of Germany, Kreuzberg was on the eastern edge of the city, so was relatively underdeveloped. Since the fall of the Berlin Wall, all three neighbourhoods have undergone varying levels of gentrification.</p>

<p>Coming from the obvious beauty of Prague or Amsterdam, Berlin was a little brutal. On our block, there are multiple featureless, indistinguishable mid-1970s apartment complexes. They&rsquo;re covered in graffiti and look pretty drab.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/kreuzberg-apartment.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/kreuzberg-apartment.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Typical Kreuzberg apartment building</div>
</div>


<p>So far, I&rsquo;m probably not painting a great picture of Berlin, am I? The thing that really draws Hampton and me to the city is the people and the atmosphere. I&rsquo;d call it artistic or care-free; I&rsquo;m sure an American could equally describe it as entrepreneurial. Confused? Let me try and describe an example.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re staying just off the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spree">Spree</a>. It&rsquo;s a little industrial along our side of the river, with brick warehouses and lots of gates. We saw some place recommended on FourSquare along the river, but weren&rsquo;t that sure where it was. After walking through what looked like a gate to an industrial estate, we saw a couple of shipping containers stacked on top of each other with a 1970s car on top.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar-entry.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar-entry.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Shipping container garden</div>
</div>


<p>As you continue walking towards the bank of the river, you see a makeshift beach.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Sage Bar – a beach</div>
</div>


<p>And there&rsquo;s this wonderful bar, hidden away, popular at all times of the day. Kids are running around playing in their sand as their tattooed, mid-thirties parents sip an Aperol and soda. There&rsquo;s grey-haired couples drinking tall beers, reading books. And right across the river is one of the longest <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Side_Gallery">still-standing stretches of the Berlin Wall</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar-view.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar-view.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">View over the Spree and the Berlin Wall</div>
</div>


<p>Berlin is such a strange mixture of rule-following, energy, and laissez-faireness. People are frenetic and excited on the streets, playing loud music and drinking and rushing to the next bar&hellip; before languishing the next morning over a three-hour brunch. It takes a while to get used to, but it&rsquo;s something that I find very energising and disruptive.</p>

<p>One of the strangest moments so far was going for karaoke with the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Travis_CI">Travis CI</a> folks. The karaoke bar was just across the river from Kreuzberg, in Friedrichshain. To get there, we walked along the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oberbaum_Bridge">Oberbaum bridge</a>, which used to be an East-West border crossing.</p>

<p>We then walked past a stretch of the Berlin Wall, which was turned into an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Side_Gallery">open-air gallery</a> soon after the unification of Germany.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/east-side-gallery.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/east-side-gallery.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The East Side Gallery</div>
</div>


<p>The gallery itself is really neat, and on a separate occasion we took a longer stroll along it.</p>

<p>Anyway, we got to karaoke, sang a few songs, drank a few beers. Then someone put on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%22Heroes%22_(David_Bowie_song)">&ldquo;Heroes&rdquo;</a> by David Bowie. Recorded in the 1970s in Berlin, it&rsquo;s about two lovers who can&rsquo;t be together: one is from East Berlin, and one is from West Berlin.</p>

<p>And there we were, singing about the horror of the wall, in a karaoke bar about 500ft away, having just crossed an ex-border crossing.</p>

<p>Above all, Berlin is wonderful and strange.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Food and Drink in Amsterdam]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/09/amsterdam-food/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-09T13:20:31+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/09/amsterdam-food</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We visited a couple of great cocktail bars while in Amsterdam. The first was <a href="http://www.door-74.com/">Door 74</a>. You need to phone up to get a reservation, but we did that literally minutes before knocking on the door, and they had a table.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Unassuming door</div>
</div>


<p>The menu was neat. I got the impression it was seasonal, as it was heavily themed on 60s sci-fi despite the bar not having anything remotely about that. They had a few drinks from every planet. Each drink had a ray-gun indicator next to it showing how strong the drink was.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-menu.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-menu.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Menu</div>
</div>


<p>Our friend got the special, some blend of vodka and fruit juice that was served in a tiki container. It was poured at the table, which was neat.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-kettle.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-kettle.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The special – poured out of a dry-ice kettle</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-gin.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-gin.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Tezuka's Lost World</div>
</div>


<p>The other place we enjoyed was <a href="http://njoycocktails.com/">NJoy</a>. It&rsquo;s slightly odd – there&rsquo;s lots of neon lighting and trying-hard-to-be-hip furniture, like a scene out of Sex and the City.</p>

<p>The menu was arranged into pretentious categories – each a supposed personality type. Are you an Alchemist or a Trendsetter? A Dreamer or a Connoisseur? The drinks were all novel and had some really interesting combinations of flavours. The bartenders were really friendly and the drinks were well-made and delicious – and that&rsquo;s why we kept coming back.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-chartreuse.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-chartreuse.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Something with Chartreuse that I ordered</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-monkey.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-monkey.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Monkey's Martini</div>
</div>


<p>A word of warning: NJoy is located on &ldquo;restaurant row&rdquo; (Leidsedwarsstraat). It&rsquo;s full of possibly the most pushy restaurants I&rsquo;ve ever walked past. In super-touristy areas, I&rsquo;m used to people asking, &ldquo;You looking for a place to eat? We have delicious steak!&rdquo; and me ignoring them. This was a whole other level. People hold menus in your face, they block your way, they won&rsquo;t let you past unless you&rsquo;ve responded to them. Our tactic to avoid this as best as we could was to appear to be in a heated debate as we rapidly walked the gauntlet.</p>

<p>Anyway, onto food. When travelling, I enjoy eating the local food. <a href="https://twitter.com/roy">Roy</a>, our Dutch friend who met us on our first night in Amsterdam, explained that there&rsquo;s not much that&rsquo;s considered Dutch cuisine. It&rsquo;s mostly French food or German. Anyway, we tried our best and visited <a href="http://www.thepantry.nl/">The Pantry</a>. They called themselves Dutch cuisine, so hey, let&rsquo;s give it a go.</p>

<p>I got a trio of what were essentially mashed potatoes with other stuff in them. In the picture below, starting from the top and going clockwise, there&rsquo;s:</p>

<ul>
<li>Zuurkoolstamppot (sauerkraut)</li>
<li>Hustpot (beef, carrots, onions)</li>
<li>Boerenkoolstamppot (kale)</li>
</ul>


<p>(with a meatball in the middle)</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/potatoes.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/potatoes.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Mashed potatoes</div>
</div>


<p>The sauerkraut one was the best. Nom nom.</p>

<p>The other thing that seemed to be everywhere was pancakes. We went to a pancake place and saw they had <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poffertjes">poffertjes</a> – a kind of cross between beignets and American-style pancakes. They were served with butter and icing sugar. Very healthy.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/poffertjes.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/poffertjes.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Poffertjes</div>
</div>


<p>We went for a memorable meal at a steak and ribs place – <a href="http://www.castellamsterdam.nl/en/">Castell</a>. We made a reservation, showed up on time, and the waiter showed us to our table. We were a little confused. Rather than a regular dining table, it was coffee table-height, and our seats were leather benches surrounding one end (another group was at the other end).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-table.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-table.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Our table (we ordered some escargot)</div>
</div>


<p>We weren&rsquo;t quite sure whether this was a pre-dinner drink table or what. But soon we received some wicker trays, one per person, on which to eat our steaks.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-lap.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-lap.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hampton with his tray</div>
</div>


<p>I got the ribs, and Hampton got a steak. They came on wooden blocks with little copper pans of sauce, and were delivered onto our trays. Eating was challenging, to say the least. There was no real space to put your tray if you needed to get up. I couldn&rsquo;t really reach my drink without my shirt getting ribs all over it. It was <em>not</em> easy.</p>

<p><strong>But</strong> (and it&rsquo;s a big one) – those ribs were amazing. No, seriously – possibly the best ribs I&rsquo;ve ever had (and I&rsquo;ve spent time in the South). The meat was tender, falling off the bone, and had a crisp char. The rub they used had just the right balance of vinegar, spice, and sugar. I&rsquo;d <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aYsLh4QjBPc#t=16">step over my own mother</a> for those ribs.</p>

<p>Something we noticed in Amsterdam – the service is slow. Exceptionally slow. Even taking into account European-style service (which we&rsquo;re both fine with!), Amsterdam added an extra level to that. Not sure why, but there you go.</p>

<p>Anyway, now we&rsquo;re in Berlin for a couple of weeks. We&rsquo;re staying in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kreuzberg">Kreuzberg</a> district, so stay tuned for posts about that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AnonymouS Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/30/anonymous-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-30T10:10:05+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/30/anonymous-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>Our time in Prague is almost at an end – today, we're taking a flight to Amsterdam. We saved an intriguing bar for our last new experience in the cocktail world of Prague. <a href="http://www.anonymousbar.cz/cs"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">AnonymouS Bar</span></a> (their weird capitalisation, not mine) is off a small alley in the old town, and it is themed around the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gunpowder_Plot">gunpowder plot</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/V_for_Vendetta">V for Vendetta</a>, and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anonymous_(group)">Anonymous</a> movement.</p>

  <p>Inside, the bar is styled like the interior of V's hideout in the comic book/film. It allows the use of comfortable chairs, but also brick-showing-through-plaster murals and classic portraits with faces replaced by the Guy Fawkes mask. It kind of reminded us (in the best way possible, as we're theme park nerds) of a Universal Studios or Disney experience.</p>

  <p>The menu has a really great concept: a list of standard drinks on one page, paired up with an AnonymouS-bar twist on the classics. It was a goodway to quickly pick out a drink you'd be sure to like. I went for the St Marry's Virus – again, that's their weird spelling, and I'm not sure if it's deliberate or not. It was a twist on the Piccadilly martini. The bartender came over with a biohazard box, which opened to reveal a giant syringe containing the cocktial.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-st-marrys.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-st-marrys.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">St Marry's Virus</div>
  </div>

  <p>Hampton went for a take on a gimlet, and it was really delicious! I think they added cucumber and some other stuff.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-butterfly.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-butterfly.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">M. Butterfly</div>
  </div>

  <p>The menu, aside from the drink and liquor list, was pretty entertaining. They had neat explanation of their thought process behind the concept. As I was flicking through, I noticed there was a cocktail set apart from the rest, alone on the very first page. It didn't have a description, aside from the old rhyme: "Remember, remember the fifth of November..." It was too puzzling not to get.</p>

  <p>Hampton got it after me, so I have photos of what it entailed. The bartender handed you a Guy Fawkes mask and took your photo.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-photo.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-photo.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">They had to find more film</div>
  </div>

  <p>After that, they make the drink. It involved lining a brandy snifter with liquor and setting it on fire. Once the fire had died down, they poured in a whisky-based old-fashioned-esque cocktail. They placed the photo on top to stop the smoke from the flames coming out.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-remember.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-remember.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Remember</div>
  </div>

  <p>Here are the photos of our night. It's nice to have something to keep after a night out. Especially once you've had a few cocktails.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-polaroid.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-polaroid.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Ahh, memories!</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">The themeing theatricality of AnonymouS bar is great, but it's really backed up by the delicious cocktails on offer.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">8.5</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orange Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/orange-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-23T10:33:48+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/orange-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.orangebar.cz/en/homepage.html"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Orange Bar</span></a> is pretty close by to us and has decent reviews. It's a little tricky to find, down a couple of side-streets, but there's a nice orange-shaped sign outside to let you know when you're there.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/outside.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/outside.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">From the street</div>
  </div>

  <p>From the outside, it looks pretty normal, right? Inside, though, it reminded me of a bar in Dune or something. The only lights had orange filters, and all the walls were molded to give the appearance of being dug out of a cave.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/bar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/bar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The bar (I think the spice is kept on the top shelf)</div>
  </div>

  <p>The bar shelves were all integrated into the back wall. The other walls had fake columns with cubbies for desert plants.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/plants.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/plants.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Walls with plants</div>
  </div>

  <p>The cocktail list leaned heavily towards rum-based beach drinks – mai tais, piña coladas, zombies etc. There's also a good list of classics, too. Hampton went for (of course) a manhattan. I tried out the mai tai but it was a little too sweet for me.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/cocktails.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/cocktails.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Manhattan and a mai tai</div>
  </div>

  <p>We were there during a massive thunderstorm and didn't have umbrellas, so we stayed for another round (or two). The moscow mule was <em>much</em> better. Get that! It had a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physalis_peruviana">physalis</a> garnish too, which is awesome.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/moscow-mule.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/moscow-mule.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Moscow mule</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Orange bar has a neighbourhood feel and a fun theme. The drinks are sweet, but tasty, so I'd stick to non-tiki drinks (unless you're a particular fan).</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">7.1</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
