<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Cocktails | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/cocktails/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-05T13:57:47+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nightjar]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/04/nightjar/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-04T12:49:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/04/nightjar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">
  <p>We are in London for a few nights and squeezing in as many activities as possible. Obviously, a major focus of this was drinking. Finding cocktails here is pretty easy compared with continental Europe – within a few blocks of where we're staying there's <a href="http://www.happinessforgets.com/">Happiness Forgets</a> and <a href="http://www.calloohcallaybar.com/">Callooh Callay</a>, both excellent cocktail bars. </p>

  <p>However, I was most excited about visiting <a href="http://barnightjar.com"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Nightjar</span></a>. We were recommended it by a friend in San Francisco. The menu online looked interesting, so I booked a table. There's no standing in the bar, and you have to have a table to get service. I booked about four days before, on a Tuesday, and could only get a table at 6pm.</p>

  <p>It's behind an unassuming door <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/preview?q=nightjar&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;ei=3FyPU4TXOsXhPPGVgKAI&amp;ved=0CAoQ_AUoAw">just near Old Street underground station</a>. The bouncer checks your name against a list, and sends you downstairs. After being in the daylight, heading down a candle-lit staircase was a little disorienting. At the bottom of the stairs, the maitre d' (is that even what they're called in a cocktail bar?) welcomed us and sat us down at a small table next to a cabinet of old liqueuers.</p>


  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/mat.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Nightjar coaster</div>
  </div>

  <p>The menu had an incredible cover, with the Nightjar appearing on it multiple times. Throughout the night the silhouette of the bird was a recurring theme – punched into lemon-rinds or branded on the side of a mug.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/menu.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Menu</div>
  </div>

  <p>The menu was extensive, sorted by pre-prohibition, prohibition, post-war and signature drinks. Most of the cocktails had at least one ingredient I'd never heard of. It took us a while to decide what to go for, but the bartender was helpful in pointing you towards certain things. With her help, I chose the <a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/new-orleans-daisy">New Orleans Daisy</a> as it had chartreuse in it – but the bartender suggested I take it with gin. Turns out it comes in an owl-shaped container with a candied hibiscus flower and a peacock feather.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/new-orleans-daisy.jpg">
    <div class="alt">New Orleans Daisy</div>
  </div>

  <p>It was really quite incredible. It had an almost buttery flavour with a nectar aftertaste.</p>

  <p>Our friend went for the <a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/london-mule">London Mule</a>. The picture below doesn't quite convey the size of the mug: it was probably about 12 inches high. Most of that was packed ice. It was a great interpretation of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moscow_mule">mule</a>-style of drink.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/london-mule.jpg">
    <div class="alt">London Mule</div>
  </div>

  <p>Hampton got a <a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/toronto">Toronto</a>, which was similar to an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Fashioned">Old Fashioned</a> but with maple syrup as the sweetener. Its garnish was a candy-floss nest with some mini-eggs in it.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/toronto.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Toronto</div>
  </div>

  <p>I noticed another table received a cocktail in some sort of two-neck condensing flask. I asked what it was, and it's called the <a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/foragers-shrub">Forager's Shrub</a>. Of course I went for that next.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/foragers-shrub1.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Forager's Shrub in flask</div>
  </div>

  <p>The cocktail itself was in the bigger bulb. In the internal, smaller bulb was an oil with some dry ice (I think). It produced a vapour which I was instructed to smell. It smelt of pine and nettles, like a forest after some rain.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/foragers-shrub2.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Must-smell item</div>
  </div>

  <p>The bartender then poured the drink out – the fragrant oil into a chalice and the drink itself into a tumbler with ice. I was instructed to smell the oils before drinking. Sure, it was fairly pretentious but here's the thing – the smell really did make it taste different. And the cocktail was amazing, so I didn't care if I looked like a wally taking a big huff before every sip.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/foragers-shrub3.jpg">
    <div class="alt">The final cocktail (yes that's a mini corn on the cob)</div>
  </div>

  <p>My last drink was a <a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/marmalade-no-2">Marmalade Nº 2</a>. It tasted exactly like a Seville orange marmalade – acidic, bitter, bursting with orange flavour. I loved it.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/london/nightjar/marmalade-2.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Marmalade Nº 2</div>
  </div>

  <p>Other drinks we had but I didn't take pictures of:</p>

  <ul>
    <li><a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/bloody-mary">Bloody Mary</a> – served in a hollowed-out squash (you can almost see it behind the Marmalade Nº 2 above)</li>
    <li><a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/name-samurai">Name of the Samurai</a> - served in an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sake_set">ochoko</a> set inside a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Masu_(Japanese)">masu</a> which had burnt herbs inside</li>
    <li><a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/secret-cocktail">Secret Cocktail</a> – a gin/egg white combination that was pretty tasty, but had icing sugar around the whole glass so was impossible to drink without getting sticky</li>
    <li><a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/deep-sea">Deep Sea</a> - had squid ink in it, and had nori around the rim of the glass</li>
    <li><a href="http://www.barnightjar.com/drinks/prairie-flip">Prarie Flip</a> – had a garnish of a boiled quail's egg and had a weird garlicky taste... not sure I'd recommend this one</li>
  </ul>

  <p>The cocktails weren't too expensive – between £8 and £12 was the average. Considering that such care went into not only the flavours, but also the decoration and presentation, I found it to be a worthwhile treat.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Nightjar serves innovative cocktails in both taste and presentation.</span> I can see Hampton and I coming back here whenever we're in London. </p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">9.6</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drinking in the Costa Del Sol]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/29/drinking-costa-del-sol/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-29T10:37:41+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/29/drinking-costa-del-sol</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The next stage of our trip took us to the south of Spain – the &ldquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Costa_del_Sol">Costa del Sol</a>,&rdquo; a clichéd destination for sun-starved Brits. My family were meeting us there and spending a few days in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mijas">Mijas</a> – a small village scattered on mountains overlooking the Mediterranean.</p>

<p>Our fruitful cocktail hunt in Paris was great. However, we didn&rsquo;t want to push our luck, so we decided to try some more traditional drinks while in a less cosmopolitan area.</p>

<p>First up: fino. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fino">Fino</a> is a dry sherry served very cold. It&rsquo;s taken as an apéretif, and apparently it&rsquo;s what all the locals drink. I&rsquo;m a fan of sherry, so I thought I&rsquo;d try it out.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/fino.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Glass of fino</div>
</div>


<p>With regular sherry, the sweetness cuts through some of the flavour of the alcohol, which makes it palatable to me. With fino, you could definitely taste the alcohol compared with &ldquo;sweet&rdquo; sherry. The fino started with a sharp acidity, then followed with a fresher aftertaste. If I lived in Spain, I&rsquo;d probably get used to it, but I wouldn&rsquo;t necessarily order it again.</p>

<p>Next up, at <a href="http://www.tripadvisor.co.uk/Restaurant_Review-g580271-d2413104-Reviews-Pampa_Tablas_y_Tapas-Mijas_Costa_del_Sol_Province_of_Malaga_Andalucia.html">a local tapas bar called Pampa</a>, we tried the stereotypical Spanish alcoholic drink: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sangria">sangria</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/sangria.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Glass and pitcher of sangria</div>
</div>


<p>Sangria is awesome and I presume everyone has had it. If not, you should try it. It&rsquo;s traditionally made with red wine, brandy, and some kind of sweetener. You also put in pieces of chopped fruit. However, I believe this one had some rum in it as well. I&rsquo;ll try adding rum when I next make sangria at home, cause it added a nice kick.</p>

<p>On our final night, we went to a &ldquo;gin bar.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s a slight misnomer: for one, it&rsquo;s more of a tapas place, and for two it served other alcohol as well. But gin is where this place shone. <a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/graphicdetail/2013/06/daily-chart-9">Spain is one of the highest per capita consumers of gin</a> (other fun facts from the linked infographic: India is the largest consumer of rum, and France is the largest consumer of Scotch). So, despite being a traditionally British drink, we had some Spanish-style gin and tonics.</p>

<p>The bar we were at, <a href="http://www.bodegaelplacer.com/">Bodega El Placer</a>, had about thirty gins on offer. There were five of us and we asked for five different gins, so we could sample them all. Each gin came in a big glass with ice and individually-prepared garnishes.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/just-gin.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Gin with garnishes</div>
</div>


<p>The garnishes ranged from juniper berries, cinnamon sticks and cardamom seeds to a simple lemon slice. The gins were all pretty different. Luckily, I liked a deep-flavoured sour gin that no one else enjoyed, so I didn&rsquo;t have to fight to finish that one off. I believe it was <a href="http://www.bulldoggin.com/">Bulldog gin</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/tonic-regular.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Gin and tonic</div>
</div>


<p>Fun fact: in most of Europe, when you want a gin and tonic, you just say &ldquo;gintonic.&rdquo; All one word.</p>

<p>They also had a blue tonic, but I&rsquo;m not really sure what the difference between regular tonic and the blue stuff was. I was a bad scientist and didn&rsquo;t do a same-gin, different-tonic experiment.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/tonic-blue.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Blue tonic?!</div>
</div>


<p>I should also mention the tapas: it was really good. It was more inventive than I was expecting – they had tempura aubergine with a honey sauce, and a melt-in-your-mouth tuna sashimi plate. My favourite, of course, was the jamón. It was one of the better jamón ibérico we had while in Spain.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/mijas/jamon.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Jamón ibérico</div>
</div>


<p>We were only in Spain a few days. Despite that, we managed to do two excellent day trips: one to Granada to see the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alhambra">Alhambra</a> (check out some photos <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/malrase/sets/72157644507980879/">on Flickr</a>), and one to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gibraltar">Gibraltar</a> (<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/malrase/sets/72157644507822700/">Flickr photos</a>). If you&rsquo;re ever in the south of Spain, I highly recommend taking a trip to those. I also hear Seville is great, but we didn&rsquo;t make it there.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re now on our way to the UK, which I&rsquo;m worried will be a bit of a shock. We&rsquo;re leaving sunny, 24ºC weather and heading towards a rainy 10ºC.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cocktails in Paris]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/24/cocktails-in-paris/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-24T13:08:01+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/24/cocktails-in-paris</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Living in San Francisco, we&rsquo;re spoiled when it comes to cocktails. Almost any bar you wander into could make a half-decent manhattan or gimlet. As <a href="/blog/2014/05/13/linz">I&rsquo;ve brought up before</a>, cocktails in Europe are a little lacking. Hampton and I wanted to find some decent mixed drinks, so did some research on the cocktail scene in Paris.</p>

<p>There are a handful of well-rated places, and we learnt that the first high-end cocktail bar to be successful was the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Experimental-Cocktail-Club/129531980432588">Experimental Cocktail Club</a> (&ldquo;ECC&rdquo;), which has been open for about six years. Apparently, a number of trainee bartenders from there have spread across the city, opening their own high-end cocktail bars. We went to three (alas, we didn&rsquo;t make it to the ECC).</p>

<p>We ended up at the similarly-named <a href="http://www.prescriptioncocktailclub.com/">Prescription Cocktail Club</a>, in the <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Prescription+Cocktail+Club/@48.854997,2.337909,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x9d147b310bda215">Saint Germain quarter</a>, as it was close to one of our favourite restaurants in Paris (<a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/fish-la-boissonnerie-paris-2">Fish la Boissonnerie</a>). There was no obvious sign from the street that it was a cocktail bar, but we were pretty sure we had the right address. We peered in a window and saw a bunch of people sipping cocktails, so we went in. Although we showed up at 9pm on a Friday, we were lucky enough to get a table. The service was pretty good (there was table service at every bar we went to), and the cocktails were competent. I ordered something with gin, green Chartreuse, and crème de menthe. It was a little too sweet for my taste, but drinkable nontheless.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.lemaryceleste.com/">Mary Celeste</a> was another bar we went to. It had pretty good cocktails and some tasty-looking tapas – we&rsquo;d just eaten so we&rsquo;ll have to go back for the food.</p>

<p>The bizarrely-named <a href="http://www.sherrybuttparis.com/">Sherry Butt</a>, <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Sherry+Butt/@48.853303,2.364085,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x47e671ffaa10ef7d:0x2b98a01f163bffd1">not far from Bastille</a>, was probably my favourite cocktail bar that we went to. We went on a Thursday night and it was really quiet (being quiet is definitely a bonus for us). The bar was set up like a workshop – unfinished wood tables and odd contraptions on shelves. The menu was inventive and they seemed to produce a lot of their own syrups and flavourings for their drinks. Although they only listed their own concoctions, I asked for a Last Word and the bartender didn&rsquo;t hesitate to make one. The bartender was super-friendly and explained to us the cocktail scene in Paris – about how the &ldquo;ECC&rdquo; started it all, and that most of the high-end bartenders originated there. He was surprised we hadn&rsquo;t been to Candelaria, and strongly recommended we go there next.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.candelariaparis.com/">Candelaria</a>, just <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Candelaria/@48.862981,2.364034,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0xfe5e1d4c40b38ec0">south of République</a>, is a pretty strange place. It reminded me of something you&rsquo;d find in San Francisco. From the street, it&rsquo;s a tiny, bright taqueria. There&rsquo;s one table and a handful of seats at a bar. At 9pm on a Thursday night, it was packed. People were spilling out onto the street, and we were told it would be a 30min wait if we wanted food. However, we were there for the cocktails.</p>

<p>If you squeeze past the people sitting at the diner-style bar, there&rsquo;s an unmarked door. Go through it and you&rsquo;re in a much larger room – although equally busy – lit by candles. The space was decorated with Day-of-the-Dead style skeletons and it really did feel like we were back in the Mission. Unfortunately, the cocktails were mediocre. We hadn&rsquo;t reserved a table ahead, so we were stuck standing elbow-to-elbow with the hipsters of Paris. It was a little clostrophobic in there.</p>

<p>We went to another cocktail bar/tapas restaurant nearby Candelaria: <a href="http://www.lemaryceleste.com/cocktails/">Le Mary Celeste</a>. As far as I know, the bartenders weren&rsquo;t ECC alumni, but they had a neat cocktail menu. The bar had a vaguely nautical theme, and the cocktails were refreshing – both on-menu and classics like a manhattan or a gimlet. If you&rsquo;re in the area, and want to get away from the intensity of Candelaria, I&rsquo;d say it&rsquo;s a good call.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s worth pointing out that cocktails in Paris are expensive. €13 (~$18) was not unusual. Compare that to cocktails in San Francisco, where anything more than $12 would be considered pricey. It&rsquo;s a trade-off, obviously – the price of a baguette (80¢ or ~$1.10) or some great cheese is way less in Paris than in San Francisco.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m happy we found these places. Most were a little tricky to track down, but fun to drink at. It&rsquo;s good to know there are decent cocktial bars in Paris – even if you have to walk down a weird side-alley to get to them. I look forward to finding more next time we&rsquo;re in the city.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Philadelphia]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/02/philadelphia-revolutions-and-murals/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-02T21:00:41+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/02/philadelphia-revolutions-and-murals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a quick trip to Jacksonville for my father-in-law&rsquo;s birthday, our next stop was Philadelphia. I had only visited Philadelphia by passing through its airport, and I&rsquo;ve heard a lot about it as a city, so I was excited to spend a few days there. I was on my best behaviour and only made one joke about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It's_Always_Sunny_in_Philadelphia">it being sunny</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/phl/chesse-steak.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Classic Philly chesse steak</div>
</div>


<p>Our first night we went to <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/the-ranstead-room-philadelphia">the Ranstead Room</a>, at 20th and Ranstead. It&rsquo;s down an alley behind a modest black door.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/phl/ranstead.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Door to Ranstead Room</div>
</div>


<p>The cocktails were classics done well – try one of the fizzes if you&rsquo;re unsure where to start. The bartender was great at asking what you like and making something up. I got a Chartreuse and egg white drink (called the, uh, &ldquo;Chika Chika Boom Boom&rdquo;) that I thoroughly enjoyed.</p>

<p>They serve food from the pared-down menu of their sister restaurant, El Rey. They had great tacos, plus some amazing popcorn with Jamaican spice that was both citrusy and umami.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><a href="http://twitter.com/amyhoy">Our delightful host</a> took us on a tour of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_City,_Philadelphia">Old City</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Society_Hill,_Philadelphia">Society Hill</a>, and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_Street_(Philadelphia)">South Street</a>. Old City and Society Hill have quaint colonial houses with a lot of history. Maybe I&rsquo;ve been living in San Francisco too long, but I was impressed with all the pre-1800 buildings.</p>

<p>We stopped in <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/jinxed-tuckers-digs-philadelphia">a neat store</a> that seemed to sell a lot of odd items (including lamps made out of what looked like spinal columns). On the way out, I looked down a small alley – <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/@39.941169,-75.148958,3a,75y,102.7h,81.52t/data=!3m4!1e1!3m2!1sQadqWDkEoiNfRxrUPPZrGA!2e0">Kater St</a> – to see some incredible mosaic-murals.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/phl/kater-mural.jpg">
  <div class="alt">South side of Kater St</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/phl/mural-selfie.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Up close: mosaic selfie! </div>
</div>


<p>The mosaics are the work of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isaiah_Zagar">Isaiah Zagar</a>, who has around 200 mosaics in the South Street area of Philadelphia. They use a lot of mirror pieces and include quotations and the address of the place. They were mesmerising and I felt I could have spent hours sitting in front of them. Apparently there&rsquo;s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_a_Dream_(film)">a movie about him</a>, so I&rsquo;ll have to check that out.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/phl/kater-mural2.jpg">
  <div class="alt">North side of Kater St</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/phl/mural-selfie2.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Up close</div>
</div>


<p>I&rsquo;d like to spend more time in the South Street area of Philadelphia to find more of these murals.</p>

<h3>An aside:</h3>

<p>The amount of history in Philadelphia, especially regarding the founding of the United States and the beginning of the revolutionary war, was a little overwhelming.</p>

<p>Obviously, I&rsquo;m not ignorant of the history between the UK and the USA. Being British in the USA leads to good-natured ribbing about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_coat_(British_army)">being a redcoat</a>. However, wandering around the centre of where the USA was founded and independence was sought is different. Everywhere there&rsquo;s information about how the revolutionaries were throwing off their repressive chains and seeking liberty. Implicit in all of the historical placards and explanatory signage was that they wanted to get away from the baddies. And in this case, the baddies were my ancestors (well, kinda).</p>

<p>I felt defensive, like I needed to stand up for my country: the UK wasn&rsquo;t <em>that</em> bad, was it? I&rsquo;m not a patriotic person, so feeling protective about my homeland was novel. I also felt conspicuous – that some tell would give me away, and people would be mad that the enemy was desecrating their site,  even though I was just standing there. I was sure I was only a moment away from being kicked out of the Constitution Museum or something.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve never really lived in another country, so I assume this is a pretty standard foreigner&rsquo;s paranoia. Maybe I should start wearing one of those sweet <a href="http://www.animalshirts.net/americanflagshirts/eaglefly.jpg">stars-and-stripes, eagle-soaring shirts</a> to blend in more.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Columbia Room]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/04/25/the-columbia-room/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-25T19:29:59+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/04/25/the-columbia-room</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>I was glad our friend had already been to <a href="http://columbiaroomdc.com/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">The Columbia Room</span></a> and met us outside, otherwise I don't think we would have been able to find it. It's hidden in the back of an upscale dive bar called The Passenger on 7th St in D.C. Inside, it's tiny (I think there were ten seats) and sparsely-decorated (some apothecary-style bottles with herbs were behind the bar). The service, level of expertise from the bartenders, and the inventiveness of flavour pairings reminded me of the few Michelin-starred restaurants I've been to. Except with liquor instead of food.</p>

  <p>The set menu consists of three drinks and a couple of snacks, coming in at around $65 per person. Pricey, but definitely worth it.</p>

  <!-- more -->

  <p>After being offered cold towels scented with cucumber (!), we started out with a rum and lemon-based punch served in a teacup. It tasted pretty much like iced tea – but, y'know, alcoholic. So better than regular iced tea.</p>

  <p>The second drink, the Getaway, had two main ingredients: a black rum and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cynar">cynar</a> (<em>chee</em>-nar). </p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/dc/getaway-ingredients.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Ingredients for the Getaway</div>
  </div>

  <p>Cynar is a dark brown artichoke-based liqueur. It has a number of other spices in it, so it's not like you're drinking artichoke juice or anything. Mixed with the dark rum, some salted bitters and a bit of lemon, and wow. With each sip you went through four or five different flavour profiles – acidity of the lemon, saltiness, herbs, molasses. It was extremely drinkable and all three of us had to pace ourselves so we didn't finish it in two gulps.</p>

  <p>The Getaway was served with an artichoke (to pair with the cynar) and green olive tapenade-type thing. It was pretty tasty, but I wish there had been more of it. Or maybe I should have eaten more for dinner.</p>

  <p>For last cocktail of the set, we had a choice. Either a cynar and grapefruit/blood orange soda <strong>or</strong> a cynar and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Akvavit">akvavit</a> combination. Two of us plumped for the cynar/aquavit drink – it tasted a lot like a negroni. The soda drink was refreshing and a nice end to the tasting.</p>

  <p>As the previous cocktails were so good, we decided to stay for another one each. We asked the bartender for two gin-based drinks – one with citrus and one without.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/dc/dry-martini.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Dry Martini</div>
  </div>

  <p>Hampton got a dry martini with Plymouth gin. It was pretty delicious. The bartender recommended Plymouth as a good go-to gin that mixes well with other ingredients.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/dc/last-word-ingredients.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Last Word Ingredients</div>
  </div>

  <p>I received a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Word_(cocktail)">Last Word</a> – Tanqueray 10 gin, Luxardo <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maraschino">maraschino liqueur</a>, lime juice and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chartreuse_(liqueur)">Chartreuse</a>. I had been drinking Chartreuse the previous Saturday, both neat and in a Chartreuse gimlet. I liked it a lot, so I was pretty excited it came up in the cocktail the bartender made for me here.</p>

  <p>The Maraschino liqueur was strange. I'm familiar with Luxardo-style maraschino cherries, so was expecting the liqueuer to be a deep purple syrup. However, it looked and tasted more like a simple syrup that had a hint of cherry flavour.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/dc/last-word-cocktail.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Last Word</div>
  </div>

  <p>Mixing all of them together was amazing. The freshness of the limes worked well with the herbal qualities of the gin and the Chartreuse. The Maraschino added a touch of sweetness to round it all out. Apparently, the bartender likes to put a little more gin compared to normal Last Word-style drinks, which is what he said gives his the edge over the competition.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">I highly recommend visiting this place if you're in the D.C. area.</span> We managed to make reservations a couple of weeks in advance for a Wednesday night. I hear the building is being taken over soon – although I assume they will be moving to a new location.</p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">9.1</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
