<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Disneyland | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/disneyland/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-30T13:17:06-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drinking at the Disneyland Resort]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2015/06/20/drinking-in-disneyland/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-20T14:00:29-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2015/06/20/drinking-in-disneyland</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We were in the mountains above Los Angeles for <a href="http://www.maxfuncon.com/">MaxFunCon</a>, a neat comedy/podcasting conference at which we had a lot of fun. Since we were in L.A., why not head to the Disneyland Resort in Anaheim, too?</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s Disneyland&rsquo;s 60th anniversary, so there&rsquo;s a lot of cool stuff going on. In particular, the fireworks at Disneyland are spectacular. If you can make it before the celebrations are over, it&rsquo;s well worth it. Make sure to get a prime spot on Main Street and you won&rsquo;t be disappointed.</p>

<p>Anyway, the rides and all that are fun, but a more pressing question is: are those of us who like cocktails doomed to saccharine cruise-ship drinks while at the parks?</p>

<p>We set off to find out.</p>

<p>The first point: of the two parks in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disneyland_Resort">Disneyland Resort</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disneyland">Disneyland</a> is completely dry (well, apart from <a href="http://www.snopes.com/disney/parks/club33.asp">Club 33</a>). The only park you&rsquo;ll find a drink in is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disney_California_Adventure">Disney California Adventure</a>.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s where we started our investigatory stroll. Our first stop was the Alfresco Tasting Terrace. We&rsquo;d been there on a previous trip, but since then they had stopped serving cocktails. There&rsquo;s only wine and beer now.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/disney/june15/alfresco-terrace.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/alfresco-terrace.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Alfresco Tasting Terrace</div>
</div>


<p>They have wine flights, which are pretty fun. And all the wineries seem to have some connection to Disney – some ex-executive started a winery, and now you can drink it here.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s also a pretty good spot to grab a glass of wine to go. This is especially handy before the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_of_Color">World of Color</a> show. Seen below is us with our to-go cups of wine.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/disney/june15/alfresco-wine-to-go.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/alfresco-wine-to-go.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Booze you can take with you = the best</div>
</div>


<p>Our next stop was more fruitful: the Carthay Circle lounge. It gets busy after around 5pm, and the lounge is first-come-first-served, so make sure you get a seat. The drinks were good, and decently priced ($10-12 each). Because of the Disneyland 60th anniversary, they&rsquo;re putting diamond-shaped cubes in every drink (including Martinis and Manhattans), so if you want your drink unsullied, make sure to mention it.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/disney/june15/carthay-circle-lounge.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/carthay-circle-lounge.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Carthay Circle Lounge</div>
</div>


<p>They didn&rsquo;t just have standard cocktails, either. They had some crème de violette/tequila thing that came with a candied flower on it. It tasted great!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/disney/june15/carthay-violet.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/carthay-violet.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Violet cocktail from Carthay Circle</div>
</div>


<p>We headed over to The Cove, which is by the Paradise Pier area of the park. Like the Carthay Circle lounge, this place gets really busy, so come early. It&rsquo;s a lot of fun people-watching and sitting outside (if you can take a little sun). I was pleasantly surprised that the discontinued cocktail menu from the Alfresco Terrace was now over here! So I had my favourite drink from that – the Smoked Turkey.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/disney/june15/the-cove.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/the-cove.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The Cove bar – Smoked Turkey and a Manhattan</div>
</div>


<p>(Oh, you should also get the lobster nachos while you&rsquo;re there. Deeeelicious.)</p>

<p>After we&rsquo;d exhausted Disney California Adventure, we went to our favourite bar at the resort – Trader Sam&rsquo;s Enchanted Tiki Bar. It&rsquo;s located by the pool at the Disneyland Hotel. It&rsquo;s a bit of a trek from the parks (about 10-15mins walk through Downtown Disney), but we enjoy it. Here&rsquo;s the entrance:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-entrance.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-entrance.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Entrance to Trader Sam&#8217;s Enchanted Tiki Bar</div>
</div>


<p>There&rsquo;s a doorman – like every other bar, this one gets really busy. The doorman had implemented a one-in-one-out policy.</p>

<p>Inside, it&rsquo;s filled with trinkets and tchotchkes over the walls. Every surface is covered in this stuff, and it&rsquo;s really interesting to read/look at. Like everything at Disney theme parks, there&rsquo;s a back-story to every item. Nothing is just put up without thorough thought. There are letters from people Trader Sam has met on adventures. There&rsquo;s things people have mailed. It&rsquo;s quite incredible.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-indoor.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-indoor.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside Trader Sam&#8217;s</div>
</div>


<p>The drink menu has a standard tiki-theme – mostly rums and fruit juices. Most of the drinks have ridiculous names (&ldquo;Tiki Tiki Tiki Tiki Tiki Rum,&rdquo; for example).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/disney/june15/trader-sams1.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/trader-sams1.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">HippopotoMai-Tai and a Lost Safari</div>
</div>


<p>The Mai Tai was fine, but nothing special. The Lost Safari was really good, though.</p>

<p>For our next round, I ordered the Krakatoa Punch. It came with a glowing &ldquo;ice-cube&rdquo; in it. When I ordered it, the bar lights went low. Through one of the trompe l&#8217;oiel &ldquo;windows&rdquo;, a volcano erupted in a neat little display.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-krakatoa.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-krakatoa.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Krakatoa Punch</div>
</div>


<p>In fact, these things happen for a number of drinks. Every 15 minutes or so, you&rsquo;ll be interrupted. The Shipwrek on the Rocks causes a ship in a painting behind the bar to sink. Plus the bartender sprays you with water.</p>

<p>Our final drink was the Uh Oa. It&rsquo;s a sharing drink, and arrives with a flaming sugar cube. You throw cinnamon and nutmeg onto the flames, creating sparks, while the whole bar erupts in chants of &ldquo;Uh oa! Uh oa!&rdquo;</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-uh-oa.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-uh-oa.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Uh Oa!</div>
</div>


<p>Trader Sam&rsquo;s is entertaining. It&rsquo;s exactly how you&rsquo;d imagine Disney would want a bar to be – adults can get the sense of fun and magic that is often left only to kids.</p>

<p>That was our drinking experience at Disneyland Resort. When we&rsquo;re next down at Walt Disney World, I&rsquo;ll try to do a similar thing for those parks, too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
