<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Czech-republic | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/czech-republic/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-22T15:55:26+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zinc Lounge, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/21/zinc-lounge-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-21T11:52:10+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/21/zinc-lounge-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>After the underwhelming experience at <a href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/19/cloud-9-prague">Cloud 9</a>, I wanted to try out the bar at the other Prague-based Hilton: <a href="http://www.hiltonpragueoldtown.com/loungebar-en.html"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Zinc Lounge and Bar</span></a>, found in the <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Hilton+Prague+Old+Town/@50.088515,14.431864,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x63a407a250359dc7">Hilton Prague Old Town</a>. I wanted to see how it measured up, and in short: it was pretty bad. Please forgive me, Cloud 9, I didn't realise your sister bar was so awful. I would have cut you some slack otherwise!</p>

  <p>The Hilton Prague Old Town is pretty easy to find compared with the other Hilton. It's just off Náměstí Republiky, one of the main squares in the Old Town. The Zinc Bar and Lounge is just to the right as you come in. "Zinc" is also the name of the hotel restaurant, just behind the bar</p>

  <p>Inside, it's decorated like a dreary hotel lobby. Leather seats and low, round wooden tables. Holey partitions of wood try to separate the actual hotel lobby from the bar. Despite their best efforts, we were still drinking around a bunch of people loudly chatting on Skype (I assume there's free wi-fi in the lobby area) and wheeling their luggage around, waiting for their ride to the airport.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-bar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-bar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Zinc Bar</div>
  </div>

  <p>The menu consisted almost entirely of classic cocktails. There was nothing inventive or fancy like at Cloud 9. We stuck to our staples and got a gimlet and a manhattan. They were both OK – competently done and similar to what you could find at a lot of bars in Prague.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-cocktails.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-cocktails.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Drinks: gimlet and a manhattan</div>
  </div>

  <p>The thing is, these cocktails were 220Kč (~$11) each. And there was me going off on how expensive the Cloud 9 cocktails were, at 185Kč (~$9)! Like I said in the beginning, I'M SORRY CLOUD 9. The Cloud 9 cocktails were far more reasonably-priced (I still think they're expensive, though). At least you get something different, innovative. At Zinc you get a standard cocktail that at another bar (say, Groove Bar) would be 100Kč (~$5).</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-interior.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-interior.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Hampton looking SUPREMELY DISAPPOINTED</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Put together the atmosphere of the hotel lobby with the fact that the drinks were exceedinly expensive for what they were, and you get a disappointing experience. I'd suggest venturing a little out of the hotel to find a better cocktail bar.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">4.6</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud 9, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/19/cloud-9-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-19T11:39:32+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/19/cloud-9-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.cloud9.cz/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Cloud 9</span></a> (or, in full, Cloud 9 Sky Bar & Lounge) is located in the <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/preview?safe=off&ie=UTF-8&fb=1&cid=4324379790027078551&q=Hilton+Prague+Hotel&ei=BVnGU-X9E-aV7Ab6loCQDQ&ved=0CMQBEPwSMAo">Hilton</a>, just east of the central Old Town district of Prague. It's got pretty good reviews, most extolling the views over Prague. So, of course we had to go.</p>

  <p>Firstly: getting to the Hilton is surprisingly tricky. (<strong>NB</strong>: there are two Hiltons in Prague, the more central <a href="http://d1pa4et5htdsls.cloudfront.net/images/vfml/1/1/2/9/6/1/5/709926e0_prgothi_74095_s-original.jpg">Hilton Prague Old Town</a> and the <a href="http://www.hotels-in-czech.com/clfiles/photos/big/29-hilton-budova.jpg">Hilton Prague</a>. This is in the latter.) It's strange how much Prague changes between the first and eighth districts. It quickly goes from windy cobblestone streets to broad roads and unfriendly pedestrian crossings. The Hilton itself takes up a whole square block, yet finding the right route to get there – even finding the right entrance to use – was confusing. We just about managed by following the tourists forming a trail on their way to the Old Town.</p>

  <p>Once you've found your way in (use the west entrance to the Hilton, and take a sharp right for the lift to the ninth floor), the views are the first thing that strike you. It was early evening as we came in, and the sun slowly setting gave some nice cloud patterns. However, I guess I was expecting more of a grand view of the <em>centre</em> of Prague. Instead, you get a beautiful view of the Allianz building next door.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-west.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-west.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The view west, towards the centre of Prague</div>
  </div>

  <p>I suppose I'm being a little harsh – you can just see the top of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_of_Our_Lady_before_T%C3%BDn">Church of Our Lady before Týn</a> on the left. </p>
  
  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-tyn.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-tyn.png">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">I found <span class="strike">Wally</span> the Church!</div>
  </div>

  <p>The north and east views are nicer – but more pastoral than the gothic spires I was imagining.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-north.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/view-north.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The view north</div>
  </div>

  <p>The bar itself was decorated like a hotel bar. Clean lines, mirrors everywhere, leather-backed chairs. They had a couple of outside seating areas, but these were filled up with hotel guests.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/bar-interior.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/bar-interior.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Interior of the bar.</div>
  </div>

  <p>Speaking of the clientele, I wasn't too surprised to find it filled with tourists. It was early (7pm), the bar is tricky to find, and it's a <em>hotel bar</em>, so you're not going to get an authentic Czech experience. Even so, the groups of English/North American tourists asking the waitress to pronounce "Na zdraví!" ("Cheers!") over and over was grating. But onto the cocktails!</p>

  <p>The menu was interesting, and had a good mix of classics plus some that had been made up in the bar. Their inventions all had new-agey, etherial names like SUNSHINE and MYSTIC and DESIRE. Their most famous cocktail (according to them, at least) is the CHARISMA.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Charisma</div>
  </div>

  <p>The Charisma is so famous that it has intricate instructions for drinking.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma-instructions.jpg">
      </a><img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma-instructions
      .jpg">
    <div class="alt">Instructions for drinking</div>
  </div>

  <p>Despite that, you still look like a wally drinking something with a giant chili pepper sticking out of it.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma-drinking.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/charisma-drinking.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Looking suave</div>
  </div>

  <p>My drinks weren't nearly as exciting. They didn't even have instructions on how to drink them. Sad times.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/mystic.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/mystic.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Mystic</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/desire.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/desire.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Desire (the thumbs up is for size reference, not endorsement)</div>
  </div>

  <p>The Mystic was a vodka-ginger-lime-sugar thing and was delicious. The Desire, on the other hand, tasted like what I imagine pot pourri tastes like (i.e. gross).</p>

  <p>The bar snacks were delicious. We never really found out what they were, due to the language barrier, but it seemed to be some kind of caramel-coated peanut in a crispy shell dusted in salt and dried tomato (? maybe). We scarfed them down in about five minutes.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/bar-snack.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cloud9/bar-snack.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Bar snacks</div>
  </div>

  <p>The prices were pretty crazy. I'm not sure if it's because it's in a hotel or because it has views (probably a little of both), it ran to about 185Kč (~$9) a drink. That may not sound like much, but they were easily the priciest cocktails we've had in Prague and the previous holder of that title was around 145Kč (~$7).</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">For a hotel bar, Cloud 9 is pretty decent. You have good views of Prague and some tasty cocktails. The hassle of finding it plus the prices mean it's not really worthwhile to go unless you're staying at the Hilton.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">6.3</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

  <p><strong>UPDATE</strong>: I went to the bar in the other Hilton and turns out, it was <a href="">way worse</a>.</p>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bugsy's Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/17/bugsys-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-17T10:37:25+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/17/bugsys-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">
  <p>We moved to a (slightly) different area of Prague the other day. I was pretty excited because hey, there'll be a whole new bunch of cocktail bars to go to! Looking online, it seemed like <a href="http://www.bugsysbar.cz/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Bugsy's Bar</span></a> is one of the nicer cocktail bars in Prague. If you like <a href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/20/hemingway-bar-prague">Hemmingway</a>, Foursquare said, you'd like Bugsy's. Their website is very slick – look how dapper the bartenders are, with their bow-ties and braces! Anyway, we gave it a shot. We weaved our way through old town street, went past a scary bouncer and down into a basement where the only lighting seemed to come from neon-pink spotlights pointed at the ceiling.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-interior.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-interior.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Inside Bugsy's</div>
  </div>

  <p>The crowd was... strange. Everyone was dressed as if they were in a club. Short skirts and heels for women, blazers and super-shiny shoes for the guys. When we walked out later that evening, we realised we must be in the "club" district, as every other doorway had a bouncer and a line of people waiting to get in. Maybe Bugsy's is more of a pre-club venue?</p>

  <p>When we sat down, we were presented with one of the most amazing drink menus I've seen. It's a thick book designed as a graphic novel. The cocktails are split into broad categories, and each category has a beautiful double-page spread listing out the cocktails followed by a few pages of a story. We follow a single character through a noir scene (for classic cocktails), a Caribbean adventure (for rum cocktails), a scene with Batman (for "Gotham Cocktails," whatever they are), and so on. There was even a page for mocktails where our hero ended up being pulled over and passing a breathalyser test.</p>

  <p>Anyway, the *range* of cocktails (despite the menu) was pretty disappointing. Nearly all were either classics, or vague variations on rum cocktails. I got a gin fizz and Hampton a vesper.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-vesper.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-vesper.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Vesper</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-ginfizz.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-ginfizz.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Gin fizz. It came with a bunch of... flowers? Berries? Something on top.</div>
  </div>

  <p>For a bar snack, the server gave us this shot-glass of things that looked like undercooked chips. Turns out they were some kind of string-cheese that had been rolled in spices or something? It was super-weird.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-cheese.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-cheese.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Weird cheese</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Overall, I was pretty disappointed, to be honest. That plus my confusion (or their confusion) of what the bar <em>was</em>. The cocktails were pretty high-end, and not cheap – which suggests an upscale bar. Yet mix that with the disco soundtrack, weird pink lighting everywhere, and about-to-go-clubbing crowd and I didn't really want to spend a lot of time there.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">3.4</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black Angel's Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/17/black-angels-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-17T10:35:09+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/17/black-angels-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">
  <p><a href="http://www.blackangelsbar.cz/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Black Angel's Bar</span></a> was recomended to us by a number of people – both bartenders and general cocktail-lovers. It's in a basement just off the old town square, underneath a hotel. As we were taken down to the bar, we were warned about a long list of "no nos": no cameras, no hats, no speaking too loud. It was a weird way to be introduced to a bar.</p>

  <p>The cocktails were inventive and presented well. They had a broad menu – a bunch of famous bartenders (I can't vouch for their renown as I hadn't heard of any of them. Saying that, I don't know if I <em>could</em> name a famous bartender.) came up with a list of drinks. There's a lot of award-winning cocktails in there too. I had a couple of pre-prohibition ones, which were delicious.

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Despite the cocktails being great, there was something a little off about the place. I'm not sure if it was the number of tourists (it is just off the main square, after all) or the man at the piano playing the theme song to Forrest Gump (?!), but it wasn't as enjoyable of an experience as I thought it would be.</span></p>

  <p>Oh, and watch out for the bathrooms. They charge for their use for non-customers. I got confused and paid the person, but turns out that wasn't necessary. (There was a sign saying "No charge for guests," but I assumed they meant guests of the hotel.)</p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">6.8</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sansho, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/15/sansho-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-15T13:25:28+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/15/sansho-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>We asked for recommendations for the best retaurant in Prague and were told that <a href="http://www.sansho.cz/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Sansho</span></a> was the place to go. Most of the places I found online described it as Czech-Asian fusion, which sounded too weird to pass up. Plus, it was our <a href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/26/the-anniversary-question">third first-year anniversary</a> so we decided to book a table.</p>

  <p>It's in the north of the Old Town, on a <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Sansho/@50.091722,14.43483,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0xe3da7dc930221279">beautiful square</a> right next to this amazing church.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/church.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/church.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Church outside – notice the creepy bird installation on the tower</div>
  </div>

  <p>Apparently you can eat outside during the daytime, but it was a little chilly so we ate in. The interior was pretty sparse, and reminded me of <a href="http://www.suppenkuche.com/">Suppenküche</a> in San Francisco. There were long tables with benches for mixed group dining, as well as a couple of individual tables. The servers could have been from San Francisco, too. They were all in plaid shirts and may have just wandered in off Valencia Street.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/restaurant.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/restaurant.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Interior of the restaurant</div>
  </div>

  <p>For dinner, the only option you have is the set menu, which is fine by us. I love not having to decide what I'm going to eat. Each course came for the two of us to share. The set menu changes every night. What's weird was that other tables didn't get the same set menu that we did – some had the same dishes in a different order, some had a much different menu. It didn't seem to be dictated by any dietary requirements, so I can't quite figure it out. Anyway, onto the food.</p>

  <p>The first two courses were fish. There was a salmon sashimi, which was kinda standard. Then there was a soft-shell crab slider. It was really good. The bun had a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cha_siu_bao">steamed bun</a> texture which went great with the crispy crab. There was a little too much wasabi on it for my taste, but whatever.</p> 

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/salmon.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/salmon.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">One: Salmon sashimi with soy and red peppercorns</div>
  </div>
  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/crab.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/crab.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Two: Soft-shell crab slider with wasabi cream (what's up with the doily, amirite?)</div>
  </div>

  <p>Then there was a salad course: asparagus with ginger dressing and a crispy egg. I didn't get the egg bit, but the asparagus with ginger was great. I don't think I've ever had asparagus with more Asian-inspired flavours before. I guess this was the only thing that I could identify as really Czech-Asian fusion. Following the salad there were some gyoza, which were tasty but nothing special. (Don't get me wrong, I love gyoza, but they're like crème brûlée to me: if you're competent enough to make it, it's gonna be delicious.)</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/asparagus.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/asparagus.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Three: Asparagus and ginger salad with a crispy egg</div>
  </div>
  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/gyoza.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/gyoza.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Four: Pork and shrimp gyoza </div>
  </div>

  <p>Next up were my favourite two dishes. First there was a tender pork belly with chunks of watermelon. The pork belly had a sticky, sweet sauce on the outside which melted perfectly with the watermelon. Then there was a panang-style curry with some chili jam. It was served with some bread, sticky rice and a papaya salad. The curry had a strange texture, and the server explained that it was made up of "everything else from the pig."</p>

  <p>Apparently the restaurant is a "whole animal" restaurant. There was a chalk-board sign out front explaining this. Up until this point of the meal – aside from the whole crab slider – there wasn't much evidence of the "whole animal" philosophy. But I guess getting a curry with "everything else" in it counts.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/pork.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/pork.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Five: Pork belly with watermelon</div>
  </div>
  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/panang.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/panang.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Six: Pork panang with chili jam</div>
  </div>

  <p>Here's another thing I'm a sucker for: dessert taster plates. I can never decide if I should get the sticky toffee pudding (it might be too heavy!) or the sorbet (it's such a dull option!) or the apple pie (it might be too bland!). Every restaurant should have a dessert taster plate so I can eat all the desserts without feeling guilty.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/dessert.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/dessert.jpg">
    </a> 
    <div class="alt">Seven: Cookie with peanut ice-cream; cheesecake; sticky toffee pudding</div>
  </div>

  <p>The sticky toffee pudding was the favourite, but the cookie/peanut ice-cream came a close second.</p>

  <p>The seven courses and came out at about 1000Kč (~$50) per person, so pretty pricey for Prague. Plus they did this thing that I've noticed a lot of restaurants do here, which is give you something without you asking, then charge you for it. It's happened with bread and jugs of water a bunch of times. I kind of assume that if something's placed down on the table and I haven't specifically asked for it, it's going to be free. I don't know if this is just a traditional thing or what, but I haven't noticed it elsewhere in Europe really.</p>

  <p>All in all, <span itemprop="summary">Sansho is a great place for a special meal, with some inventive twists on Asian cuisine.</span> If you're here for a special occasion and want something a little out of the ordinary, I'd recommend it. Just make sure you're prepared for the bill.</p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">7.8</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
