<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Czech-republic | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/czech-republic/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-14T17:47:11-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AnonymouS Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/30/anonymous-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-30T04:10:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/30/anonymous-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>Our time in Prague is almost at an end – today, we&#8217;re taking a flight to Amsterdam. We saved an intriguing bar for our last new experience in the cocktail world of Prague. <a href="http://www.anonymousbar.cz/cs"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">AnonymouS Bar</span></a> (their weird capitalisation, not mine) is off a small alley in the old town, and it is themed around the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gunpowder_Plot">gunpowder plot</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/V_for_Vendetta">V for Vendetta</a>, and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anonymous_(group)">Anonymous</a> movement.</p>

  <p>Inside, the bar is styled like the interior of V&#8217;s hideout in the comic book/film. It allows the use of comfortable chairs, but also brick-showing-through-plaster murals and classic portraits with faces replaced by the Guy Fawkes mask. It kind of reminded us (in the best way possible, as we&#8217;re theme park nerds) of a Universal Studios or Disney experience.</p>

  <p>The menu has a really great concept: a list of standard drinks on one page, paired up with an AnonymouS-bar twist on the classics. It was a goodway to quickly pick out a drink you&#8217;d be sure to like. I went for the St Marry&#8217;s Virus – again, that&#8217;s their weird spelling, and I&#8217;m not sure if it&#8217;s deliberate or not. It was a twist on the Piccadilly martini. The bartender came over with a biohazard box, which opened to reveal a giant syringe containing the cocktial.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-st-marrys.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-st-marrys.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">St Marry&#8217;s Virus</div>
  </div>

  <p>Hampton went for a take on a gimlet, and it was really delicious! I think they added cucumber and some other stuff.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-butterfly.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-butterfly.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">M. Butterfly</div>
  </div>

  <p>The menu, aside from the drink and liquor list, was pretty entertaining. They had neat explanation of their thought process behind the concept. As I was flicking through, I noticed there was a cocktail set apart from the rest, alone on the very first page. It didn&#8217;t have a description, aside from the old rhyme: &#8220;Remember, remember the fifth of November&#8230;&#8221; It was too puzzling not to get.</p>

  <p>Hampton got it after me, so I have photos of what it entailed. The bartender handed you a Guy Fawkes mask and took your photo.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-photo.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-photo.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">They had to find more film</div>
  </div>

  <p>After that, they make the drink. It involved lining a brandy snifter with liquor and setting it on fire. Once the fire had died down, they poured in a whisky-based old-fashioned-esque cocktail. They placed the photo on top to stop the smoke from the flames coming out.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-remember.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-remember.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Remember</div>
  </div>

  <p>Here are the photos of our night. It&#8217;s nice to have something to keep after a night out. Especially once you&#8217;ve had a few cocktails.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-polaroid.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-polaroid.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Ahh, memories!</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">The themeing theatricality of AnonymouS bar is great, but it&#8217;s really backed up by the delicious cocktails on offer.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">8.5</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[La Degustation]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/27/la-degustation/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-27T05:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/27/la-degustation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.ladegustation.cz/en/#index"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">La Degustation</span></a>, one of two restaurants in Prague to have <a href="http://www.viamichelin.com/web/Restaurants/Restaurants-Prague-_-Praha_hlavni_mesto-Czech_Republic?strLocid=31MzhkeDEwY05UQXVNRGczT0RFPWNNVFF1TkRJd05EWT0=">a Michelin star</a>, was our special treat as our time in Prague is coming to an end. Its slogan is &#8220;bohême bourgeoise,&#8221; which I found amusing.</p>

  <p>Inside, I don&#8217;t know if anything can be gothic minimalist, but I think that&#8217;s an accurate description. Arches ribbed the ceiling, and artfully-placed dim spotlights created wonderful shadows. The walls were bare and painted a light grey, and the furniture was all low-backed and dark wood. The windows onto the street had the restaurant&#8217;s signature checkered pattern.</p>

  <p>As we sat down, the waiter came over and gave us an envelope.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/envelope.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/envelope.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">We were handed an envelope</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/back-envelope.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/back-envelope.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The back of the envelope</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/contents.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/contents.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Open it to find the checkered pattern</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/menu.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/menu.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Two menu options</div>
  </div>

  <p>We went for the eleven-course menu, with wine pairings. It was definitely a lot of food, and I wish I hadn&#8217;t eaten so much of the delicious bread they brought. The menu focussed on Czech ingredients and dishes, but with modern, vaguely molecular-gastronomic twists. Apparently a lot of the inspiration for their dishes comes from a late-19th century Czech cookbook.</p>

  <p>I didn&#8217;t take pictures and I won&#8217;t bore you with a course-by-course detailing of everything. A couple of stand-out dishes, though: dijon mustard ice-cream with hot tomato sauce. The sauce was the perfect distillation of tomato flavour. Add that to the mustard (which wasn&#8217;t too spicy), plus the mixing of the hot sauce with the cold ice-cream and you get an incredible dish that&#8217;s not quite like anything I&#8217;ve had before.</p>

  <p>There was a foie gras course where the liver had been finely grated over wine jelly and pistachio. I&#8217;d never eaten foie gras grated before, and it really helped take away the heaviness you sometimes get. Then there was the beef tongue &#8220;signature dish.&#8221; </p>

  <p>I really enjoyed the wine pairings. They used mostly Czech wines, and it was nice to see the variety in types they produce here. There was also a great unfiltered Slovenian wine called <a href="http://www.scurek.com/www/index.php/en/wines/white-wines">Kontra</a>. The cheese course came with a delicious IPA from the <a href="http://www.beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/23493/">Matuška Brewery</a>.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">If you&#8217;re willing to splash out, this place is definitely worth it. It&#8217;s a modern take on Czech flavours and ingredients, and the courses are presented beautifully.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">9.3</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Touring the Jewish Quarter of Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/25/jewish-quarter-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-25T06:58:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/25/jewish-quarter-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Josefov">Jewish Quarter</a> (or Josefov) of Prague is in the Old Town, just north of the Old Town Square. We&rsquo;d been told that the <a href="http://www.jewishmuseum.cz/en/apinkas.htm">Pinkas Synagogue</a> was a must-see, so we set off on a visit without learning much about it. All I knew was that it&rsquo;s now a memorial to victims of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Holocaust">Holocaust</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Pinkas Synagogue from the outside</div>
</div>


<p>We arrived at lunchtime and the queue was really long and slow-moving. Not good.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-queue.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-queue.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Long queue waiting for tickets</div>
</div>


<p>However! We found an EXPERT WORK-AROUND for buying tickets without having to wait in line. Head slightly east on the same road and take the first left. You&rsquo;ll find <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Maiselova+38%2F15,+110+00+Praha-Praha+1,+Czech+Republic/@50.089592,14.4181715,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x470b94e8669ff2a5:0xb73abb80fc435169">a ticketing office</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ticket-office.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ticket-office.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Just around the corner – under 2 mins walk.</div>
</div>


<p>There was no queue and we got our tickets immediately. You can&rsquo;t buy a single ticket to see the synagogues/museums of Josefov individually – you have to buy a multi-attraction ticket. The most basic ticket was 300Kč (~$15) for four attractions: the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Jewish_Cemetery,_Prague">Old Jewish Cemetery</a>, the <a href="http://www.jewishmuseum.cz/en/aklaus.htm">Klausen Synagogue</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jewish_Ceremonial_Hall,_Prague">Ceremonial Hall</a>, and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_Synagogue_(Prague)">Spanish Synagogue</a>. You could pay 100Kč more if you wanted to see the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_New_Synagogue,_Prague">Old New Synagogue</a>, but we gave that one a miss. The ticket is valid over seven days, though, which is good if you don&rsquo;t have enough time to visit all the places in one day.</p>

<p>After we bought our tickets we went back to the Pinkas Synagogue and sailed past the line there to buy tickets.</p>

<p>The inside of the Pinkas Synagogue serves as a memorial to the 80,000 Bohemian and Moravian Jews that were victims of the Holocaust.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-room.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-room.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside the synagogue</div>
</div>


<p>There were about five rooms like the one above – and see those red and black, floor-to-ceiling patches that line the walls? Those are the victims&#8217; names, birth-dates and death-dates. Across the rooms they&rsquo;re written out like that, in letters maybe a centimetre high.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-names.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-names.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Names, births and deaths of victims</div>
</div>


<p>At first, you don&rsquo;t quite understand it. Then as you start reading, seeing the families grouped together, it&rsquo;s a little overwhelming. Especially when you see room after room of them. It was powerful stuff, and something I&rsquo;d recommend everyone do while they&rsquo;re in Prague.</p>

<p>After exiting the synagogue, you walk through the Old Jewish Cemetery. While not that large geographically, it apparently contains over 12,000 tombstones.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Old Jewish Cemetery</div>
</div>


<p>Needless to say, it was crowded with graves. The tombstones stuck out at all kinds of angles, and many were only just sticking out of the soil.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery2.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery2.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Another view of the cemetery</div>
</div>


<p>The cemetary exit leaves you just outside of Ceremonial Hall and the Klausen Synagogue. As we already had the multi-ticket, we decided to give them a visit.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Ceremonial Hall outside</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall-floor.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall-floor.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Ceremonial Hall tiled floor</div>
</div>


<p>The Ceremonial Hall used to be a kind of mortuary, so had a bunch of exhibits on the rituals surrounding death in Judaism. It was kind of interesting, but mostly just items in display cases.</p>

<p>The Klausen Synagogue was similar. Apart from the Pinkas Synagogue earlier on, I&rsquo;d never been inside a synagogue before. I&rsquo;m not quite sure what I was expecting from the inside of a synagogue, but I was kind of disappointed that it looked just like a Christian church.</p>

<p>Inside the main area of the Klausen Synagogue, there were display cases showing items relating to Judaism. I found it a little strange. I almost wanted the museum part and the religious-building part to be more separate. Maybe it&rsquo;s just because I wasn&rsquo;t expecting it to be so much of a museum.</p>

<p>After leaving the Klausen Synagogue, the route to the next stop on our ticket took us past the Old New Synagogue. I only learnt afterwards that it&rsquo;s Europe&rsquo;s oldest active synagogue. Apparently, its attic is also the storage place for the infamous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golem#The_classic_narrative:_The_Golem_of_Prague">Golem of Prague</a> (<em>spooky noises</em>).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/old-new.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/old-new.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Old New Synagogue</div>
</div>


<p>We continued walking, made a couple of quick turns, and found ourselves at the Spanish Synagogue. Not much to look at from the outside, inside it&rsquo;s absolutely stunning.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Spanish Synagogue interior</div>
</div>


<p>The walls are covered in intricate patterns, mostly using reds and golds. The Star of David appears in motifs everywhere, and I spent ages just following the patterns and their interplay across the walls. The central dome is beautiful and has a Star of David-shaped chandelier in the centre.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish-dome.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish-dome.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Dome of the Spanish Synagogue</div>
</div>


<p>Fun fact: it doesn&rsquo;t seem to be clear why it&rsquo;s called the Spanish Synagogue. One theory is that the interior design reminded people of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golden_age_of_Jewish_culture_in_Spain">&ldquo;Golden Age&rdquo;</a> of Judaism in Spain. Another theory is that it used to be a location for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romaniotes">Byzantine Jewish</a> worship, and that led to legends of the Iberian <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sephardi_Jews">Sephardi Jews</a> once worshipping there.</p>

<p>Like the Klausen Synagogue, the Spanish Synagogue is a museum as well as a religious building. I was mostly distracted by the detailing on the walls, but I did look at a couple of the display cases in the upper balconies. They were pretty interesting, detailing the history of Josefov across the centuries. If it hadn&rsquo;t been over 30ºC in there, I would have stayed longer.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m glad we ended up seeing more of the Jewish Quarter than just the Pinkas Synagogue, but I&rsquo;m not sure I&rsquo;d see the Klausen Synagogu and the Ceremonial Hall if I were pushed for time. I definitely found it more rewarding than most of Prague Castle, though. I made a <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/dir/Maiselova+38%2F15,+110+00+Praha,+Czech+Republic/Pinkas+Synagogue,+%C5%A0irok%C3%A1+23%2F3,+110+00+Praha,+Czech+Republic/Klausov%C3%A1+synagoga,+U+star%C3%A9ho+h%C5%99bitova+3a,+110+00+Praha-Josefov,+Czech+Republic/The+Old-New+Synagogue,+Maiselova+18,+110+01+Praha+1,+Czech+Republic/50.0900973,14.4211259/@50.090032,14.4178231,18z/data=!4m32!4m31!1m5!1m1!1s0x470b94e8669ff2a5:0xb73abb80fc435169!2m2!1d14.4181715!2d50.089592!1m5!1m1!1s0x470b94e85e9af185:0x294f2ae19539722d!2m2!1d14.416972!2d50.089277!1m5!1m1!1s0x470b94e877e558db:0xdd1a2cc59bf35380!2m2!1d14.417069!2d50.09002!1m10!1m1!1s0x470b94e868e5c8c9:0x94be0e2fdb884bfa!2m2!1d14.418567!2d50.090051!3m4!1m2!1d14.4190562!2d50.0899754!3s0x470b94e844b3b4d3:0x32c184f0e15a1660!1m0!3e2">map of the route we took</a> – but note that the bit from the Pinkas to Klausen is through the cemetery rather than around Maiselova.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orange Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/orange-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-23T04:33:48-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/orange-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.orangebar.cz/en/homepage.html"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Orange Bar</span></a> is pretty close by to us and has decent reviews. It&#8217;s a little tricky to find, down a couple of side-streets, but there&#8217;s a nice orange-shaped sign outside to let you know when you&#8217;re there.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/outside.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/outside.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">From the street</div>
  </div>

  <p>From the outside, it looks pretty normal, right? Inside, though, it reminded me of a bar in Dune or something. The only lights had orange filters, and all the walls were molded to give the appearance of being dug out of a cave.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/bar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/bar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The bar (I think the spice is kept on the top shelf)</div>
  </div>

  <p>The bar shelves were all integrated into the back wall. The other walls had fake columns with cubbies for desert plants.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/plants.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/plants.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Walls with plants</div>
  </div>

  <p>The cocktail list leaned heavily towards rum-based beach drinks – mai tais, piña coladas, zombies etc. There&#8217;s also a good list of classics, too. Hampton went for (of course) a manhattan. I tried out the mai tai but it was a little too sweet for me.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/cocktails.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/cocktails.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Manhattan and a mai tai</div>
  </div>

  <p>We were there during a massive thunderstorm and didn&#8217;t have umbrellas, so we stayed for another round (or two). The moscow mule was <em>much</em> better. Get that! It had a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physalis_peruviana">physalis</a> garnish too, which is awesome.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/moscow-mule.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/moscow-mule.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Moscow mule</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Orange bar has a neighbourhood feel and a fun theme. The drinks are sweet, but tasty, so I&#8217;d stick to non-tiki drinks (unless you&#8217;re a particular fan).</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">7.1</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hoffa, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/hoffa-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-23T04:32:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/hoffa-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>For some reason, there&#8217;s a bar in Prague named after <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jimmy_Hoffa">Jimmy Hoffa</a>, the American union leader who went missing in the 70s. Unfortunately, my lack of Czech skills (and poor Google translating) don&#8217;t help much with the &#8220;About&#8221; page on the <a href="http://hoffa.cz"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Hoffa</span></a> website.</p>

  <p>First and foremost: this is a non-smoking bar! Yay! That automatically gets you points in my book. Most bars have smoking and non-smoking areas, but that&#8217;s not quite the same. Location-wise, it&#8217;s on a little intersection near the main train station (so great for people-watching), and has big windows. The decor is neat – they have a massive trompe-l&#8217;œil mural on one side so it looks like you&#8217;re in a warehouse.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-mural.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-mural.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Mural in Hoffa</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-bar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-bar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The bar</div>
  </div>

  <p>They have mostly traditional drinks, with some specials on a chalkboard. The drink I had was pretty good, but nothing amazing. I went for a glass of Pimm&#8217;s as it was ridiculously hot outside.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-pimms.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-pimms.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Pimm&#8217;s!</div>
  </div>

  <p>They offer decent bar snacks, too. We got some tortilla chips with salsa and sour cream.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-tortillas.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-tortillas.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Tortilla chips with salsa and sour cream</div>
  </div>

  <p>We also got some hamburgers, which were amazing. They were juicy, cooked medium-rare, and had spicy-sweet secret sauce on them. Delicious!</p>

  <p>The bathroom doors were pretty neat, too.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-mural.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-bathroom.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Bathroom door</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">I can see us returning to this place for its relaxed atmosphere, neat interior, and reasonably-priced decent drinks. It seemed like a nice place to call your local.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">7.0</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
