<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Czech-republic | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/czech-republic/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-17T10:42:00+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bugsy's Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/17/bugsys-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-17T10:37:25+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/17/bugsys-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">
  <p>We moved to a (slightly) different area of Prague the other day. I was pretty excited because hey, there'll be a whole new bunch of cocktail bars to go to! Looking online, it seemed like <a href="http://www.bugsysbar.cz/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Bugsy's Bar</span></a> is one of the nicer cocktail bars in Prague. If you like <a href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/20/hemingway-bar-prague">Hemmingway</a>, Foursquare said, you'd like Bugsy's. Their website is very slick – look how dapper the bartenders are, with their bow-ties and braces! Anyway, we gave it a shot. We weaved our way through old town street, went past a scary bouncer and down into a basement where the only lighting seemed to come from neon-pink spotlights pointed at the ceiling.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-interior.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Inside Bugsy's</div>
  </div>

  <p>The crowd was... strange. Everyone was dressed as if they were in a club. Short skirts and heels for women, blazers and super-shiny shoes for the guys. When we walked out later that evening, we realised we must be in the "club" district, as every other doorway had a bouncer and a line of people waiting to get in. Maybe Bugsy's is more of a pre-club venue?</p>

  <p>When we sat down, we were presented with one of the most amazing drink menus I've seen. It's a thick book designed as a graphic novel. The cocktails are split into broad categories, and each category has a beautiful double-page spread listing out the cocktails followed by a few pages of a story. We follow a single character through a noir scene (for classic cocktails), a Caribbean adventure (for rum cocktails), a scene with Batman (for "Gotham Cocktails," whatever they are), and so on. There was even a page for mocktails where our hero ended up being pulled over and passing a breathalyser test.</p>

  <p>Anyway, the *range* of cocktails (despite the menu) was pretty disappointing. Nearly all were either classics, or vague variations on rum cocktails. I got a gin fizz and Hampton a vesper.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-vesper.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Vesper</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-ginfizz.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Gin fizz. It came with a bunch of... flowers? Berries? Something on top.</div>
  </div>

  <p>For a bar snack, the server gave us this shot-glass of things that looked like undercooked chips. Turns out they were some kind of string-cheese that had been rolled in spices or something? It was super-weird.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/bugsys-cheese.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Weird cheese</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Overall, I was pretty disappointed, to be honest. That plus my confusion (or their confusion) of what the bar <em>was</em>. The cocktails were pretty high-end, and not cheap – which suggests an upscale bar. Yet mix that with the disco soundtrack, weird pink lighting everywhere, and about-to-go-clubbing crowd and I didn't really want to spend a lot of time there.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">3.4</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black Angel's Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/17/black-angels-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-17T10:35:09+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/17/black-angels-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">
  <p><a href="http://www.blackangelsbar.cz/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Black Angel's Bar</span></a> was recomended to us by a number of people – both bartenders and general cocktail-lovers. It's in a basement just off the old town square, underneath a hotel. As we were taken down to the bar, we were warned about a long list of "no nos": no cameras, no hats, no speaking too loud. It was a weird way to be introduced to a bar.</p>

  <p>The cocktails were inventive and presented well. They had a broad menu – a bunch of famous bartenders (I can't vouch for their renown as I hadn't heard of any of them. Saying that, I don't know if I <em>could</em> name a famous bartender.) came up with a list of drinks. There's a lot of award-winning cocktails in there too. I had a couple of pre-prohibition ones, which were delicious.

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Despite the cocktails being great, there was something a little off about the place. I'm not sure if it was the number of tourists (it is just off the main square, after all) or the man at the piano playing the theme song to Forrest Gump (?!), but it wasn't as enjoyable of an experience as I thought it would be.</span></p>

  <p>Oh, and watch out for the bathrooms. They charge for their use for non-customers. I got confused and paid the person, but turns out that wasn't necessary. (There was a sign saying "No charge for guests," but I assumed they meant guests of the hotel.)</p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">6.8</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sansho, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/15/sansho-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-15T13:25:28+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/15/sansho-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>We asked for recommendations for the best retaurant in Prague and were told that <a href="http://www.sansho.cz/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Sansho</span></a> was the place to go. Most of the places I found online described it as Czech-Asian fusion, which sounded too weird to pass up. Plus, it was our <a href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/06/26/the-anniversary-question">third first-year anniversary</a> so we decided to book a table.</p>

  <p>It's in the north of the Old Town, on a <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Sansho/@50.091722,14.43483,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0xe3da7dc930221279">beautiful square</a> right next to this amazing church.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/church.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Church outside – notice the creepy bird installation on the tower</div>
  </div>

  <p>Apparently you can eat outside during the daytime, but it was a little chilly so we ate in. The interior was pretty sparse, and reminded me of <a href="http://www.suppenkuche.com/">Suppenküche</a> in San Francisco. There were long tables with benches for mixed group dining, as well as a couple of individual tables. The servers could have been from San Francisco, too. They were all in plaid shirts and may have just wandered in off Valencia Street.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/restaurant.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Interior of the restaurant</div>
  </div>

  <p>For dinner, the only option you have is the set menu, which is fine by us. I love not having to decide what I'm going to eat. Each course came for the two of us to share. The set menu changes every night. What's weird was that other tables didn't get the same set menu that we did – some had the same dishes in a different order, some had a much different menu. It didn't seem to be dictated by any dietary requirements, so I can't quite figure it out. Anyway, onto the food.</p>

  <p>The first two courses were fish. There was a salmon sashimi, which was kinda standard. Then there was a soft-shell crab slider. It was really good. The bun had a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cha_siu_bao">steamed bun</a> texture which went great with the crispy crab. There was a little too much wasabi on it for my taste, but whatever.</p> 

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/salmon.jpg">
    <div class="alt">One: Salmon sashimi with soy and red peppercorns</div>
  </div>
  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/crab.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Two: Soft-shell crab slider with wasabi cream (what's up with the doily, amirite?)</div>
  </div>

  <p>Then there was a salad course: asparagus with ginger dressing and a crispy egg. I didn't get the egg bit, but the asparagus with ginger was great. I don't think I've ever had asparagus with more Asian-inspired flavours before. I guess this was the only thing that I could identify as really Czech-Asian fusion. Following the salad there were some gyoza, which were tasty but nothing special. (Don't get me wrong, I love gyoza, but they're like crème brûlée to me: if you're competent enough to make it, it's gonna be delicious.)</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/asparagus.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Three: Asparagus and ginger salad with a crispy egg</div>
  </div>
  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/gyoza.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Four: Pork and shrimp gyoza </div>
  </div>

  <p>Next up were my favourite two dishes. First there was a tender pork belly with chunks of watermelon. The pork belly had a sticky, sweet sauce on the outside which melted perfectly with the watermelon. Then there was a panang-style curry with some chili jam. It was served with some bread, sticky rice and a papaya salad. The curry had a strange texture, and the server explained that it was made up of "everything else from the pig."</p>

  <p>Apparently the restaurant is a "whole animal" restaurant. There was a chalk-board sign out front explaining this. Up until this point of the meal – aside from the whole crab slider – there wasn't much evidence of the "whole animal" philosophy. But I guess getting a curry with "everything else" in it counts.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/pork.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Five: Pork belly with watermelon</div>
  </div>
  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/panang.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Six: Pork panang with chili jam</div>
  </div>

  <p>Here's another thing I'm a sucker for: dessert taster plates. I can never decide if I should get the sticky toffee pudding (it might be too heavy!) or the sorbet (it's such a dull option!) or the apple pie (it might be too bland!). Every restaurant should have a dessert taster plate so I can eat all the desserts without feeling guilty.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/sansho/dessert.jpg">
    <div class="alt">Seven: Cookie with peanut ice-cream; cheesecake; sticky toffee pudding</div>
  </div>

  <p>The sticky toffee pudding was the favourite, but the cookie/peanut ice-cream came a close second.</p>

  <p>The seven courses and came out at about 1000CZK (~50USD) per person, so pretty pricey for Prague. Plus they did this thing that I've noticed a lot of restaurants do here, which is give you something without you asking, then charge you for it. It's happened with bread and jugs of water a bunch of times. I kind of assume that if something's placed down on the table and I haven't specifically asked for it, it's going to be free. I don't know if this is just a traditional thing or what, but I haven't noticed it elsewhere in Europe really.</p>

  <p>All in all, <span itemprop="summary">Sansho is a great place for a special meal, with some inventive twists on Asian cuisine.</span> If you're here for a special occasion and want something a little out of the ordinary, I'd recommend it. Just make sure you're prepared for the bill.</p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">7.8</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Absinthe Tasting in Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/11/absinthe-tasting-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-11T14:38:26+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/11/absinthe-tasting-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>I'd read recently about how <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Absinthe">absinthe</a> was having a resurgence in popularity, especially in Prague. While we're here, we decided to book a tasting with <a href="http://absinthe-prague.com"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Absinthe Prague</span></a>.</p>

  <p>I'd had absinthe before in London, and I remembered enjoying it despite not liking anise-flavoured things. I was looking forward to tasting a range of absinthes to see if I could taste any differences.</p>

  <p>The tasting itself is in the basement of <a href="http://groovebar.cz/">Groove Bar</a>, a trendy cocktail bar <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Groove+Bar/@50.080446,14.416966,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x470b94f1c418d2a1:0xe8a4fa7d2309d51f">just off the river</a>. The host is Aaron Johns, an ex-pat living in Prague who definitely knows his stuff – both about absinthe and beer (he runs a <a href="http://tastelocalbeer.com/">local beer tour</a>, too). He gave a lot of interesting history on absinthe, most of which I had no clue about. He explained in detail all about how it's made, why it's made that way, and even about the ban. He was great at answering questions, too.</p>

  <p>The ritual of drinking absinthe was enjoyable to learn about and even more fun to do – the sugar cube, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ouzo_effect">louche</a>, the absinthe spoon all came together to produce a great experience. You get a little absinthe in a glass, then balance the spoon over the top. Then you place a sugar cube on the spoon and drip ice-cold water onto the sugar until there's a ratio of about five parts water to one part absinthe. As you drip the water in, the absinthe goes from clear to cloudy (the "louche"). At that point it's ready to drink.</p>

  <p>The tasting covered six absinthes – two each from France, Switzerland and the Czech Republic. They all had unique characters and it was a lot of fun comparing notes with what others thought.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/absinthe.jpg">
    <div class="alt">The absinthes we tasted</div>
  </div>

  <p>We started out with a Swiss "le bleu" style – it was colourless rather than the vivid green usually associated with absinthe. During the louche it had a slight blue tint to it. The anise flavour was pretty strong, and that put me off a little.</p>

  <p>We then moved onto two "classic" absinthes – one French and one Swiss. They were both heavier on the wormwood, and less on the anise flavour. The French one, made by Pernod, was quite nice. The <a href="http://absinthe-prague.com/products/absinthe-roquette-1797/">Roqeutte 1797</a> was apparently based on a recipe from the original inventor of absinthe. It had a really complex palate, having hints of citrus as well as the other anise/wormwood flavours. It was a little intense for me.</p>

  <p>My two favourites were the unconventional absinthes. Both produced in the Czech Republic, one was based on a honey liquor and one was from an American recipe. The honey one didn't even need sugar added, and it went down really smoothly. It almost tasted like a cocktail. The American-recipe absinthe, <a href="http://absinthe-prague.com/products/absinthe-butterfly/">Butterfly</a> had almost a gin-like flavour.</p>

  <p>The last absinthe was French: <a href="http://absinthe-prague.com/products/la-grenouille-by-zufanek/">La Grenouille</a>. I was glad it was saved to the end, cause it had a very intense flavour.</p>

  <p>We ended up learning a lot about absinthe (such as what absinthe actually means, and the difference between absinthe and absinth) – it was a super-entertaining evening. The pours weren't too heavy, so we weren't blasted by the time we finished. It also gave both Hampton and me a deeper appreciation (and understanding) of the drink. In fact, the next night, we both ordered absinthe off the menu.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Absinthe Prague is great, and something you should definitely do if you're seeking out a unique, informative evening with some tasty spirits.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">8.8</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day Trip to Kutná Hora]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/07/day-trip-to-kutna-hora/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-07T17:44:03+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/07/day-trip-to-kutna-hora</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Prague has excellent rail connections to many smaller cities and towns in the Czech Republic. Taking day (or weekend) trips, especially if you&rsquo;re staying in Prague for an extended time, is pretty easy. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kutn%C3%A1_Hora">Kutná Hora</a> was our first destination.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://www.cd.cz/en/">website for the Czech rail system</a> is great – it gave detailed times and information on the trains, all in English. From Prague, there were direct trains to Kutná Hora every two hours or so. As our timing didn&rsquo;t line up, we took a train to Kolín, then transferred. Pro tip: jot down the final destination of your planned train. It won&rsquo;t be Kutná Hora! We ended up just following the other tourists. The journey took about an hour total, and ended up at Kutná Hora hl. n., the main train station in the town. (The journey back was a bit worse, but more on that later.)</p>

<p>Kutná Hora hl. n is close (about a 10 minute walk) to the Sedlec end of the town. In Sedlec (a small suburb of Kutná Hora) are two famous sites: the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sedlec_Ossuary">Sedlec Ossuary</a> and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_of_the_Assumption_of_Our_Lady_and_Saint_John_the_Baptist">Church of the Assumption of Our Lady</a>. I&rsquo;d heard of the Ossuary before, and that was the main reason we were in the town.</p>

<p>Getting to the ossuary was pretty simple – there were some signs pointing in the right direction (follow those labelled &ldquo;Kostnice&rdquo;). When you get to the ossuary, you can buy a ticket for up to four attractions: the ossuary and the Church of Our Lady (both in Sedlec), and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._Barbara%27s_Church,_Kutn%C3%A1_Hora">Church of St Barbara</a> and the Jesuit College (in the Kutná Hora town centre). The Jesuit College was closed on Mondays so we didn&rsquo;t go. The admission was 160CZK (~8USD) for the three attractions.</p>

<p>The ossuary was neat. It was a lot smaller than I was expecting – basically one room, with a tonne of bones. It was creepy, but the number of tourists taking photos in there made it feel more like a room in the <a href="http://dedicatedtodlp.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/potc-queue1.jpg">Pirates of the Caribbean queue</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/bones.png">
  <div class="alt">Bones, skull and crossbones, bone chandelier, bone signature.</div>
</div>


<p>They hand out laminated sheets with some information on them, so you get a little historical information. However, I&rsquo;d recommend either loading up Wikipedia or having it on your phone for more detail.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/bone-arms.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Coat of Arms in bones, cause, y'know, why not?</div>
</div>


<p>After the ossuary, we went to the Church of the Assumption of Our Lady. We were the only people in there. It was a little strange – I&rsquo;ve not really been in a Gothic-looking cathedral where all the walls are painted beige/yellow.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/church-of-our-lady.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Church of the Assumption of Our Lady</div>
</div>


<p>Aside from a couple of <a href="http://www.onestepinto.com/gallery/Kutna%20Hora/DSC_4303_Kutna_OSI.jpg">garishly-dressed relics</a> it was pretty dull. I wouldn&rsquo;t recommend going but it&rsquo;s a bit of a waste as you walk right by it heading into town from the ossuary.</p>

<p>There are supposedly a number of buses that go from the ossuary into the centre, but we decided we&rsquo;d walk it. The best thing I can say about <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/dir/Sedlec+Ossuary,+Z%C3%A1meck%C3%A1,+284+03+Kutn%C3%A1+Hora,+Czech+Republic/St+Barbara's+Church,+Barborsk%C3%A1,+284+01+Kutn%C3%A1+Hora,+Czech+Republic/@49.9533462,15.2670308,15z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m14!4m13!1m5!1m1!1s0x470c40fc635ac54f:0x320cc9caa5f1508e!2m2!1d15.288043!2d49.961782!1m5!1m1!1s0x470c41a6cd710ae9:0xa19ced0f3eeca1db!2m2!1d15.26362!2d49.944911!3e2">the walk from Sedlec into Kutná Hora proper</a> is that it was about 40 minutes and got us a fair few steps on our fitbits. The walk is mainly through industrial and suburban parts of the town, and for the most part there&rsquo;s not much to look at. However, once you get into the centre itself, Kutná Hora is gorgeous.</p>

<p>There are a number of winding cobblestone back-streets with beautiful buildings. I think we could have spent a few hours just wandering around the town. We had a quick lunch at <a href="http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g274701-d1570760-Reviews-Restaurant_Cafe_Harmonia-Kutna_Hora_Central_Bohemian_Region_Bohemia.html">Café Harmonia</a>, which had amazing gnocchi. Then we headed for the next church on our list: St Barbara&rsquo;s.</p>

<p>The walk up to the cathedral was beautiful – there&rsquo;s a promenade-type thing with statues along it that reminded us of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Bridge">Charles Bridge</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/walk-to-cathedral.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Walking towards St Barbara's</div>
</div>


<p>From the promenade you get a great view looking over Kutná Hora.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/view.jpg">
  <div class="alt">View over Kutná Hora</div>
</div>


<p>Inside, St Barbara&rsquo;s was amazing. Much better than the Church of the Assumption of Our Lady.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/st-barbaras.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Beautiful gothic interior.</div>
</div>


<p>There were murals all along the apse and the sides of the nave.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/apse-mural.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Mural in the apse</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/nave-mural.jpg">
  <div class="alt">14th century mural at the back of the nave</div>
</div>


<p>There were a few stained glass windows from the 1910s, which were neat. The one which I found interesting was from 2013. I find modern stained glass intriguiging as it&rsquo;s not really a standard modern art form (aside from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gilbert_%26_George">Gilbert and George</a>).</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/kutna-hora/stained-window.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Stained glass window from 2013</div>
</div>


<p>After we had explored the cathedral, we started our journey back to Prague. Rather than walk the 40 minutes back to Kutná Hora hl. n., we went to the station in the centre of town – Kutná Hora město. It&rsquo;s tiny and rural, without any real platforms. There&rsquo;s a shuttle train that runs between this station and the main station. When we arrived, the next train was in 40 minutes(!), and we didn&rsquo;t have much choice but to wait for it. We changed at the main station to a train to Kolín. From Kolín to Prague we ended up on the Berlin train, an EC-class train. It was slightly nicer than the R-class we took on the way there, but not by much. It ended up taking us about two hours for the return journey. I&rsquo;d recommend timing your trip back carefully.</p>

<p>All in all it was a pretty nice day trip. If you&rsquo;re travelling around the Czech Republic, or you&rsquo;re staying in Prague for a while and want to get out of the city, it&rsquo;s a fun thing to do.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
