<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Alcatraz | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/alcatraz/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-07T14:48:31-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ai Weiwei @Large]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/12/29/ai-wei-wei-at-large/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-29T09:59:26-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/12/29/ai-wei-wei-at-large</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.for-site.org/project/ai-weiwei-alcatraz/">@Large</a> is an art exhibition created by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ai_Weiwei">Ai Weiwei</a> to be displayed specifically at <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alcatraz_Federal_Penitentiary">Alcatraz</a>. You don&rsquo;t need special tickets to view it – you just buy <a href="http://www.alcatrazcruises.com/">regular tickets to Alcatraz</a>. The art is scattered across a number of buildings/areas of the island, so you can explore it while you&rsquo;re on the regular Alcatraz tour.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/dock.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/dock.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Poster at the Entrance</div>
</div>


<p>The exhibition includes an area I hadn&rsquo;t seen before – the <a href="http://www.for-site.org/places-artists/places/alcatraz-island/new-industries-building">New Industries Building</a>. Last time I visited it was closed off, so it was nice to visit an extra area of the island.</p>

<p>Inside are three of the installations: <a href="http://www.for-site.org/project/ai-weiwei-alcatraz-with-wind/">With Wind</a>, <a href="http://www.for-site.org/project/ai-weiwei-alcatraz-trace/">Trace</a>, and <a href="http://www.for-site.org/project/ai-weiwei-alcatraz-refraction/">Refraction</a>. With Wind consists of traditional kite sculptures – one large dragon snaking through the room, plus a number of other smaller kites.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/with-wind.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/with-wind.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">With Wind</div>
</div>


<p>The dragon had &ldquo;subversive&rdquo; quotes written on it. The smaller kites were made of fabric printed with birds and animals from nations that have less-than-stellar human rights records.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/with-wind-2.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/with-wind-2.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">With Wind</div>
</div>


<p>The fact that these kites – usually symbols of freedom, soaring across the sky – are cooped up in a factory building was jarring.</p>

<p>The next room contained Trace. A series of portraits of political prisoners made in Lego covered the floor.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/trace.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/trace.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Trace – <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shin_Suk-ja">Shin Suk-ja</a></div>
</div>


<p>Along the side there were books explaining the portraits – who they were, where they were imprisoned, what they did to end up there. It was overwhelming, and a little difficult to connect with. The sheer number of prisoners – most of whom I&rsquo;d (shamefully) never heard of – made it impossible to know everything about all of them.</p>

<p>Looking at a couple, though, is worthwhile. The most surprising for me was <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Kiriakou">John Kiriakou</a>, who was the first agent to relase the information that the CIA was using waterboarding to torture prisoners. He&rsquo;s currently serving jail time for this. <a href="http://www.for-site.org/project/ai-weiwei-alcatraz-trace/">You can see a list of the political prisoners featured in the artwork on the installation&rsquo;s website.</a></p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/trace-2.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/trace-2.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Trace – <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Kiriakou">John Kiriakou</a></div>
</div>


<p>In the old dining room, there&rsquo;s another part of @Large – <a href="http://www.for-site.org/project/ai-weiwei-alcatraz-yours-truly/">Yours Truly</a>. Here you can write postcards to the prisoners depicted in Trace. The postcards are already addressed, and on the front have national plants or animals from the prisoner&rsquo;s home country.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/yours-truly.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/yours-truly.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Yours Truly</div>
</div>


<p>It&rsquo;s a nice idea to remind these prisoners that there are people still thinking of them. I certainly felt good about writing a postcard. Afterwards, though, I wondered if they would actually reach the prisoners. I don&rsquo;t mean to question the honesty of the volunteers who mail them – but I&rsquo;m unsure as to whether the Bahrain government (or whereever) would allow their prisoners to get such a large amount of mail.</p>

<p>The hospital wing had an installation called <a href="http://www.for-site.org/project/ai-weiwei-alcatraz-blossom/">Blossom</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/blossom.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/blossom.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Blossom</div>
</div>


<p>It consisted of beautiful and delicate porcelain flowers arranged in the toilets, bathtubs, and sinks of the wing.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/blossom-2.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/blossom-2.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Blossom</div>
</div>


<p>The flowers chosen were, again, national symbols of countries with serious human rights infractions.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/blossom-3.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/aiweiwei/blossom-3.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Blossom</div>
</div>


<p>Also on the tour there were two sound installations. <a href="http://www.for-site.org/project/ai-weiwei-alcatraz-illumination/">Illumination</a>, in the psychiatric cells of the hospital, had Tibetan and Native American chants echoing around the tiled rooms.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.for-site.org/project/ai-weiwei-alcatraz-stay-tuned/">Stay Tuned</a>, in A Wing, opened up some cells for you to sit in. Music, poetry, or speeches from political prisoners was piped in through a tiny grate in the floor. Sitting on a stool, alone, listening to these songs gave me a strong feeling of shame. It was certainly the biggest emotional reaction I got from the exhibit.</p>

<p>Here I was, having paid to come here. I chose to sit in a jail cell and listen to music. I could get up and leave at any point I wanted. I was – dare I say it – having <em>fun</em>. It was a little perverse.</p>

<p>But maybe that&rsquo;s the point? It managed to open my eyes to a wider issue, and obviously one that Ai Weiwei is concerned about. I&rsquo;ve researched more of the political prisoners since visiting the exhibit.</p>

<p>So, at least in that way, the exhibition is a great success.</p>

<p><em><a href="http://www.for-site.org/project/ai-weiwei-alcatraz/">@Large: Ai Weiwei on Alcatraz</a> runs until 26th April 2015.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
