<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Review | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/review/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-14T17:48:18-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AnonymouS Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/30/anonymous-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-30T04:10:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/30/anonymous-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>Our time in Prague is almost at an end – today, we&#8217;re taking a flight to Amsterdam. We saved an intriguing bar for our last new experience in the cocktail world of Prague. <a href="http://www.anonymousbar.cz/cs"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">AnonymouS Bar</span></a> (their weird capitalisation, not mine) is off a small alley in the old town, and it is themed around the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gunpowder_Plot">gunpowder plot</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/V_for_Vendetta">V for Vendetta</a>, and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anonymous_(group)">Anonymous</a> movement.</p>

  <p>Inside, the bar is styled like the interior of V&#8217;s hideout in the comic book/film. It allows the use of comfortable chairs, but also brick-showing-through-plaster murals and classic portraits with faces replaced by the Guy Fawkes mask. It kind of reminded us (in the best way possible, as we&#8217;re theme park nerds) of a Universal Studios or Disney experience.</p>

  <p>The menu has a really great concept: a list of standard drinks on one page, paired up with an AnonymouS-bar twist on the classics. It was a goodway to quickly pick out a drink you&#8217;d be sure to like. I went for the St Marry&#8217;s Virus – again, that&#8217;s their weird spelling, and I&#8217;m not sure if it&#8217;s deliberate or not. It was a twist on the Piccadilly martini. The bartender came over with a biohazard box, which opened to reveal a giant syringe containing the cocktial.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-st-marrys.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-st-marrys.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">St Marry&#8217;s Virus</div>
  </div>

  <p>Hampton went for a take on a gimlet, and it was really delicious! I think they added cucumber and some other stuff.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-butterfly.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-butterfly.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">M. Butterfly</div>
  </div>

  <p>The menu, aside from the drink and liquor list, was pretty entertaining. They had neat explanation of their thought process behind the concept. As I was flicking through, I noticed there was a cocktail set apart from the rest, alone on the very first page. It didn&#8217;t have a description, aside from the old rhyme: &#8220;Remember, remember the fifth of November&#8230;&#8221; It was too puzzling not to get.</p>

  <p>Hampton got it after me, so I have photos of what it entailed. The bartender handed you a Guy Fawkes mask and took your photo.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-photo.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-photo.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">They had to find more film</div>
  </div>

  <p>After that, they make the drink. It involved lining a brandy snifter with liquor and setting it on fire. Once the fire had died down, they poured in a whisky-based old-fashioned-esque cocktail. They placed the photo on top to stop the smoke from the flames coming out.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-remember.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-remember.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Remember</div>
  </div>

  <p>Here are the photos of our night. It&#8217;s nice to have something to keep after a night out. Especially once you&#8217;ve had a few cocktails.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-polaroid.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/anon-polaroid.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Ahh, memories!</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">The themeing theatricality of AnonymouS bar is great, but it&#8217;s really backed up by the delicious cocktails on offer.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">8.5</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[La Degustation]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/27/la-degustation/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-27T05:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/27/la-degustation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.ladegustation.cz/en/#index"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">La Degustation</span></a>, one of two restaurants in Prague to have <a href="http://www.viamichelin.com/web/Restaurants/Restaurants-Prague-_-Praha_hlavni_mesto-Czech_Republic?strLocid=31MzhkeDEwY05UQXVNRGczT0RFPWNNVFF1TkRJd05EWT0=">a Michelin star</a>, was our special treat as our time in Prague is coming to an end. Its slogan is &#8220;bohême bourgeoise,&#8221; which I found amusing.</p>

  <p>Inside, I don&#8217;t know if anything can be gothic minimalist, but I think that&#8217;s an accurate description. Arches ribbed the ceiling, and artfully-placed dim spotlights created wonderful shadows. The walls were bare and painted a light grey, and the furniture was all low-backed and dark wood. The windows onto the street had the restaurant&#8217;s signature checkered pattern.</p>

  <p>As we sat down, the waiter came over and gave us an envelope.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/envelope.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/envelope.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">We were handed an envelope</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/back-envelope.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/back-envelope.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The back of the envelope</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/contents.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/contents.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Open it to find the checkered pattern</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/menu.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/menu.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Two menu options</div>
  </div>

  <p>We went for the eleven-course menu, with wine pairings. It was definitely a lot of food, and I wish I hadn&#8217;t eaten so much of the delicious bread they brought. The menu focussed on Czech ingredients and dishes, but with modern, vaguely molecular-gastronomic twists. Apparently a lot of the inspiration for their dishes comes from a late-19th century Czech cookbook.</p>

  <p>I didn&#8217;t take pictures and I won&#8217;t bore you with a course-by-course detailing of everything. A couple of stand-out dishes, though: dijon mustard ice-cream with hot tomato sauce. The sauce was the perfect distillation of tomato flavour. Add that to the mustard (which wasn&#8217;t too spicy), plus the mixing of the hot sauce with the cold ice-cream and you get an incredible dish that&#8217;s not quite like anything I&#8217;ve had before.</p>

  <p>There was a foie gras course where the liver had been finely grated over wine jelly and pistachio. I&#8217;d never eaten foie gras grated before, and it really helped take away the heaviness you sometimes get. Then there was the beef tongue &#8220;signature dish.&#8221; </p>

  <p>I really enjoyed the wine pairings. They used mostly Czech wines, and it was nice to see the variety in types they produce here. There was also a great unfiltered Slovenian wine called <a href="http://www.scurek.com/www/index.php/en/wines/white-wines">Kontra</a>. The cheese course came with a delicious IPA from the <a href="http://www.beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/23493/">Matuška Brewery</a>.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">If you&#8217;re willing to splash out, this place is definitely worth it. It&#8217;s a modern take on Czech flavours and ingredients, and the courses are presented beautifully.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">9.3</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orange Bar, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/orange-bar-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-23T04:33:48-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/orange-bar-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.orangebar.cz/en/homepage.html"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Orange Bar</span></a> is pretty close by to us and has decent reviews. It&#8217;s a little tricky to find, down a couple of side-streets, but there&#8217;s a nice orange-shaped sign outside to let you know when you&#8217;re there.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/outside.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/outside.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">From the street</div>
  </div>

  <p>From the outside, it looks pretty normal, right? Inside, though, it reminded me of a bar in Dune or something. The only lights had orange filters, and all the walls were molded to give the appearance of being dug out of a cave.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/bar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/bar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The bar (I think the spice is kept on the top shelf)</div>
  </div>

  <p>The bar shelves were all integrated into the back wall. The other walls had fake columns with cubbies for desert plants.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/plants.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/plants.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Walls with plants</div>
  </div>

  <p>The cocktail list leaned heavily towards rum-based beach drinks – mai tais, piña coladas, zombies etc. There&#8217;s also a good list of classics, too. Hampton went for (of course) a manhattan. I tried out the mai tai but it was a little too sweet for me.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/cocktails.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/cocktails.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Manhattan and a mai tai</div>
  </div>

  <p>We were there during a massive thunderstorm and didn&#8217;t have umbrellas, so we stayed for another round (or two). The moscow mule was <em>much</em> better. Get that! It had a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physalis_peruviana">physalis</a> garnish too, which is awesome.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/moscow-mule.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/orangebar/moscow-mule.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Moscow mule</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Orange bar has a neighbourhood feel and a fun theme. The drinks are sweet, but tasty, so I&#8217;d stick to non-tiki drinks (unless you&#8217;re a particular fan).</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">7.1</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hoffa, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/hoffa-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-23T04:32:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/23/hoffa-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>For some reason, there&#8217;s a bar in Prague named after <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jimmy_Hoffa">Jimmy Hoffa</a>, the American union leader who went missing in the 70s. Unfortunately, my lack of Czech skills (and poor Google translating) don&#8217;t help much with the &#8220;About&#8221; page on the <a href="http://hoffa.cz"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Hoffa</span></a> website.</p>

  <p>First and foremost: this is a non-smoking bar! Yay! That automatically gets you points in my book. Most bars have smoking and non-smoking areas, but that&#8217;s not quite the same. Location-wise, it&#8217;s on a little intersection near the main train station (so great for people-watching), and has big windows. The decor is neat – they have a massive trompe-l&#8217;œil mural on one side so it looks like you&#8217;re in a warehouse.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-mural.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-mural.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Mural in Hoffa</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-bar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-bar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The bar</div>
  </div>

  <p>They have mostly traditional drinks, with some specials on a chalkboard. The drink I had was pretty good, but nothing amazing. I went for a glass of Pimm&#8217;s as it was ridiculously hot outside.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-pimms.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-pimms.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Pimm&#8217;s!</div>
  </div>

  <p>They offer decent bar snacks, too. We got some tortilla chips with salsa and sour cream.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-tortillas.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-tortillas.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Tortilla chips with salsa and sour cream</div>
  </div>

  <p>We also got some hamburgers, which were amazing. They were juicy, cooked medium-rare, and had spicy-sweet secret sauce on them. Delicious!</p>

  <p>The bathroom doors were pretty neat, too.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-mural.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/hoffa-bathroom.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Bathroom door</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">I can see us returning to this place for its relaxed atmosphere, neat interior, and reasonably-priced decent drinks. It seemed like a nice place to call your local.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">7.0</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zinc Lounge, Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/21/zinc-lounge-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-21T05:52:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/21/zinc-lounge-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>After the underwhelming experience at <a href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/19/cloud-9-prague">Cloud 9</a>, I wanted to try out the bar at the other Prague-based Hilton: <a href="http://www.hiltonpragueoldtown.com/loungebar-en.html"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Zinc Lounge and Bar</span></a>, found in the <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Hilton+Prague+Old+Town/@50.088515,14.431864,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x63a407a250359dc7">Hilton Prague Old Town</a>. I wanted to see how it measured up, and in short: it was pretty bad. Please forgive me, Cloud 9, I didn&#8217;t realise your sister bar was so awful. I would have cut you some slack otherwise!</p>

  <p>The Hilton Prague Old Town is pretty easy to find compared with the other Hilton. It&#8217;s just off Náměstí Republiky, one of the main squares in the Old Town. The Zinc Bar and Lounge is just to the right as you come in. &#8220;Zinc&#8221; is also the name of the hotel restaurant, just behind the bar</p>

  <p>Inside, it&#8217;s decorated like a dreary hotel lobby. Leather seats and low, round wooden tables. Holey partitions of wood try to separate the actual hotel lobby from the bar. Despite their best efforts, we were still drinking around a bunch of people loudly chatting on Skype (I assume there&#8217;s free wi-fi in the lobby area) and wheeling their luggage around, waiting for their ride to the airport.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-bar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-bar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Zinc Bar</div>
  </div>

  <p>The menu consisted almost entirely of classic cocktails. There was nothing inventive or fancy like at Cloud 9. We stuck to our staples and got a gimlet and a manhattan. They were both OK – competently done and similar to what you could find at a lot of bars in Prague.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-cocktails.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-cocktails.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Drinks: gimlet and a manhattan</div>
  </div>

  <p>The thing is, these cocktails were 220Kč (~$11) each. And there was me going off on how expensive the Cloud 9 cocktails were, at 185Kč (~$9)! Like I said in the beginning, I&#8217;M SORRY CLOUD 9. The Cloud 9 cocktails were far more reasonably-priced (I still think they&#8217;re expensive, though). At least you get something different, innovative. At Zinc you get a standard cocktail that at another bar (say, Groove Bar) would be 100Kč (~$5).</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-interior.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/cocktails/zinc-interior.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Hampton looking SUPREMELY DISAPPOINTED</div>
  </div>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">Put together the atmosphere of the hotel lobby with the fact that the drinks were exceedinly expensive for what they were, and you get a disappointing experience. I&#8217;d suggest venturing a little out of the hotel to find a better cocktail bar.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">4.6</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
