<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: The-journey-2014 | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/the-journey-2014/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-12T14:50:31-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SassConf 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/10/10/sass-conf-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-10T11:33:48-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/10/10/sass-conf-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week was the second <a href="http://sassconf.com/">SassConf</a>. After having a blast last year, we had to come back (and it gave us a great excuse to be in New York City for a while).</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/itsmisscs">Claudina</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/Snugug">Sam</a>, and the other organisers did a great job of having community events for the whole week in the run-up to the conference. A large number of SassConf attendees were staying in New York for a while, so it was a great idea to have some &ldquo;unofficial&rdquo; community events beforehand.</p>

<p>There were great talks by <a href="https://twitter.com/smithschwartz">Smith Schwartz</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/patrickhamann">Patrick Hamann</a> on Monday night. On Wednesday there was a fireside chat with the Sass Design team. Hampton talked about the original concept behind Sass and its unconventional branding, then <a href="https://twitter.com/jina">Jina Bolton</a> walked through the complete redesign of the <a href="http://sass-lang.com">Sass website</a> that she spearheaded last year.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/sass-conf/fireside-chat.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/sass-conf/fireside-chat.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Wednesday&#8217;s Sass Design fireside chat</div>
</div>


<p>It was a fitting topic – at last year&rsquo;s SassConf, the new website was launched. <a href="https://twitter.com/bermonpainter">Bermon Painter</a> joined in to explain the new logo, too. It was an entertaining evening.</p>

<p>The first day of the conference consisted of talks. It was neat hearing from <a href="https://twitter.com/Una">Una</a> about the global Sass community, and I always enjoy listening to <a href="https://twitter.com/smithschwartz">Smith</a> talk about art and how you can bring art into your everyday life.</p>

<p>It was also great to finally give <a href="https://twitter.com/nex3">Natalie</a> the <a href="https://thenetawards.com/">net Game-Changer of the Year award</a>. It was picked up by <a href="https://twitter.com/kaelig">Kaelig</a> back in May. He gave it to us when we were in London, then we asked my Mum to ship it to New York for SassConf.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/sass-conf/gamechanger.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/sass-conf/gamechanger.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Natalie receiving the Game-Changer of the Year award</div>
</div>


<p>The next day was workshop-based. I wasn&rsquo;t able to go to any, but from what I could see on Twitter people had a great time and learnt a lot.</p>

<p>The after-party was on Friday night, and it involved a boat trip (with open bar and karaoke) around the bottom of Manhattan. I guess boats are &ldquo;in&rdquo; at conferences – we did a boat trip for lunch during <a href="http://2014.la-conf.org/">LaConf</a> in Paris.</p>

<p>Anyway, it was <em>awesome</em>. Seeing any city from a new perspective is great, and Manhattan is absolutely gorgeous at night.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/sass-conf/boat-wallst.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/sass-conf/boat-wallst.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">World Trade Center from the boat</div>
</div>


<p>We sailed from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chelsea_Piers">Chelsea Piers</a> to near the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brooklyn_Bridge">Brooklyn Bridge</a>. Then, on the way back, we got really close to the Statue of Liberty!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/sass-conf/boat-liberty.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/sass-conf/boat-liberty.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Statue of Liberty</div>
</div>


<p>The number of attendees at the conference was small enough that you recognised most people at the after-party. I felt like I could go up to anyone and strike up a conversation. Everyone had a great time.</p>

<p>The next day was the &ldquo;unconference&rdquo; – something I&rsquo;m not familiar with at all. The idea is that people would form their own groups to talk/discuss/code about what they&rsquo;re feeling passionate about. I must admit, I was pretty sceptical going into the day. I expected it to end up being isolated people working on their own thing, with minimal discussions.</p>

<p>I was very wrong.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/sass-conf/new-work-city.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/sass-conf/new-work-city.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The unconference was held in the New Work City offices</div>
</div>


<p>Within the first ten minutes, all the meeting rooms had been booked up with various meetings – everything from the minutiae of libsass to contributing to open source to motivation for making things. It was great seeing strangers come together to discuss these topics and try to figure out solutions or help each other out.</p>

<p>I recruited Smith and a couple of other people to help me with a project I&rsquo;ve been sitting on for a while. It&rsquo;s almost done and I&rsquo;ll be posting about it soon.</p>

<p>It was a great end to the conference, and really drove home one of the things that I believe sets the Sass community apart from most other tech communities I&rsquo;ve seen: the realisation that building a diverse and welcoming community is just as important as building the technology itself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Ninth Avenue Bars]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/30/some-ninth-avenue-bars/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-30T11:36:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/30/some-ninth-avenue-bars</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post has an awkward title. That&rsquo;s chiefly because the bars in New York are so numerous that I couldn&rsquo;t claim knowledge of even 0.1 percent. I couldn&rsquo;t even claim to have exhausted bars in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chelsea,_Manhattan">Chelsea</a> (our current neighbourhood), or even the Ninth Avenue bit of Chelsea. In fact, a more accurate title for this post would be &ldquo;Bars Between 20th and 17th Streets on Ninth Avenue: A Small Sampling.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s strange coming from Prague, where we managed to check off almost all of the decent cocktail bars in the centre, to a city where we&rsquo;ve barely scratched the surface of our neighbourhood.</p>

<p>Anyway, we&rsquo;ve been trying out some of the recommended bars in the area. We haven&rsquo;t found a bar we&rsquo;re completely comfortable with – the nice mix of decent cocktails and relaxed atmosphere has eluded us so far in Chelsea.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://tipsyparson.com/">Tipsy Parson</a> is a great restaurant as well as a pretty good cocktail bar. You know how often, a Southern-style restaurant can&rsquo;t beat the food you actually get in the South? Well, that&rsquo;s not the case here. I had fried catfish with gravy, and Hampton had shrimp and grits. Both were great – the catfish was crisp and the gravy wasn&rsquo;t too peppery (which happens a lot with Southern gravy).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/catfish.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/catfish.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Fried catfish</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/shrimp-grits.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/shrimp-grits.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Shrimp and grits</div>
</div>


<p>Looking at the menu, we spotted the head chef&rsquo;s name: Ty-Lör Boring. That&rsquo;s quite an unusual na- wait, it&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.bravotv.com/people/ty-lor-boring/bio"><em>that</em> Ty-Lör</a>, from Top Chef?! It was!</p>

<p>They also have seats at the bar. The cocktails are a little bit hit and miss. They&rsquo;re trying hard to be inventive, but a lot of them miss the mark. There was a ginger-based drink that was <em>way</em> too gingery, even for me. The Professor Plum was pretty good, although due to seasonal changes of the menu I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s available any more.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/tipsy-plum.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/tipsy-plum.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Professor Plum cocktail</div>
</div>


<p><a href="http://bathtubginnyc.com/">Bathtub Gin</a> is a speakeasy behind a coffee shop. It&rsquo;s quite conspicuous for a speakeasy – walking past on a Saturday night you see a line of people outside an empty coffee bar. I&rsquo;m no fool! No coffee is that tasty. We booked for 6pm on a quiet night and even then the bouncer made us wait outside, despite it being empty when we were eventually let in.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/bathtub-logo.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/bathtub-logo.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Bathtub Gin logo</div>
</div>


<p>The drinks were quite good. We started out with a Martini and a Blushing Lady #2.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/bathtub-martini.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/bathtub-martini.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Martini</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/blush.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/blush.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Blushing Lady #2</div>
</div>


<p>The Blushing Lady #2 tasted like a sour grape candy. The Martini was OK. The secound round proved better – a Vesper and a Last Word.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/bathtub-vesper.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/bathtub-vesper.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Vesper</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/last-word.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/last-word.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Last Word</div>
</div>


<p>They had some great small plates to share – the mushroom gnocchi was my favourite. The pork belly sliders were also super-tasty.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/bathtub-sliders.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/bathtub-sliders.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Pork belly sliders</div>
</div>


<p>The staff were a little stand-offish, which I&rsquo;m getting tired of when it comes to fancy speakeasy-style bars. Bourbon &amp; Branch in SF has a similar problem. (<em>Update</em>: we went to the speakeasy <a href="http://www.mlkhny.com/newyork/">Milk and Honey</a> and the staff there were delightful. The drinks were great too!)</p>

<p><a href="http://www.themaritimehotel.com/labottega.php">La Bottega</a> is in a crazy-looking hotel called the Maritime. Its windows are all circular, and it&rsquo;s sides are sloped inwards. The drinks there are OK, but not very well balanced. The Vesper tasted like pure vodka; the Manhattan was almost pure vermouth.</p>

<p>Some other bars we&rsquo;ve been to in the Chelsea area (but not on 9th) are <a href="http://www.theparknyc.com/">The Park</a>, on 10th avenue, and <a href="http://heartwoodnyc.com/">Heartwood</a>, on 8th.</p>

<p>The Park is in a beautiful converted parking garage, with an indoor &ldquo;garden&rdquo; area. The front bar was pretty crowded, so we sat in the garden area where – pro-tip – there&rsquo;s a secret back bar! We ordered drinks from both and the back bartender was way better. Plus there was no wait at the back bar.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/hendricks-mash.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/ninth-ave-bars/hendricks-mash.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hendrick&#8217;s Mash</div>
</div>


<p>Heartwood is on 8th Avenue, between 20th and 19th. I ordered a couple of drinks there and didn&rsquo;t really enjoy them – one was my fault, the other the bartender&rsquo;s. The menu had sections, one of which was classifed as &ldquo;Shrubs.&rdquo; Not being familiar with the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shrub_(drink)">drink called a shrub</a>, I picked one with gin in it. Turns out, they really do put vinegar in them. It was surprising on first taste, then just became kinda throat-burning. I love vinegar, but drinking it is a little difficult. Anyway, I put that mistake down to me, and not the bar itself. However, I then ordered a Last Word and they missed out the lime. That makes it a little undrinkable – just sweet and herbal. My first drink was too acidic, my next not acidic enough. There&rsquo;s no pleasing me.</p>

<p>Anyway, SassConf has started and I&rsquo;ll no doubt be writing about that as the week goes on.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AirBnB (Power's Out)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/25/airbnb-powers-out/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-25T09:20:36-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/25/airbnb-powers-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;re in New York City! The Big Apple! The city that never sleeps! Etc. etc.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;d booked a small but nicely-designed AirBnB in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chelsea,_Manhattan">Chelsea</a>. After a small mix-up with the address (turns out the listed address was one street off, for some reason), we arrived and settled in. It was a little dirty, and there were no towels, but a quick stop at <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Bed+Bath+%26+Beyond/@40.7406703,-73.9942279,16z/data=!3m1!5s0x89c25d0c60996adb:0x480c0d194112b5d3!4m5!1m2!2m1!1sbed+bath+and+beyond+nyc!3m1!1s0x0:0x231ff6a484b76185">Bed, Bath and Beyond</a> sorted our need for cleaning supplies and linen.</p>

<p>Our first morning, we woke up and ran some quick errands. When we came back, the power was off at the apartment. We texted the host, who said that she was at work and wouldn&rsquo;t be able to sort anything out until after 4pm – in about 6 hours (!). So&hellip; we wandered over to the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whitney_Museum_of_American_Art">Whitney</a> for the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeff_Koons">Jeff Koons</a> retrospective. I love the Whitney – give me their brutalist architecture over the Guggenheim any day. They&rsquo;re moving to a new building next year so I&rsquo;m glad I got to visit their current space one last time.</p>

<p>The Koons retrospective was great. I was only familiar with a few of his works, and the exhibition did a great job of fleshing out the rest. The Equillibrium stuff was mesmerising. Definitely check it out if you&rsquo;re around (it&rsquo;s on until the 19th October, I think) – and grab the free audioguide too!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/koons.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/koons.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Selfie in a Koons balloon</div>
</div>


<p>Still having a few hours to kill, we went to see a film. There&rsquo;s not a whole lot on right now (I&rsquo;m waiting for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gone_Girl_(film)">Gone Girl</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inherent_Vice_(film)">Inherent Vice</a> this autumn), so we took a chance on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Drop_(film)">The Drop</a> with Tom Hardy, Noomi Rapace and James Gandolfini. It&rsquo;s a slow-burning crime character study, although it&rsquo;s quite difficult to categorise. Tom Hardy does a great job of making a meek, loveable – but potentially dangerous – guy. It was also nice (but sad) to see James Gandolfini in what is his last feature-film role.</p>

<p>The film finished and we headed back to the apartment – the electricity was still off. We tried contacting our host, who told us that she&rsquo;d forgotten to pay the electricity bill for the past couple of months. Not only that, but everyone had gone home for the day and they wouldn&rsquo;t be able to turn the power on until tomorrow. Oh dear.</p>

<p>By this point, it was starting to get dark and our living area looked a little bit like this:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/darkness.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/darkness.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The sofa</div>
</div>


<p>We called AirBnB who, to their credit, had great customer support. They said they&rsquo;d comp us for a meal and a hotel for that night. They said if the power wasn&rsquo;t on tomorrow, they&rsquo;d help us find a new place in NYC.</p>

<p>They arranged everything and got us a room at a <a href="https://www.kimptonhotels.com/stay/eventi-hotel-chelsea-ny">nearby Kimpton</a>. So, we packed up our satchels for an overnight adventure. We stopped for a quick meal on the way, and arrived at about 10:30pm. The check-in desk told us they were all booked up, and only had one strange room left – a library with a veranda. They said we could look at the room first, but we decided to go with it. At this point, as long as we had power we didn&rsquo;t really mind.</p>

<p>We got to the room and it was more of a suite or event space. One half had a library.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/library.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/library.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Library</div>
</div>


<p>And the other half had a dining room.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/dining-room.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/dining-room.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Dining Room</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/panorama.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/panorama.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Panorama of the library</div>
</div>


<p>The room was on the corner of the building and had a wrap-around balcony/veranda. From there you had a great view of the Empire State Building.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/veranda-view.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/veranda-view.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The view from the veranda</div>
</div>


<p>We were feeling pretty great about this room until&hellip; wait, where was the bed?</p>

<p>Turns out, they forgot to bring a bed into the room. We called down to the front desk and they promptly sent up a couple of guys to make up a sofa bed for us.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/bed.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/bed.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Our bed</div>
</div>


<p>It was pretty comfortable, for a sofa-bed. Anyway, to make up for the weird room and lack of a proper bed, they gave us some credit for room service. As we&rsquo;d already eaten, we used the credit on better things.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/wine.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/nyc/power-out/wine.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Better things = wine</div>
</div>


<p>The next morning we headed back to the apartment and the power was still off – however the host had arranged for the electricity company and the super to come and get it all sorted out.</p>

<p>Although it was a bit of a nightmare, this is the first bad experience with AirBnB we&rsquo;ve had in the five months we&rsquo;ve been travelling. The AirBnB customer support was great, and the host also said she&rsquo;d give us the previous night free. Still, it was a pretty stressful adventure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bar Chef]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/20/bar-chef/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-20T12:10:44-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/20/bar-chef</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>We&#8217;ve been using <a href="http://www.worldsbestbars.com/">World&#8217;s Best Bars</a> to find bars when we&#8217;ve been travelling. It&#8217;s a little hit-and-miss, and you need to do some extra research before you randomly pick one. But it&#8217;s great if you&#8217;re in a place that doesn&#8217;t really use Yelp or FourSquare. We showed it to Mike and Melissa, and they laughed at a lot of the choices for Toronto. One, however, they recommended: <a href="http://www.barcheftoronto.com/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Bar Chef</span></a>.</p>

  <p>It&#8217;s in the second-coolest neighbourhood in the world (according to <a href="http://www.vogue.com/slideshow/1080625/fifteen-coolest-street-style-neighborhoods/">Vogue</a>) – Queen Street West. They serve fancy cocktails and want to &#8220;challenge the [&#8230;] cocktail experience.&#8221; SOUNDS FUN!</p>

  <p>Oh, it was dark inside, so most of my photos are a little grainy. Sorry.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/barchef.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/barchef.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Bar Chef placemat</div>
  </div>

  <p>We started out with two normal-ish cocktails. The Symphony No 5 was a gin/vanilla thing that was OK. The Basil Daiquiri was tasty – super-drinkable.

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/symphony-daiquiri.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/symphony-daiquiri.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Symphony No. 5 and the Basil Daiquiri</div>
  </div>

  <p>These two cocktails were pretty good. However, we noticed there was a &#8220;modernist&#8221; section that had more expensive ones – some with some weird ingredients (&#8220;spring fog&#8221;? &#8220;beach essence&#8221;?).</p>

  <p>Hampton got a $45 (!) Manhattan. It came under a giant cloche filled with smoke.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/manhattan-cloche.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/manhattan-cloche.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Cloche full of smoke</div>
  </div>

  <p>It rested on the table for a minute or two before the bartender came over and slowly swirled the cloche off the top of the pedestal. Underneath was the smokey Manhattan!</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/manhattan.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/manhattan.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Manhattan</div>
  </div>

  <p>It was seriously smokey. Even though I was only sat next to Hampton, my clothes smelt like a wood fire for the next day.</p>

  <p>The next modernist cocktail we got was the Black Truffle. It came with six tiny spoons. The spoons had a coconut foam/lime dust mixture on them. You were supposed to eat one of those, then drink the gin-based concoction. Those spoons were amazing, and they went well with the drink. The drink had elderflower in it, too, so I loved it.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/black-truffle.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/black-truffle.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Black Truffle</div>
  </div>

  <p>Next up, there was a Cedar. It came on a wood platter set up like a zen garden. There was a sprig of cedar in one corner, some cacao &#8220;soil&#8221; and chunks of pear. You dip the pear in the &#8220;soil,&#8221; and eat that before you drink. I didn&#8217;t get much from the food bit, but the drink (a gin-chamomile-pear thing) was clean and fresh.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/cedar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/cedar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Cedar</div>
  </div>

  <p>I think the weirdest drink of the night was the Spring Thaw. It came in a tiny glass surrounded by moss. The bartender came over and poured water (?) over the moss, and it started misting. I&#8217;m guessing there was perfumed dry ice in there somewhere – it smelled just like a spring forest.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/spring-thaw-mist.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/spring-thaw-mist.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Spring thawing all over the table</div>
  </div>

  <p>The cocktail itself was a gin-campari thing. It had a campari sorbet of some kind, and as you were drinking the sorbet melted into the rest. It&#8217;s a neat concept, but it was strange that the drink got more and more bitter as you went on.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/spring-thaw.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/spring-thaw.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The Spring Thaw cocktail itself</div>
  </div>

  <p>We also got a punch bowl, which I&#8217;d recommend if you&#8217;re tired of the pomp around the other cocktails.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">I love any kind of ceremony or ostentation around food and drink. There&#8217;s something fun about the process – in these cases, eating something special before you drink, or smelling a fog that surrounds your glass. So I&#8217;m already inclined to like a place like this – and I did. A lot. It&#8217;s definitely not cheap, though, and certainly not a casual after-work-drinks kinda place.</span></p>


  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">9.0</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Momofuku and Other Toronto Eats]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/16/daisho/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-16T10:15:28-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/16/daisho</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve enjoyed watching <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Chang">David Chang&rsquo;s</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Momofuku_(restaurants)">Momofuku</a> empire grow, but I&rsquo;ve never had the opportunity to eat at one of his restaurants. As he hasn&rsquo;t opened a restaurant in San Francisco, the closest I&rsquo;ve got is reading <a href="http://lky.ph/">Lucky Peach</a>. I was super excited to go to one of his restaurants in Toronto.</p>

<p>There are four Momofuku properties in Toronto – all housed in the same building. In order of increasing fanciness, they are Noodle Bar, Nikai (a cocktail bar), Daishō and Shōtō. The building is pretty cool – it almost looks like an Apple store with its glass exterior and giant Momofuku sign.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/momofuku.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/momofuku.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Momofuku sign</div>
</div>


<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toronto_International_Film_Festival">Toronto International Film Festival</a> is going on, and right next to the Momofuku building is the Shangri-la hotel. On its third-floor deck, there was a pre-premiere party for a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wild_(film)">new Reese Witherspoon film</a>. From our table we could see right into the pre-party and had a lot of fun figuring out what it was for. We saw <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Evans_(actor)">Chris Evans</a> there! But we didn&rsquo;t see Reese Witherspoon.</p>

<p>Anyway, onto the food. We were eating at Daishō, which has a bunch of smaller dishes plus some larger, 4-10 person plates if you want to do that. They also have a small, but interesting, cocktail list. I got a bijou and it was nicely done (although you couldn&rsquo;t really taste the Chartreuse).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/cocktail.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/cocktail.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Bijou and menu</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/whiskey-flight.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/whiskey-flight.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hampton got a whiskey flight</div>
</div>


<p>Momofuku is known for its buns, so we got some duck and shrimp versions. It was strange seeing the duck come in patty form – but it tasted absolutely amazing, so I didn&rsquo;t care.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/duck-bun.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/duck-bun.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Duck bun</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/shrimp-bun.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/shrimp-bun.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Shrimp bun</div>
</div>


<p>The steak tartare was made with such tender beef. They added enough yolk to keep it glossy, without it being too sloppy. Plus it has sunflower seeds in it which added some nice texture. One of the best tartares I&rsquo;ve had.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/tartare.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/tartare.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Steak tartare</div>
</div>


<p>The other popular thing on the menu is the ssäm (pronounced with a long &ldquo;a&rdquo;, like psalm). <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ssam">Ssäm</a> is a Korean dish whereby you wrap meat inside a large lettuce leaf. It&rsquo;s a make-your-own lettuce wrap kinda thing. We decided to go for the secreto ssäm, mainly because we didn&rsquo;t know what secreto was (turns out it&rsquo;s a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Iberian_pig">cut of pork</a>). It was really delicious!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/ssam.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/ssam.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Secreto Ssäm</div>
</div>


<p>We also ordered some crab cakes, which came out looking a lot more different than I thought. Turns out Korean-style crab cakes aren&rsquo;t patty-shaped. They&rsquo;re long tube-like things that aren&rsquo;t totally unlike crab sticks. They came in a spicy sauce, too.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crab-cakes.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crab-cakes.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Korean-style crab cakes</div>
</div>


<p>Despite being fit to burst at this point, we were recommended the crack pie. IT WAS AMAZING. That&rsquo;s about all I can say. If you have an opportunity, get it.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crack-pie.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crack-pie.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Crack pie</div>
</div>


<p>As well as Daishō, there were a bunch of other awesome places we ate at.</p>

<p><a href="http://guu-izakaya.com/sakabar">Guu Sakabar</a> is an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Izakaya">izakaya</a>-style bar/restaurant. They have a bunch of smaller dishes on the <a href="http://guu-izakaya.com/docs/sakabar_menu1.pdf">menu</a>, and you order a few each and share. They have a wide range of stuff, from standard (like takoyaki) to weird (udon carbonara?). My favourite was kabocha korokke – a pumpkin croquette thing with a boiled egg in the middle, served with a sauce that was kinda like thousand island dressing.</p>

<p>They had an Ontario-produced sake which I can&rsquo;t find on the menu but it was delicious.</p>

<p><a href="http://416snackbar.wordpress.com/">416 Snack Bar</a> is a hipster tapas-style place. They had chalkboard on the walls and don&rsquo;t offer you any cutlery. The best thing here was either the foie torchon or the steak tartare.</p>

<p>The other place I enjoyed was <a href="http://patriatoronto.com/">Patria</a>, a Spanish tapas restaurant (all the places we went to were tapas, it seems). They had great authentic Spanish-style food (even jamón Ibérico!) plus some tasty sangria. We got a cornish hen paella, which was weird but worked pretty well.</p>

<p>These restaurants barely scratch the surface of Toronto, I&rsquo;m sure. We&rsquo;ve eaten really well here, no doubt due to the excellent choices of our friends <a href="http://twitter.com/mferrier">Mike</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/melissaiscool">Melissa</a> who pretty much recommended/chose all of these places to eat at.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
