<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: The-journey-2014 | malrase]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/the-journey-2014/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-26T15:13:02-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Columbia Room]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/04/25/the-columbia-room/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-25T14:29:59-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/04/25/the-columbia-room</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was glad our friend had already been to <a href="http://columbiaroomdc.com/">The Columbia Room</a> and met us outside, otherwise I don&rsquo;t think we would have been able to find it. It&rsquo;s hidden in the back of an upscale dive bar called The Passenger on 7th St in D.C. Inside, it&rsquo;s tiny (I think there were ten seats) and sparsely-decorated (some apothecary-style bottles with herbs were behind the bar). The service, level of expertise from the bartenders, and the inventiveness of flavour pairings reminded me of the few Michelin-starred restaurants I&rsquo;ve been to. Except with liquor instead of food.</p>

<p>The set menu consists of three drinks and a couple of snacks, coming in at around $65 per person. Pricey, but worth it.</p>

<p>After being offered cold towels scented with cucumber (!), we started out with a rum and lemon-based punch served in a teacup. It tasted pretty much like iced tea – but, y'know, alcoholic. So better than regular iced tea.</p>

<p>The second drink, the Getaway, had two main ingredients: a black rum and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cynar">cynar</a> (<em>chee</em>-nar).</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/dc/getaway-ingredients.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Ingredients for the Getaway</div>
</div>


<p>Cynar is a dark brown artichoke-based liqueur. It has a number of other spices in it, so it&rsquo;s not like you&rsquo;re drinking artichoke juice or anything. Mixed with the dark rum, some salted bitters and a bit of lemon, and wow. With each sip you went through four or five different flavour profiles – acidity of the lemon, saltiness, herbs, molasses. It was extremely drinkable and all three of us had to pace ourselves so we didn&rsquo;t finish it in two gulps.</p>

<p>The Getaway was served with an artichoke (to pair with the cynar) and green olive tapenade-type thing. It was pretty tasty, but I wish there had been more of it. Or maybe I should have eaten more for dinner.</p>

<p>For last cocktail of the set, we had a choice. Either a cynar and grapefruit/blood orange soda <strong>or</strong> a cynar and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Akvavit">akvavit</a> combination. Two of us plumped for the cynar/aquavit drink – it tasted a lot like a negroni. The soda drink was refreshing and a nice end to the tasting.</p>

<p>As the previous cocktails were so good, we decided to stay for another one each. We asked the bartender for two gin-based drinks – one with citrus and one without.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/dc/dry-martini.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Dry Martini</div>
</div>


<p>Hampton got a dry martini with Plymouth gin. It was pretty delicious. The bartender recommended Plymouth as a good go-to gin that mixes well with other ingredients.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/dc/last-word-ingredients.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Last Word Ingredients</div>
</div>


<p>I received a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Word_(cocktail)">Last Word</a> – Tanqueray 10 gin, Luxardo <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maraschino">maraschino liqueur</a>, lime juice and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chartreuse_(liqueur)">Chartreuse</a>. I had been drinking Chartreuse the previous Saturday, both neat and in a Chartreuse gimlet. I liked it a lot, so I was pretty excited it came up in the cocktail the bartender made for me here.</p>

<p>The Maraschino liqueur was strange. I&rsquo;m familiar with Luxardo-style maraschino cherries, so was expecting the liqueuer to be a deep purple syrup. However, it looked and tasted more like a simple syrup that had a hint of cherry flavour.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/dc/last-word-cocktail.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Last Word</div>
</div>


<p>Mixing all of them together was amazing. The freshness of the limes worked well with the herbal qualities of the gin and the Chartreuse. The Maraschino added a touch of sweetness to round it all out. Apparently, the bartender likes to put a little more gin compared to normal Last Word-style drinks, which is what he said gives his the edge over the competition.</p>

<p>I highly recommend visiting this place if you&rsquo;re in the D.C. area. We managed to make reservations a couple of weeks in advance for a Wednesday night. I hear the building is being taken over soon – although I assume they will be moving to a new location.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Packing for Seven Months in a Carry-on]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/04/22/carry-on-packing-for-seven-months/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-22T13:09:09-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/04/22/carry-on-packing-for-seven-months</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A <a href="http://twitter.com/melissaiscool">good friend</a> converted us to <a href="http://melissadreamsofsushi.com/?p=7432">always packing carry-ons</a> when going on trips. It&rsquo;s far easier to travel with a carry-on – especially when taking low-cost airlines that charge to check luggage.</p>

<p>The longest we have spent living out of a carry-on has been about three months. The benefits definitely outweighed the negatives. If we ran out of clothes, we could often find laundry facilities. Anything we forgot could usually be bought locally. So, for this trip we took the plunge and aimed to pack only a carry-on for seven months of travel.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s easier to pack for seven months in a carry-on when you&rsquo;re travelling during summer. No hats, scarves, gloves, or bulky coats are necessary. Of course, when we make it back to the East Coast it will be autumn and may be a little chilly. At that point, we can easily buy warmer clothes (as <a href="https://twitter.com/hcatlin/status/458307183470342144">Hampton pointed out</a>, clothes tend to be more expensive in Europe).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Choosing things to pack was pretty simple. I went through T-shirts I liked and grabbed them. One pair of darker jeans (that could work in a nicer restaurant) is useful. Shirts that look good without needing to be ironed are helpful if you need a dressier option and don&rsquo;t have an iron handy.</p>

<p>I also made sure to pack some older clothes, too, so I could throw things out if necessary.</p>

<p>Getting it into the suitcase was simple by rolling everything up. If you&rsquo;re not familiar with <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/slideshow/2010/05/06/business/businessspecial/20100506-pack-ss.html?_r=0">the &ldquo;roll&rdquo; style of packing</a>, it&rsquo;s excellent and allows you to fit a lot more in a suitcase (and keep things mostly wrinkle-free).</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/side-one.JPG">
  <div class="alt">First side</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/side-two.JPG">
  <div class="alt">Second side</div>
</div>


<p>The two images above contain about two weeks' worth of clothes.Making sure I wear bulky items when travelling means that the lighter versions (e.g. a lighter jacket, thinner shoes) fit in the suitcase. The contact lenses should be <a href="https://www.tsa.gov/traveler-information/medically-necessary-liquids">allowed as medical liquids</a>.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the full list:</p>

<ul>
<li>15 T-shirts</li>
<li>1 polo shirt</li>
<li>3 shirts</li>
<li>11 regular socks</li>
<li>7 ankle socks</li>
<li>16 pairs of underwear</li>
<li>2 pairs of trousers</li>
<li>1 pair of shorts</li>
<li>1 pair of swimming trunks</li>
<li>2 pairs of shoes (one boot-like, one light and foldable)</li>
<li>2 jackets (one light, one heavy)</li>
<li>1 toothbrush</li>
<li>1 razor</li>
<li>1 pair of sunglasses</li>
<li>90 pairs of contact lenses</li>
<li>1 international adaptor</li>
</ul>


<p>Our laptop bags will have toiletries (shaving cream, toothpaste and deodorant only – everything else we can buy as we need it), our laptops, kindles, and chargers.</p>

<p>And there you go. That&rsquo;s how you pack for seven months in only carry-on.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
