<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Kreuzberg | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/kreuzberg/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-12T14:31:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Markhalle Neun and Sage]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/20/markhalle-neun-and-sage/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-20T08:43:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/20/markhalle-neun-and-sage</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s a great indoor market called <a href="http://www.markthalleneun.de/">Markthalle Neun</a> that&rsquo;s about <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/preview?ie=UTF-8&amp;fb=1&amp;cid=10953314371184579858&amp;q=Markthalle+Neun+GmbH&amp;ei=3sHwU4q8BLDQ7Aa4tYDgCg&amp;ved=0CL0BEPwSMA4">a block away from where we&rsquo;re staying</a>. It&rsquo;s not a traditional market in that there are people selling stuff every day. On a normal day there&rsquo;s a handful of stands or mini-kitchens selling locally-made food, wine, and other stuff.</p>

<p>On Thursdays, however, there&rsquo;s a &ldquo;street food&rdquo; gathering where a lot more people show up. All the booths are filled with people selling their food – everything from pancakes to samosas to steamed buns. There&rsquo;s also a couple of food trucks outside, too. It gets incredibly packed, but it&rsquo;s a lot of fun.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Street food Thursdays</div>
</div>


<p>There&rsquo;s also a Sunday morning &ldquo;breakfast market,&rdquo; which has more of a focus on breakfast foods.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve been to a couple of these events, but mostly we go on weekdays for lunch. There&rsquo;s such a wide variety of food there it&rsquo;s difficult to go wrong. Anyway, I&rsquo;ve taken pictures of pretty much everything I&rsquo;ve eaten there, so this will mainly be a bunch of pictures of delicious food.</p>

<p>The best thing I&rsquo;ve had so far has been the barbeque from <a href="http://www.bigstuff.de/">Big Stuff Smoked BBQ</a>. It blew away most of the BBQ I&rsquo;ve had in the USA.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bbq-ribs.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bbq-ribs.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">BBQ rib sandwich</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bbq-pork.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bbq-pork.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">BBQ pork belly sandwich</div>
</div>


<p>There was a Vietnamese stall that did rice-stuffed rolls and some steamed buns.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bun.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bun.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Steamed bun with pretty much EVERYTHING inside</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-rolls.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-rolls.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Delicious rolls with rice and meat inside</div>
</div>


<p>There was a great vegetarian burger place. We accidentally went there because it had the shortest queue. Then we found out it was vegetarian, almost left, but stuck with it. The burger was so good! I think it was tofu or something, but it was mainly tasty cause they slathered it in peanut sauce.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-veggie-burger.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-veggie-burger.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The best veggie-burger I&#8217;ve ever had</div>
</div>


<p>The next place I went to, I had their veggie-burger but it sucked, so I went back to eating all meat all the time.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m English so I love savoury pies. What luck! There was a pie place in the market. I got a cheese and mince one and it was SO GOOD. I would eat ten more right now.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-pie.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-pie.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Cheese and mince pie (note: not <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mince_pie">that kind of mince pie</a>, which would probably be gross with cheese in it)</div>
</div>


<p>If you don&rsquo;t like pies (like Hampton), you can get a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reuben_sandwich">reuben sandwich</a>! It had pastrami on it. Apparently this guy from Portland moved to Berlin and was upset he couldn&rsquo;t get decent pastrami&hellip; so he opened a deli!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-reuben.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-reuben.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Reuben sandwich</div>
</div>


<p>Don&rsquo;t fancy savoury items? Well there&rsquo;s a tonne of sweet stuff, too. There&rsquo;s a great waffle place.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-waffles.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-waffles.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Making waffles</div>
</div>


<p>Usually I&rsquo;m not the biggest fan of waffles, but these were so good. Crisp on the outside and moist on the inside. Oh, and covered in caramel sauce.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-waffle-caramel.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-waffle-caramel.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">My waffle</div>
</div>


<p>The waffle place also did some crazy ice-creams&hellip;</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-icecream.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-icecream.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Raspberry and basil</div>
</div>


<p>And there was a lady selling ice-lollies (or &ldquo;popsicles&rdquo;).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-lollipop.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-lollipop.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Buttermilk and lemon</div>
</div>


<p>OK, that&rsquo;s all my Markthalle photos. We did eat some fancy food as well – at <a href="http://www.sage-restaurant.de/cms/">Sage</a>. I really like the interior of this place. It&rsquo;s in a warehouse and has lots of industrial touches – like giant chains hanging from the ceiling. But it&rsquo;s also bright due to the large windows and white canvases on the walls.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Sage interior</div>
</div>


<p>We went for a four-course Chef&rsquo;s surprise menu. It was a great choice – full of interesting flavours and ingredients that I&rsquo;d never come across before. Here&rsquo;s some pictures:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-octopus.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-octopus.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Octopus, potato foam, chorizo</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-monkfish.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-monkfish.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Monkfish, black potato purée</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-beef.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-beef.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Beef, spinach polenta, mushrooms, spiced pumpkin</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-icecream.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-icecream.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Lemon sorbet, chocolate-covered marscapone ice-cream</div>
</div>


<p>It was super-tasty and you should definitely go if you&rsquo;re in the area. Get an apéritif on the beach beforehand!</p>

<p>Our time in Berlin is almost over, and next we&rsquo;ll be heading off to Stockholm for <a href="http://hybridconf.net/">HybridConf</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drinking Around Kreuzberg]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/17/drinking-around-kreuzberg/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-17T09:39:07-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/17/drinking-around-kreuzberg</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I say &ldquo;around Kreuzberg,&rdquo; that&rsquo;s a little misleading as we haven&rsquo;t really managed to explore the whole area. Berlin is pretty massive – more like London than Paris or New York. It&rsquo;s not that easy to walk to other areas (although we did take a nice stroll over to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friedrichshain">Friedrichshain</a> a couple of times).</p>

<p>As you are probably aware, Hampton and I scouted out as many cocktail bars as we could as soon as we arrived. For the past two weeks, we&rsquo;ve been slowly venturing further from our apartment to test out other places. Here&rsquo;s our list (and <a href="https://mapsengine.google.com/map/edit?mid=zSa_dTkSRnX0.kH2Fqz02A-M4">a handy map</a>).</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not sure why, but there&rsquo;s a cocktail bar named after a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Muir">noted American environmentalist</a>: <a href="http://johnmuirberlin.com/">John Muir</a>. To be honest, I only knew about him because I&rsquo;ve made a couple of day trips up to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muir_Woods_National_Monument">Muir Woods</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-outside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-outside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Entrance to John Muir</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Bar area – it&#8217;s a little dark as it&#8217;s in a half-cellar</div>
</div>


<p>The inside is all exposed brick, with a couple of naturalist touches (like some stuffed animals). It&rsquo;s nice and cosy (but the bathrooms are disco-themed??). They have a regularly-rotating drinks menu and their custom drinks are <em>really</em> good. I got the Lightning Bug, which was a citrus-gin thing with some other delicious extras (honey and lillet, I think?).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-drinks.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/muir-drinks.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Lightning bug and a manhattan</div>
</div>


<p>I tried a couple of other cocktails on offer, and they were also excellent. It was strange that it never seemed to get too busy. Most people ordered beer or wine, and I wanted to shout at them because the cocktails were so tasty. Overall: 8.0/10</p>

<p>Not far from John Muir is <a href="">Kirk Bar</a>. Again, not really sure why it&rsquo;s named that. Star Trek reference, maybe? Nerds.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/kirk-bar.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/kirk-bar.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside Kirk Bar</div>
</div>


<p>The inside is pretty bad-ass. It has a real crumbling old-timey feel, with a patina most bars wish they could get. Beautiful cornicing and high ceilings. The first time we went, I was pretty drunk so I&rsquo;m not sure what I ordered. I think it was a gin sour – but I remember thinking it was good.</p>

<p>When we came back, I was more sober and remembered my drink order – a Hemingway sour. It was the same as a regular gin sour, but with grenadine added. (I thought Hemingway liked rum?)</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/kirk-sours.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/kirk-sours.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">On the left, a gin sour (?), on the right, Hemingway Sour</div>
</div>


<p>Overall: 7.6/10</p>

<p>I talked briefly about <a href="http://www.sage-restaurant.de/cms/">Sage</a> <a href="/blog/2014/08/13/berlin-how-do-you-think-it-feels/">in my previous post</a> – it&rsquo;s the bar on the water. Well, there&rsquo;s also a restaurant in a warehouse building just inland from the beach area. I&rsquo;ll talk about the food in another post, but I had a pretty amazing cocktail there. It was called the London garden and looked like a juice drink I&rsquo;d find in San Francisco.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/sage-london.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/sage-london.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">London Garden</div>
</div>


<p>It wasn&rsquo;t too sweet or too savoury, and it had the right amount of texture to it. It was so much more drinkable than those juices you find. Maybe it&rsquo;s the fact that it had alcohol in it or maybe it&rsquo;s&hellip; no, it was definitely the alcohol. Overall: 7.2/10</p>

<p><a href="http://www.homes-berlin.de/">Homes</a> was a little further away from our place, but we&rsquo;d read good reviews so we made the trek. It was decorated more like a casual coffee shop than a bar – it was very open, with low seating and &ldquo;cool&rdquo; murals on the walls.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/homes-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/homes-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside Homes</div>
</div>


<p>I guess it&rsquo;s a little unfair for me to be that dismissive – we were there pretty early for Berlin drinking time. Berlin is a very late city – people only consider going to a bar or club at midnight. I&rsquo;m happy to be in bed by then. It also means that bars are pretty empty around 7pm which means (yay) there&rsquo;s usually little wait but (boo) we&rsquo;re usually the only people in there.</p>

<p>Anyway, the drinks at Homes were passable. I got a gin-cacao-lillet thing that tasted way better than the ingredients list suggested.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/homes-chocolate.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/drinks/homes-chocolate.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Gin-cacao-lillet</div>
</div>


<p>I was a little underwhelmed. Overall: 6.5/10</p>

<p><a href="http://www.yelp.de/biz/schwarze-traube-berlin">Schwarze Traube</a> (&ldquo;black grape&rdquo;) was our first cocktail bar when we arrived. It&rsquo;s less than a block away from where we&rsquo;re staying and it had really good reviews. I was pretty excited.</p>

<p>The door has a sign saying you have to &ldquo;knock and smile&rdquo; to enter, which I did. The bartender was <em>not</em> happy to see us. She kind of pointed at some seats before going back behind the bar. The place is pretty small – two or three tiny rooms. The decor is great, though, with lots of fraying antique chairs and side-tables.</p>

<p>The bartender came over and told us they had a gin-based special drink. I ordered that one, and Hampton ordered a manhattan (which elicited a big sigh from the bartender). I like the idea of a no-menu, bartender-curated drinks list but only if the bartender is nice. Anyway, the drinks came after about fifteen minutes (which was weird, as we were the only people in there). They were really bloody good, and served in equisite, delicate glassware.</p>

<p>After we&rsquo;d finished our drinks, we had to wait another twenty minutes of the bartender disappearing and/or ignoring our requests for the bill. Great cocktails, but not really worth the lacklustre service. Overall: 5.6</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Berlin: How Do You Think It Feels]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/13/berlin-how-do-you-think-it-feels/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-13T08:17:16-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/13/berlin-how-do-you-think-it-feels</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aIofRTmTYVc">Title from Lou Reed&rsquo;s album, Berlin</a>)</p>

<p>Berlin doesn&rsquo;t feel European, and it&rsquo;s not quite like anywhere else Hampton and I have visited. It doesn&rsquo;t really seem to fit any classification, there&rsquo;s so much about it that&rsquo;s unique. I get that other cities have unique qualities. Paris has&hellip; <em>Parisian</em> things about it that make it unique – but it still feels European. Berlin does not. Maybe it&rsquo;s because  of its recent tumultuous history. Maybe it&rsquo;s because the idea of &ldquo;Europeanness&rdquo; includes Paris, and London, and Rome, but somehow left out Berlin. For whatever reason, it&rsquo;s an alluring city that we made a point of returning to.</p>

<p>Last time we visited Berlin, we stayed in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prenzlauer_Berg">Prenzlauer Berg</a>, a hip ex-East Berlin neighbourhood in the north of the city. This time, we chose to stay in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kreuzberg">Kreuzberg</a>.</p>

<p>Along with Prenzlauer Berg and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friedrichshain">Friedrichshain</a>, Kreuzberg is considered to be the trendier, less-polished side of the city. Although technically in West Berlin during the separation of Germany, Kreuzberg was on the eastern edge of the city, so was relatively underdeveloped. Since the fall of the Berlin Wall, all three neighbourhoods have undergone varying levels of gentrification.</p>

<p>Coming from the obvious beauty of Prague or Amsterdam, Berlin was a little brutal. On our block, there are multiple featureless, indistinguishable mid-1970s apartment complexes. They&rsquo;re covered in graffiti and look pretty drab.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/kreuzberg-apartment.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/kreuzberg-apartment.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Typical Kreuzberg apartment building</div>
</div>


<p>So far, I&rsquo;m probably not painting a great picture of Berlin, am I? The thing that really draws Hampton and me to the city is the people and the atmosphere. I&rsquo;d call it artistic or care-free; I&rsquo;m sure an American could equally describe it as entrepreneurial. Confused? Let me try and describe an example.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re staying just off the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spree">Spree</a>. It&rsquo;s a little industrial along our side of the river, with brick warehouses and lots of gates. We saw some place recommended on FourSquare along the river, but weren&rsquo;t that sure where it was. After walking through what looked like a gate to an industrial estate, we saw a couple of shipping containers stacked on top of each other with a 1970s car on top.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar-entry.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar-entry.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Shipping container garden</div>
</div>


<p>As you continue walking towards the bank of the river, you see a makeshift beach.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Sage Bar – a beach</div>
</div>


<p>And there&rsquo;s this wonderful bar, hidden away, popular at all times of the day. Kids are running around playing in their sand as their tattooed, mid-thirties parents sip an Aperol and soda. There&rsquo;s grey-haired couples drinking tall beers, reading books. And right across the river is one of the longest <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Side_Gallery">still-standing stretches of the Berlin Wall</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar-view.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/sage-bar-view.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">View over the Spree and the Berlin Wall</div>
</div>


<p>Berlin is such a strange mixture of rule-following, energy, and laissez-faireness. People are frenetic and excited on the streets, playing loud music and drinking and rushing to the next bar&hellip; before languishing the next morning over a three-hour brunch. It takes a while to get used to, but it&rsquo;s something that I find very energising and disruptive.</p>

<p>One of the strangest moments so far was going for karaoke with the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Travis_CI">Travis CI</a> folks. The karaoke bar was just across the river from Kreuzberg, in Friedrichshain. To get there, we walked along the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oberbaum_Bridge">Oberbaum bridge</a>, which used to be an East-West border crossing.</p>

<p>We then walked past a stretch of the Berlin Wall, which was turned into an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Side_Gallery">open-air gallery</a> soon after the unification of Germany.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/east-side-gallery.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/east-side-gallery.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The East Side Gallery</div>
</div>


<p>The gallery itself is really neat, and on a separate occasion we took a longer stroll along it.</p>

<p>Anyway, we got to karaoke, sang a few songs, drank a few beers. Then someone put on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%22Heroes%22_(David_Bowie_song)">&ldquo;Heroes&rdquo;</a> by David Bowie. Recorded in the 1970s in Berlin, it&rsquo;s about two lovers who can&rsquo;t be together: one is from East Berlin, and one is from West Berlin.</p>

<p>And there we were, singing about the horror of the wall, in a karaoke bar about 500ft away, having just crossed an ex-border crossing.</p>

<p>Above all, Berlin is wonderful and strange.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
