<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Usa | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/usa/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-23T11:36:50-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drinking Spots in Jacksonville]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/12/15/drinking-spots-in-jacksonville/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-15T12:05:17-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/12/15/drinking-spots-in-jacksonville</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jacksonville,_Florida">Jacksonville</a>, Hampton&rsquo;s hometown, is pretty sprawling. As such, it&rsquo;s difficult to get to different areas of the city without driving. Thankfully, Uber recently arrived so you can drink and get home safely (although with all the recent controversy, I don&rsquo;t know how comfortable you might be with using Uber).</p>

<p>The main areas of town we went to were Downtown, San Marco, and Avondale.</p>

<p>In Downtown, I&rsquo;d highly recommend <a href="http://www.dosgatosjax.com/">Dos Gatos</a>. The cocktails are great and reasonably-priced.</p>

<p>San Marco has <a href="http://www.grapeandgrainexchange.com/">Grape and Grain Exchange</a>, with the Parlour in the back. Grape and Grain Exchange is an up-scale package store. They have a great range of liquors there – and we got some to drink at home. However it&rsquo;s worth grabbing a drink at the bar, too. The atmosphere is a little bright – it is primarily a shop, after all – but the cocktails are good. In the back there&rsquo;s the Parlour, which is a speakeasy-style bar. The service is pretty slow but they have some decent seasonal cocktails.</p>

<p>Avondale&rsquo;s top spot for drinking is <a href="http://www.mojobbq.com/mojo-no-4-urban-bbq-whiskey-bar">Mojo Nº4</a>. They have an extensive range of whiskey cocktails, all of which were tasty. Their Vieux Carré was great.</p>

<p>If Mojos is packed (and it often is, so get there early), try the <a href="http://mellowmushroom.com/store/avondale-jax">Mellow Mushroom</a> just across the street. Their pizza is pretty good, too, if you&rsquo;re hungry.</p>

<p>All in all, there&rsquo;s a few good spots around town if you&rsquo;re looking for a decent cocktail. Just make sure you have a taxi number handy to get home!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Disney Experience]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/11/29/the-disney-experience/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-29T06:31:49-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/11/29/the-disney-experience</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For our five year anniversary, we decided to head down to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walt_Disney_World">Walt Disney World</a> for a few days. I had never stayed &ldquo;on property&rdquo; (i.e. in a Disney-branded hotel) before, so we opted to stay in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disney%27s_Port_Orleans_Resort">French Quarter New Orleans</a>. It&rsquo;s priced in the middle of the pack – not as expensive as the Grand Floridian or the Contemporary, but not as cheap as the All-Star resorts. (See a handy table on the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walt_Disney_World#On-site_Disney_resorts">Wikipedia page</a>.)</p>

<p>We also wanted to get our hands on the new Disney <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MyMagic%2B#MagicBand">MagicBand</a>. It&rsquo;s an all-in-one ticket to the parks, key to your room, and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disney%27s_Fastpass">FastPass</a>. We were really excited about getting them. You customise them online and they come in the mail.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/band-box.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/band-box.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Magic Band box</div>
</div>


<p>The packaging reminded me of an Apple product – it was uncluttered and put the product up front.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/band-in-box.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/band-in-box.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside the box</div>
</div>


<p>The bands even had our names on the inside in case they got mixed up.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/band-behind.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/band-behind.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside of the band</div>
</div>


<p>Staying on-site also gives you the opportunity to take the Disney buses from hotels to the parks. You don&rsquo;t need to worry about the hellish carpark at the end of the day. We decided to do the Disney dining plan, too – one snack, one quick meal, and one sit-down meal per day.</p>

<p>We checked into the hotel, and although the surroundings were nice, the room was disappointing. It was laid out exactly like a motel – a sink area you can see as you walk in the door, a curtain to separate it from the rest of the room. It seemed like that could be a useful layout for families, but it didn&rsquo;t have the &ldquo;magical&rdquo; feeling I was expecting – especially for the price we were paying. I couldn&rsquo;t help but compare it to the far better Lowes Royal Pacific Resort at <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_Orlando">Universal</a>, where we stayed the previous week.</p>

<p>We were there for four days – with one day in each of the four WDW parks. On our first day, we headed to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epcot">Epcot</a> to catch the end of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epcot_International_Food_%26_Wine_Festival">Food and Wine Festival</a>. Held every autumn, they put up extra food stands around the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epcot#World_Showcase">World Showcase</a> representing different countries/cultures.</p>

<p>Anyway, as Epcot is one of the parks where you can drink, we decided to take advantage of the Disney bus system. Here&rsquo;s a pro-tip: <strong>don&rsquo;t use the Disney bus system</strong>. Waiting at our hotel&rsquo;s bus stop, was awful. Three or four buses for the same park would go past, and no passengers would get on. When our bus did come by, it was packed. After about fifteen minutes&#8217; wait for the bus, it was another fifteen minutes to get to the park. Then you&rsquo;re dropped off quite far from the entrance, so there&rsquo;s some extra walking. It was <strong>not</strong> worth it. In the Disney vs. Universal battle, the walkable distance from the parks to the resort hotels makes Universal a much more convenient experience.</p>

<p>Our day at Epcot was a lot of fun, though. Spending a whole day at Epcot allowed us to wander through the World Showcase. We managed to walk through all the countries – into the back areas and shops, which tended to be empty. The amount of detail is incredible. It also helps that some of the countries (such as France and Germany) have wine. That kept us in a good mood.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/epcot-drinking.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/epcot-drinking.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Wine at Epcot</div>
</div>


<p>We did Hollywood Studios the next day, then the Magic Kingdom. I was blown away by how busy the Magic Kingdom was – it was a Wednesday in the off-season and even high-throughput rides like Pirates of the Caribbean or the Haunted Mansion were at 50-minute queue times.</p>

<p>Animal Kingdom we left for the final day. They&rsquo;re apparently undergoing a lot of expansion, and we wanted to check it out before <a href="http://disneyparks.disney.go.com/blog/2014/01/construction-begins-for-avatar-inspired-land-at-disneys-animal-kingdom/">Avatar land opens</a>. We rode <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expedition_Everest">Expedition Everest</a> a couple of times – it&rsquo;s a great ride, but the only must-do at Animal Kingdom.</p>

<p>Two other disappointing things: the dining package and the FastPass options on the MagicBand. We got the standard dining package which, as I mentioned above, covers a snack, quick serve meal, and a sit-down meal. We booked it through Disney – as we were staying there three nights, we assumed the package would cover four days. Unfortunately, that&rsquo;s not the case – so be aware of that.</p>

<p>Also, the sit-down meal gives you two courses. However those two courses are <em>only</em> the entrée and dessert. You can&rsquo;t switch the dessert for an appetiser. That kinda sucked for us as neither of us really eat dessert.</p>

<p>We used two of our &ldquo;sit-down&rdquo; credits on <a href="https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/dining/grand-floridian-resort-and-spa/citricos/">Citricos</a>, the fancy restaurant in the Grand Floridian. I&rsquo;ve got to say – the overall experience was a little strange. The food was top-notch, and you could see the Magic Kingdom fireworks from the main dining hall. But the drinks were terrible and there were mostly families there – so not particularly romantic or anything. Can&rsquo;t really complain about families, though, it being Disney and all that.</p>

<p>The best thing to do if you <em>do</em> get the deal is grab a Starbucks coffee at either the Magic Kingdom or Epcot. It counts as a snack – no matter how many extra espresso shots you get. Pretty neat.</p>

<p>FastPass is the way you skip lines at Disney. You used to get a card with a specific return time on it, but now you pre-arrange three rides you want to do at specific times. Staying on Disney property <em>does not</em> give you more than three. Everyone gets that. Compare with Universal, where if you stay on property you get an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_Express_Pass">Express Pass</a> &ldquo;free,&rdquo; and it works any number of times for all designated rides.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t think we&rsquo;ll be staying at a Disney resort any time soon. If we do, I think it would have to be one with better transit options (i.e. one on the monorail). Driving to the parks is a far better option than the bus. I just don&rsquo;t see any real benefit that staying on-property offers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halloween Horror Nights 24]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/11/18/halloween-horror-nights/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-18T07:03:17-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/11/18/halloween-horror-nights</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halloween_Horror_Nights">Halloween Horror Nights</a> (also known as &ldquo;HHN&rdquo;) is an annual even put on by the Universal Studios resort in Florida. On select evenings for some of September and most of October, the park is transformed into a halloween scare-park.</p>

<p>There are usually eight or so haunted houses built in soundstages. These will be themed around something, and you walk through decorated rooms while loud noises play and actors jump out at you. There are also scare zones – areas of the park usually just for walking between rides. In these, there will be a few props around a theme, plus some scare actors who move amongst the crowds.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/entrance.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/entrance.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Universal Studios&#8217; Entrance during Halloween Horror Nights</div>
</div>


<p>This year&rsquo;s event was a blast. We were worried that attending on 31st October (Halloween itself), <strong>and</strong> because it was a Friday this year, the queues would be incredibly long. We bought the express pass (an extra cost on top of the regular cost) but we were still unsure as to whether we&rsquo;d be stuck in two-hour-plus lines to see the houses. The express pass often only cuts the regular lines down by half.</p>

<p>So, we implemented a plan laid out in <a href="http://www.orlandoinformer.com/universal/halloween-horror-nights-2014/">Orlando Informer</a> – by far the best resource to look at if you&rsquo;re thinking of visiting HHN. The trick to HHN is that you can get early entry <em>if you have a ticket for Universal Studios that day</em>.</p>

<p>The park closes at 5pm on HHN nights. Around 4:45pm, the staff set up areas of the park where you can sit and wait until HHN begins. The official start time of HHN is 6:30pm. However you&rsquo;re often let out of the areas closer to 5:45pm. That&rsquo;s a good chunk of time to explore houses before people are let in.</p>

<p>The best area to wait is in New York at Finnegans, an Irish pub. It&rsquo;s packed in there, but we got some drinks and took them outside. We put our names in for a table (it was a 40-minute wait, but we thought we&rsquo;d chance it just in case). At about 5:15pm we sat down and ate a quick salad before leaving the &ldquo;pen&rdquo; and heading into the event.</p>

<p>The Orlando Informer article gives some great advice – head to the houses first, then do the scare zones. The lines for two of the most popular mazes – <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Walking_Dead_(TV_series)">The Walking Dead</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_vs._Predator_(film)">Alien vs Predator</a> – were 20 minutes, which was great! We did those in quick succession.</p>

<p>The Walking Dead was touted as the largest house they&rsquo;d done – and it was filled with scare actors. Overall it was entertaining but unmemorable. There was one great scene in a forest, where I truly felt like zombies were coming at me from all sides. But apart from that, it seemed like a bunch of generic zombie scenes. Maybe I wasn&rsquo;t paying attention to season 4 enough?</p>

<p>Alien vs Predator did a great job of putting you in the <a href="http://avp.wikia.com/wiki/Weyland-Yutani">Weyland-Yutani</a> corporation as the Aliens take over and Predators are brought in to control them. At least, that&rsquo;s what I think the gist of the house was – it wasn&rsquo;t incredibly clear. I&rsquo;m an Alien fan, so I mostly delighted in the incredible puppet animatronics they had. Plus the ending – crawling through a narrow air-duct with an Alien waiting at the end – was an exhilarating finish.</p>

<p>We headed over to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halloween_(1978_film)">Halloween</a> house, which was over at the other end of the park. Here&rsquo;s another pro-tip: if the regular queue is pretty short, don&rsquo;t bother using your express pass. You can only use your express pass once per house. When we first went to the Halloween house, the queue was only 5 minutes – definitely not worth wasting our express on.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/halloween.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/halloween.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Front of the Halloween house</div>
</div>


<p>The house had every major scene from the 1978 classic. It was a lot of fun entering the (almost clichéd) house. The decor was perfectly 70s and I&rsquo;m glad we had a second pass at the house later on in the evening. There were a number of scenes we missed the first time around.</p>

<p>After these, we did the &ldquo;non-property&rdquo; houses. These are houses that aren&rsquo;t based on any existing intellectual property. This year, there were three: Giggles and Gore (about clowns), Roanoake (about cannibals), and Dollhouse of the Damned (about creepy dolls).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/dollhouse.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/dollhouse.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Front of Dollhouse of the Damned</div>
</div>


<p>Once we&rsquo;d done those, we were free to wander around the scare zones and attend the shows (they have special halloween-only live shows during HHN). My favourite scare zone was based around <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Purge">The Purge</a>. Hampton and I both enjoyed the films, and the theme fits well with the New York area of Universal Studios.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/gone-purging.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/gone-purging.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;Gone Purging&#8221; sign in the New York area</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/purge-bus.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/purge-bus.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hampton supports our new founding fathers</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/flowers.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/flowers.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Signature blue flowers</div>
</div>


<p>We noticed all of the above while touring the park during the day. At night, they bring out some extra props, like this sign.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/purge-sign.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/purge-sign.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Enjoy the Purge!</div>
</div>


<p>The other scare zone I enjoyed was based around the reality show <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Face_Off_(TV_series)">Face Off</a>. Some of the most famous make-ups they&rsquo;ve had on the show were there.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/face-off-1.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/face-off-1.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">FaceOff scarecrow thing</div>
</div>


<p>It was cool seeing them, but the scare zone just turned into a photo opportunity. We were guilty, too – we stood in front of the couple of make-ups we enjoyed from the series and took some photos. So not that scary, but fun nonetheless.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/face-off-2.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/hhn24/face-off-2.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">FaceOff minotaur thing</div>
</div>


<p>Halloween Horror Nights isn&rsquo;t <em>that</em> scary. We&rsquo;ve found that smaller, local events are far scarier. Scare-actors at Universal Studios can&rsquo;t touch you. You move through the houses in a giant conga-line, rather than small groups.</p>

<p>With that said, Universal puts so much money into these houses that they&rsquo;re above and beyond anything you&rsquo;ll see at another horror event. The mazes are detailed and, for those based on films or TV shows, often amazingly accurate.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal Studios' London/Diagon Alley]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/11/13/universal-studios/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-13T11:47:30-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/11/13/universal-studios</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Orlando is a strange place. Knowing a number of people who live (and have lived) there, we&rsquo;re always instructed to explore the city. &ldquo;There&rsquo;s so much more than theme parks!&rdquo; we&rsquo;re told. And that&rsquo;s true! We explored a little last year – we were recording with Treehouse and found a couple of great places. <a href="https://www.facebook.com/hansonsshoerepair">Hanson&rsquo;s Shoe Repair</a> is a cool speakeasy hidden behind a downtown bar/club. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Winter_Park,_Florida">Winter Park</a> area seems neat, too – we had a great meal at the <a href="http://www.theravenouspig.com/">Ravenous Pig</a>.</p>

<p>But exploring Orlando as a city wasn&rsquo;t on the agenda during this trip. We had four days booked at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_Orlando">Universal Orlando</a>, probably our favourite theme park complex.</p>

<p>In particular, we were there for two things: visiting the London/Diagon Alley extension of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Wizarding_World_of_Harry_Potter_(Universal_Orlando_Resort)">The Wizarding World of Harry Potter</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halloween_Horror_Nights">Halloween Horror Nights</a>.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll talk about Halloween Horror Nights in another post. Here I&rsquo;ll sum up the new Harry Potter area in Universal Studios. The London/Diagon Alley extension opened <a href="http://www.themeparkinsider.com/flume/201407/4112/">earlier this summer</a>. In all, they&rsquo;ve done a very good job. You start in London – it looks like a bunch of generic London buildings stuck together. The most exciting one (for me) was the King&rsquo;s Cross replica.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/kings-x.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/kings-x.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">King&#8217;s Cross Station</div>
</div>


<p>I liked the fact that they used King&rsquo;s Cross (rather than the more gothic <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St_Pancras_railway_station">St Pancras station</a> that was used in the films). It&rsquo;s a really good replica of the station (it was my London terminus when we lived in Cambridge). The departure board has legitimate trains – I&rsquo;ve been through Finsbury Park many times.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/departure-board.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/departure-board.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Departure board</div>
</div>


<p>You can walk into Platform 9 &frac34; and catch the Hogwarts Express to Hogsmede (in Islands of Adventure).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/platform-934.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/platform-934.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Platform 9 3/4</div>
</div>


<p>The train ride is a lot of fun – the windows project your journey from London to Hogsmede. The train takes passengers back, with a different story, so make sure you ride it both ways. If you&rsquo;re short for time, we both preferred the London -> Hogsmede direction.</p>

<p>Diagon Alley itself is hidden behind an unassuming brick wall. So unassuming, we had to have it pointed out by a Universal employee. She saw our confused looks and whispered, &ldquo;You might want to check out that brick wall over there!&rdquo;</p>

<p>It opens up into a narrow alleyway with an imposing dragon perched at the far end. It&rsquo;s sat on top of Gringotts and it makes for a stunning visual introduction to the area.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/diagon-alley.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/diagon-alley.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Diagon Alley</div>
</div>


<p>Make sure to check out the side alleys – there&rsquo;s one to each side as you walk in. In particular, Nocturn Alley (on the left as you walk in) is a dark and spooky area where you can buy all the skull-shaped items you could ever dream of.</p>

<p>Anyway, onto the new ride: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_Potter_and_the_Escape_from_Gringotts">Escape from Gringotts</a>. We had high hopes – <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_Potter_and_the_Forbidden_Journey">The Forbidden Journey</a>, over in Hogsmede, is one of our favourite rides.</p>

<p>The line times are pretty hefty – we were lucky enough to get in pretty early on a Thursday with only 30 minutes to wait. For the rest of the weekend, it was at least 120 minutes. The queue area is neat – you walk into Gringotts and see the main banking area.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-entrance.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-entrance.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Entrance to Gringotts</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-hall.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-hall.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Main room</div>
</div>


<p>Along the hallway are animatronics of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magical_creatures_in_Harry_Potter#Goblins">goblin</a> bank tellers.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-men.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-men.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Goblin bankers</div>
</div>


<p>You walk past these into the vaults and back rooms of Gringotts.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-vaults.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/gringotts-vaults.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Gringotts vaults</div>
</div>


<p>There&rsquo;s a weird break in the queue where you have your photo taken. I don&rsquo;t know why they do this – it&rsquo;s just against a plain background. Maybe it&rsquo;s because they didn&rsquo;t want to put a camera on the ride? Not a clue. But there&rsquo;s more queuing after that.</p>

<p>Then you&rsquo;re put in a &ldquo;lift&rdquo; that takes you into the deepest vault area. You then walk <em>up</em> some stairs, grab some 3D goggles, and enter a mine-cart-like-thing. It looks a little like the one from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Revenge_of_the_Mummy">Revenge of the Mummy</a>.</p>

<p>The ride is mostly large 3D projections following some half-arsed story about Voldemort. It is not an enjoyable ride. It fails in a couple of ways. To begin with, there&rsquo;s very little use of the track as a rollercoaster – there are maybe two small drops in total. It&rsquo;s definitely not an exciting ride, and makes me wonder why they decided to use a rollercoaster-style track without utilising any rollercoaster features.</p>

<p>Also, the ride is essentially a series of short 3D films. The great thing about The Forbidden Journey (or the older <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Amazing_Adventures_of_Spider-Man">Spider-man ride</a>) was that they seamlessly blended real-life features (animatronics, props, forced perspective) with pre-done projected segments. The problem with Gringotts (and the recently-opened <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transformers:_The_Ride">Transformers: The Ride</a>) is that there&rsquo;s no inventiveness – you just move from one projection to the next, and that&rsquo;s the adventure.</p>

<p>Anyway, we were pretty disappointed. We wanted to ride it again to see if it improved on second ride, but with 120 minute queues we weren&rsquo;t willing to wait. The good news is that the rest of the area (and the Hogwarts Express to Hogsmede) was really fun – and that&rsquo;s enough reason to go.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[East Coast Road Trip: Part Three]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/11/03/east-coast-road-trip-part-three/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-03T07:57:55-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/11/03/east-coast-road-trip-part-three</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Driving through Virginia is great – mostly because it reminds me of England. Gently rolling hills, lots of farms, big oak trees.</p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlottesville,_Virginia">Charlottesville</a> was our first stop in Virginia. It&rsquo;s extremely beautiful and worth a visit – it&rsquo;s only a couple of hours to drive from Washington D.C. Just south of Charlottesville is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monticello">Monticello</a>, the residence of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Jefferson">Thomas Jefferson</a>. Compared with <a href="/blog/2014/10/28/east-coast-road-trip-part-two">the absurd cost to visit Biltmore</a>, Monticello is a steal – $25 per person. I&rsquo;d suggest booking in advance, especially on busy days. You can only go through the main part of the house as part of a guided tour – and those are every 15 minutes or so. It&rsquo;s nice to know when you need to show up.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/monticello-entrance.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/monticello-entrance.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Entrance to Monticello</div>
</div>


<p>The entrance to Monticello is at the bottom of a hill. It&rsquo;s got the usual visitor centre stuff – a gift shop, some small exhibits, a café, etc. All the stuff that you can&rsquo;t build next to the UNESCO-protected house.</p>

<p>You have two options for getting to the house itself – a five-minute bus ride or a fifteen-minute walk. We arrived about half an hour before our allotted tour and walked up. It&rsquo;s a great walk (although mostly uphill) and I&rsquo;d recommend doing it if you have the time/physical capability.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/monticello-walk.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/monticello-walk.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Walk up to Monticello</div>
</div>


<p>On the way up, you pass by the graveyard where Thomas Jefferson is buried.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/jefferson-grave.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/jefferson-grave.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Jefferson&#8217;s Grave</div>
</div>


<p>The grounds are expansive and the architecture of the complex is unique. There are a couple of terraces stretching along both sides of the house with servant quarters underneath. It&rsquo;s fun to wander around the outside a little. But be careful with your timing: the tours start far before their posted time. We arrived ten minutes before ours was due to start, and the group was already together and being told about the surrounding gardens.</p>

<p>The tour was equally interesting and overwhelming for me. I didn&rsquo;t know much about Thomas Jefferson – my British education wasn&rsquo;t focussed on American history. There were a lot of &ldquo;obvious&rdquo; facts that, for me, weren&rsquo;t so obvious. &ldquo;You all know that Jefferson and Adams had a fraught relationship,&rdquo; &ldquo;naturally you all know about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sally_Hemings">Sally Hemings</a>.&rdquo; I had to nudge Hampton and ask him to fill in missing details. So if you&rsquo;re not American (or didn&rsquo;t pay attention in history), I&rsquo;d recommend reading up a little on his life before you come.</p>

<p>The house had some interesting areas. The entrance hall was used by Jefferson as a museum of sorts to prove to visitors that the Americas were ecologically and culturally distinct from the rest of Europe. Jefferson&rsquo;s bed was in an alcove that split his bedroom from his office. You can&rsquo;t take pictures inside, so I don&rsquo;t have any images of this stuff. But I do have a goofy photo of us standing outside the back of the house.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/monticello.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/monticello.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;Back&#8221; of Monticello</div>
</div>


<p>It&rsquo;s really picturesque on the grounds, and it&rsquo;s easy to take gorgeous photos.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/monticello-reflection.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/monticello-reflection.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Reflection of Monticello</div>
</div>


<p>Afterwards, we drove through Charlottesville and briefly saw the Jefferson-designed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/University_of_Virginia">University of Virginia</a>.</p>

<p>That night we stayed in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Staunton,_Virginia">Staunton</a>. It&rsquo;s a small town with a quiet centre and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Woodrow_Wilson_Presidential_Library">Woodrow Wilson Presidential Library</a>. We grabbed a Priceline deal at the <a href="http://www.stonewalljacksonhotel.com/">Stonewall Jackson Hotel</a>, which despite its questionable name, was fairly decent.</p>

<p>We found a well-reviewed cocktail bar and restaurant called <a href="http://zynodoa.com/">Zynodoa</a>. It was packed at 7:30pm on a Tuesday. Its decor and cocktails wouldn&rsquo;t have been out of place in New York. The same went for its prices – the cheapest entrée was $25. So we decided to go somewhere that seemed a little lower-rent: a BBQ place called <a href="http://www.millstreetgrill.com/">Mill Street Grill</a> – it had great reviews so we were pretty excited.</p>

<p>I wish we&rsquo;d have stuck with Zynodoa. The entrées at Mill Street Grill were about the same price (~$25), and the menu reminded me of something out of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kitchen_Nightmares">Kitchen Nightmares</a>. You know how Gordon Ramsay always complains when a menu is too large or haphazard? This menu was exactly that. There was Italian food, steaks, salads, BBQ, seafood, sandwiches. Hampton couldn&rsquo;t decide what he wanted, so he asked our waitress to pick from one of three. She didn&rsquo;t ask something like &ldquo;Do you like pasta?&rdquo; – she said &ldquo;How hungry are you?&rdquo; A bad sign.</p>

<p>We got our entrées and they were fairly tasty, but definitely not worth the price tag (why is some small town in Virginia charging so much?). The decor was bizarre – they had a bunch of deflated star and moon balloons hanging from the ceiling, a stained-glass window and a bust of Elvis (!?) on the bar. I&rsquo;d avoid it if you&rsquo;re ever in Staunton.</p>

<p>The next day we drove to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexington,_Virginia">Lexington, VA</a> – an even tinier town whose main attraction is the two universities. We were there to see <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Washington_and_Lee_University">Washington &amp; Lee</a>, where Hampton&rsquo;s father and brother both studied.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/washington-and-lee.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/washington-and-lee.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Washington & Lee</div>
</div>


<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lee_Chapel">Lee Chapel</a> is opposite the main buildings of the university, and we were lucky enough to catch a historian giving a short tour of the chapel explaining its history.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/lee-chapel.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/lee-chapel.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Lee Chapel</div>
</div>


<p>Inside it&rsquo;s all white. There are two portraits above the stage – one of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Washington">George Washington</a> and one of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_E._Lee">Robert E. Lee</a>. I found the Washington one amusing as he&rsquo;s in his British Army uniform. It&rsquo;s by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Willson_Peale">Charles Willson Peale</a>, and I had to get a photo of it.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/washington-british.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/washington-british.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">George Washington in his British Army getup</div>
</div>


<p>In the back of the chapel is a statue of Lee. It&rsquo;s not a tomb – he&rsquo;s actually buried underneath the chapel in a crypt.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/lee-statue.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/lee-statue.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Recumbent statue of Lee</div>
</div>


<p>They also have a reconstruction of his office under the chapel. Right outside is buried Lee&rsquo;s beloved horse, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Traveller_(horse)">Traveller</a></p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/traveller.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/traveller.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Traveller&#8217;s grave</div>
</div>


<p>Visiting Washington &amp; Lee was a nice detour on our trip. I&rsquo;ve heard a lot about it from Hampton&rsquo;s father, and it was nice to see that.</p>

<p>A brief aside: I&rsquo;m still not comfortable with the promotion – if not glorification – of Confederate generals that occurs in the South. I&rsquo;ve heard various justifications on numerous occasions. I understand that Lee <em>himself</em> didn&rsquo;t agree with slavery, but had to go with what his home state of Virginia wanted. However it still feels wrong. And it&rsquo;s still jarring when I see names like Stonewall Jackson or Robert E. Lee on schools or highways.</p>

<p>We made a brief family-history stop on the way there. I&rsquo;ll probably write a longer blog post about this in the future, as it might be handy for some Marshall descendants to know about. In short, we visited <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Happy_Creek,_Virginia">Happy Creek</a>. One of Hampton&rsquo;s family lineages is the Marshall family. They owned a property in Virginia called Happy Creek which, around 1912, burned down. Here&rsquo;s the ruins:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/happy-creek.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/happy-creek.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Happy Creek ruins</div>
</div>


<p>Nearby, there&rsquo;s the Marshall family graveyard.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/marshall-grave.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/virginia/marshall-grave.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Marshall graveyard</div>
</div>


<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Markham_Marshall">James Markham Marshall</a> is the brother of the Supreme Court Justice <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Marshall">John Marshall</a> and also Hampton&rsquo;s great-(x4)-grandfather.</p>

<p>After visiting, we went to Washington D.C. to see our niece. Then we had a long drive back to Jacksonville – with one short stopover in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Savannah,_Georgia">Savannah</a> because&hellip; well, why not? Savannah is beautiful. Now we&rsquo;re back in Jacksonville for a few days before heading to Orlando for a conference and (<em>cue spooky music</em>) <a href="http://www.halloweenhorrornights.com/orlando/">Halloween Horror Nights</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
