<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Food | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/food/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-14T19:55:47+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Food and Drink in Amsterdam]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/09/amsterdam-food/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-09T13:20:31+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/09/amsterdam-food</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We visited a couple of great cocktail bars while in Amsterdam. The first was <a href="http://www.door-74.com/">Door 74</a>. You need to phone up to get a reservation, but we did that literally minutes before knocking on the door, and they had a table.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Unassuming door</div>
</div>


<p>The menu was neat. I got the impression it was seasonal, as it was heavily themed on 60s sci-fi despite the bar not having anything remotely about that. They had a few drinks from every planet. Each drink had a ray-gun indicator next to it showing how strong the drink was.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-menu.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-menu.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Menu</div>
</div>


<p>Our friend got the special, some blend of vodka and fruit juice that was served in a tiki container. It was poured at the table, which was neat.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-kettle.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-kettle.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The special – poured out of a dry-ice kettle</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-gin.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-gin.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Tezuka's Lost World</div>
</div>


<p>The other place we enjoyed was <a href="http://njoycocktails.com/">NJoy</a>. It&rsquo;s slightly odd – there&rsquo;s lots of neon lighting and trying-hard-to-be-hip furniture, like a scene out of Sex and the City.</p>

<p>The menu was arranged into pretentious categories – each a supposed personality type. Are you an Alchemist or a Trendsetter? A Dreamer or a Connoisseur? The drinks were all novel and had some really interesting combinations of flavours. The bartenders were really friendly and the drinks were well-made and delicious – and that&rsquo;s why we kept coming back.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-chartreuse.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-chartreuse.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Something with Chartreuse that I ordered</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-monkey.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-monkey.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Monkey's Martini</div>
</div>


<p>A word of warning: NJoy is located on &ldquo;restaurant row&rdquo; (Leidsedwarsstraat). It&rsquo;s full of possibly the most pushy restaurants I&rsquo;ve ever walked past. In super-touristy areas, I&rsquo;m used to people asking, &ldquo;You looking for a place to eat? We have delicious steak!&rdquo; and me ignoring them. This was a whole other level. People hold menus in your face, they block your way, they won&rsquo;t let you past unless you&rsquo;ve responded to them. Our tactic to avoid this as best as we could was to appear to be in a heated debate as we rapidly walked the gauntlet.</p>

<p>Anyway, onto food. When travelling, I enjoy eating the local food. <a href="https://twitter.com/roy">Roy</a>, our Dutch friend who met us on our first night in Amsterdam, explained that there&rsquo;s not much that&rsquo;s considered Dutch cuisine. It&rsquo;s mostly French food or German. Anyway, we tried our best and visited <a href="http://www.thepantry.nl/">The Pantry</a>. They called themselves Dutch cuisine, so hey, let&rsquo;s give it a go.</p>

<p>I got a trio of what were essentially mashed potatoes with other stuff in them. In the picture below, starting from the top and going clockwise, there&rsquo;s:</p>

<ul>
<li>Zuurkoolstamppot (sauerkraut)</li>
<li>Hustpot (beef, carrots, onions)</li>
<li>Boerenkoolstamppot (kale)</li>
</ul>


<p>(with a meatball in the middle)</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/potatoes.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/potatoes.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Mashed potatoes</div>
</div>


<p>The sauerkraut one was the best. Nom nom.</p>

<p>The other thing that seemed to be everywhere was pancakes. We went to a pancake place and saw they had <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poffertjes">poffertjes</a> – a kind of cross between beignets and American-style pancakes. They were served with butter and icing sugar. Very healthy.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/poffertjes.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/poffertjes.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Poffertjes</div>
</div>


<p>We went for a memorable meal at a steak and ribs place – <a href="http://www.castellamsterdam.nl/en/">Castell</a>. We made a reservation, showed up on time, and the waiter showed us to our table. We were a little confused. Rather than a regular dining table, it was coffee table-height, and our seats were leather benches surrounding one end (another group was at the other end).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-table.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-table.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Our table (we ordered some escargot)</div>
</div>


<p>We weren&rsquo;t quite sure whether this was a pre-dinner drink table or what. But soon we received some wicker trays, one per person, on which to eat our steaks.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-lap.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-lap.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hampton with his tray</div>
</div>


<p>I got the ribs, and Hampton got a steak. They came on wooden blocks with little copper pans of sauce, and were delivered onto our trays. Eating was challenging, to say the least. There was no real space to put your tray if you needed to get up. I couldn&rsquo;t really reach my drink without my shirt getting ribs all over it. It was <em>not</em> easy.</p>

<p><strong>But</strong> (and it&rsquo;s a big one) – those ribs were amazing. No, seriously – possibly the best ribs I&rsquo;ve ever had (and I&rsquo;ve spent time in the South). The meat was tender, falling off the bone, and had a crisp char. The rub they used had just the right balance of vinegar, spice, and sugar. I&rsquo;d <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aYsLh4QjBPc#t=16">step over my own mother</a> for those ribs.</p>

<p>Something we noticed in Amsterdam – the service is slow. Exceptionally slow. Even taking into account European-style service (which we&rsquo;re both fine with!), Amsterdam added an extra level to that. Not sure why, but there you go.</p>

<p>Anyway, now we&rsquo;re in Berlin for a couple of weeks. We&rsquo;re staying in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kreuzberg">Kreuzberg</a> district, so stay tuned for posts about that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[La Degustation]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/27/la-degustation/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-27T11:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/27/la-degustation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.ladegustation.cz/en/#index"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">La Degustation</span></a>, one of two restaurants in Prague to have <a href="http://www.viamichelin.com/web/Restaurants/Restaurants-Prague-_-Praha_hlavni_mesto-Czech_Republic?strLocid=31MzhkeDEwY05UQXVNRGczT0RFPWNNVFF1TkRJd05EWT0=">a Michelin star</a>, was our special treat as our time in Prague is coming to an end. Its slogan is "bohême bourgeoise," which I found amusing.</p>

  <p>Inside, I don't know if anything can be gothic minimalist, but I think that's an accurate description. Arches ribbed the ceiling, and artfully-placed dim spotlights created wonderful shadows. The walls were bare and painted a light grey, and the furniture was all low-backed and dark wood. The windows onto the street had the restaurant's signature checkered pattern.</p>

  <p>As we sat down, the waiter came over and gave us an envelope.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/envelope.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/envelope.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">We were handed an envelope</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/back-envelope.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/back-envelope.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The back of the envelope</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/contents.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/contents.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Open it to find the checkered pattern</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/menu.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/menu.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Two menu options</div>
  </div>

  <p>We went for the eleven-course menu, with wine pairings. It was definitely a lot of food, and I wish I hadn't eaten so much of the delicious bread they brought. The menu focussed on Czech ingredients and dishes, but with modern, vaguely molecular-gastronomic twists. Apparently a lot of the inspiration for their dishes comes from a late-19th century Czech cookbook.</p>

  <p>I didn't take pictures and I won't bore you with a course-by-course detailing of everything. A couple of stand-out dishes, though: dijon mustard ice-cream with hot tomato sauce. The sauce was the perfect distillation of tomato flavour. Add that to the mustard (which wasn't too spicy), plus the mixing of the hot sauce with the cold ice-cream and you get an incredible dish that's not quite like anything I've had before.</p>

  <p>There was a foie gras course where the liver had been finely grated over wine jelly and pistachio. I'd never eaten foie gras grated before, and it really helped take away the heaviness you sometimes get. Then there was the beef tongue "signature dish." </p>

  <p>I really enjoyed the wine pairings. They used mostly Czech wines, and it was nice to see the variety in types they produce here. There was also a great unfiltered Slovenian wine called <a href="http://www.scurek.com/www/index.php/en/wines/white-wines">Kontra</a>. The cheese course came with a delicious IPA from the <a href="http://www.beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/23493/">Matuška Brewery</a>.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">If you're willing to splash out, this place is definitely worth it. It's a modern take on Czech flavours and ingredients, and the courses are presented beautifully.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">9.3</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Midsummer House: 22nd December 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2013/01/05/midsummer-house/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-05T20:10:32+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2013/01/05/midsummer-house</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We were in the UK for Christmas, and my parents told us to keep one evening free from seeing our friends &ndash; they had a plan. They didn&rsquo;t tell us what it was &ndash; not even on the cab ride there. We were equally intrigued (what could it be? It had to be dinner, right?) and anxious (what if we didn&rsquo;t like it?).</p>

<p>As we entered the backroads of northern Cambridge, we realised we were going to <a href="http://www.midsummerhouse.co.uk/">Midsummer House</a>, the 2-Michelin-starred restaurant where we got married just over three years ago. Needless to say, we were both incredibly excited. We had the tasting menu with wine pairings, and it was incredible. I think it supersedes other meals I&rsquo;ve had there to be the best meal of my life. I took some pictures, so here you go:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/bloody-mary.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/bloody-mary.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Bloody Mary amuse-bouche
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/goats-cheese.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/goats-cheese.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Celery, goat's cheese, and horseradish ice-cream.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/scallop.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/scallop.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Sautéed scallop, celeriac and truffle.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/trestle.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/trestle.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Before the third course arrived, we had this placed in front of us...
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/sweetbreads.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/sweetbreads.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Turns out, it was to hold this: sweetbreads, pistachio, maple syrup and mouli.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/brill.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/brill.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Roast brill, surf clams, cucumber, wasabi, sorrel.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/beef.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/beef.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Beef fillet, sautéed tongue, horseradish, turnip and Paris browns.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/pousse-cafe.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/pousse-cafe.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Pousse-café - maple syrup, egg-yolk, and Jack Daniels and chive foam.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/kumkwats.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/kumkwats.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Poached kumquats with lemon and thyme ice-cream.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/chocolate.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/chocolate.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Chocolate, caramel and chestnuts, chestnut frangipane.
  </div>
</div>


<p>I missed two courses: a broccoli, pear and blue cheese starter and an apple crumble thing with baked yoghurt. Both were intense and I must have dove in without thinking to take a picture.</p>

<p>The meal took four hours and I loved every minute of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[San Francisco: Part Two]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/12/30/san-francisco-part-two/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-30T20:25:25+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/12/30/san-francisco-part-two</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My first post on SF was a bit tourist-y. This one will be more focused on food and drink. And other funstuff.</p>

<p>We ate at a neat burger place on Union Sq &ndash; the aptly-named <a href="http://www.burger-bar.com/">Burger Bar</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/burger-bar-view.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/burger-bar-view.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">View from Burger Bar.</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/burger-bar.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/burger-bar.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The burger I had. I think it was buffalo?</div>
</div>


<p>The milkshakes (picture missing) were amazing. The nutella one was just ice-cream and nutella, pretty much. The burger was good&hellip; but I&rsquo;ve had better (I&rsquo;m looking at you, The Bird in Berlin.)</p>

<p>We went to an awesome beach &ndash; China Beach. It was really quiet and had insane views of the Golden Gate and its bridge.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/san-francisco/china-beach.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/china-beach.jpg">
  </a>
</div>


<p>Oh, and something else I&rsquo;d highly recommend is Nightlife at the California Academy of Sciences. It&rsquo;s on every Thursday and has a general theme every week (we went for 80s nostalgia/comedy). They have booze, you can wander around the exhibits, and they play pretty awesome music.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s about all I have to say. If you keep track of my whereabouts, you&rsquo;ll notice we&rsquo;ve now moved to San Francisco to live. It&rsquo;s awesome here!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lyon: Part Deux (La Cuisine)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/06/30/lyon-part-deux-la-cuisine/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-30T21:46:56+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/06/30/lyon-part-deux-la-cuisine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn&rsquo;t realise that Lyon was the centre for French gastronomy. But apparently it is. Anyway, I thought I&rsquo;d devote a whole post to the food I ate there, in addition to my first post on the city itself.</p>

<p>The first night, we ate at <a href="http://www.brasseriegeorges.com/">Brasserie Georges</a>. It&rsquo;s apparently pretty famous (it has a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brasserie_Georges">Wikipedia article</a> &ndash; a sure sign of prominence). They served some traditional Lyon food &ndash; including a pistachio sausage thing, which was pretty nice. Also on the list of traditional Lyon foods were a mustard sausage and calf&rsquo;s head. I think I made the right choice with a pistachio sausage.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/georges.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/georges.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    I forgot to take pictures of the food.
  </div>
</div>


<p>The second evening, we went to a place called <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps/place?hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;bav=on.2,or.r_gc.r_pw.&amp;biw=1256&amp;bih=738&amp;um=1&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;q=Les+enfants+terribles+lyon&amp;fb=1&amp;hq=Les+enfants+terribles&amp;hnear=0x47f4ea516ae88797:0x408ab2ae4bb21f0,Lyon,+France&amp;cid=9879979365541420669">Les Enfants Terribles</a>&hellip; it was OK. Nothing too special. The duck salad I had to start had too much mustard dressing on it. The main was beef, coupled with some deeeeelicious dauphinoise potatoes. I think they must have used chicken stock or something. The dessert was pretty good&hellip; but that&rsquo;s not much of a surprise as I love all tartes au citron. The filling had a strange granular texture &ndash; I think they might have added ground almonds or something.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/duck-salad.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/duck-salad.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Starter: duck salad with some foie gras.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/beef.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/beef.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Main: beef with dauphinoise potatoes.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/tarte-citron.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/tarte-citron.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Dessert: tarte au citron.
  </div>
</div>


<p>For Sunday lunch, we went to a pretty decent restaurant near the hotel (in the Brotteaux area) &ndash; it was called <a href="http://www.nordsudbrasseries.com/">Brasserie de l'Est</a>. It seems to be part of a chain. The food was pretty good! I&rsquo;d recommend it. I forgot to take pictures, though.</p>

<p>On our final night, we ended up at <a href="http://www.hippopotamus.fr/">Hippopotamus</a>. I&rsquo;ve seen a few in Paris. They&rsquo;re some kind of chain that serves vaguely French food &ndash; steaks, etc. It was, as we kinda expected, mediocre. I had an assortment of fried goods. It was very American.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/hippo.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/hippo.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    The fried stuff from Hippopotamus.
  </div>
</div>


<p>One of the better meals I had was (strangely?) at the airport. It was the airport branch of the 2-Michelin-starred <a href="http://www.nicolaslebec.com/">Nicolas Le Bec</a>, which is in the centre of Lyon. It&rsquo;s called <a href="http://www.espace-lebec.com/">Espace Le Bec</a>. We both had a really delicious penne with bolognese. It had the most amazing cheese sliced over it, too. SO GOOD.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/lyon/lys-pasta.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/lys-pasta.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Penne with bolognese.
  </div>
</div>


<p>So that&rsquo;s pretty much all the food I ate in Lyon. I wasn&rsquo;t there that long, so I can&rsquo;t really confirm or deny its status as le centre gastronomique of France. I&rsquo;ve had better meals in Paris. (But Espace Le Bec was definitely the best meal I&rsquo;ve had at an airport.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
