<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Food | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/food/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-10T14:08:43-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Momofuku and Other Toronto Eats]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/16/daisho/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-16T10:15:28-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/16/daisho</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve enjoyed watching <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Chang">David Chang&rsquo;s</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Momofuku_(restaurants)">Momofuku</a> empire grow, but I&rsquo;ve never had the opportunity to eat at one of his restaurants. As he hasn&rsquo;t opened a restaurant in San Francisco, the closest I&rsquo;ve got is reading <a href="http://lky.ph/">Lucky Peach</a>. I was super excited to go to one of his restaurants in Toronto.</p>

<p>There are four Momofuku properties in Toronto – all housed in the same building. In order of increasing fanciness, they are Noodle Bar, Nikai (a cocktail bar), Daishō and Shōtō. The building is pretty cool – it almost looks like an Apple store with its glass exterior and giant Momofuku sign.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/momofuku.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/momofuku.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Momofuku sign</div>
</div>


<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toronto_International_Film_Festival">Toronto International Film Festival</a> is going on, and right next to the Momofuku building is the Shangri-la hotel. On its third-floor deck, there was a pre-premiere party for a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wild_(film)">new Reese Witherspoon film</a>. From our table we could see right into the pre-party and had a lot of fun figuring out what it was for. We saw <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Evans_(actor)">Chris Evans</a> there! But we didn&rsquo;t see Reese Witherspoon.</p>

<p>Anyway, onto the food. We were eating at Daishō, which has a bunch of smaller dishes plus some larger, 4-10 person plates if you want to do that. They also have a small, but interesting, cocktail list. I got a bijou and it was nicely done (although you couldn&rsquo;t really taste the Chartreuse).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/cocktail.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/cocktail.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Bijou and menu</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/whiskey-flight.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/whiskey-flight.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hampton got a whiskey flight</div>
</div>


<p>Momofuku is known for its buns, so we got some duck and shrimp versions. It was strange seeing the duck come in patty form – but it tasted absolutely amazing, so I didn&rsquo;t care.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/duck-bun.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/duck-bun.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Duck bun</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/shrimp-bun.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/shrimp-bun.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Shrimp bun</div>
</div>


<p>The steak tartare was made with such tender beef. They added enough yolk to keep it glossy, without it being too sloppy. Plus it has sunflower seeds in it which added some nice texture. One of the best tartares I&rsquo;ve had.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/tartare.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/tartare.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Steak tartare</div>
</div>


<p>The other popular thing on the menu is the ssäm (pronounced with a long &ldquo;a&rdquo;, like psalm). <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ssam">Ssäm</a> is a Korean dish whereby you wrap meat inside a large lettuce leaf. It&rsquo;s a make-your-own lettuce wrap kinda thing. We decided to go for the secreto ssäm, mainly because we didn&rsquo;t know what secreto was (turns out it&rsquo;s a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Iberian_pig">cut of pork</a>). It was really delicious!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/ssam.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/ssam.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Secreto Ssäm</div>
</div>


<p>We also ordered some crab cakes, which came out looking a lot more different than I thought. Turns out Korean-style crab cakes aren&rsquo;t patty-shaped. They&rsquo;re long tube-like things that aren&rsquo;t totally unlike crab sticks. They came in a spicy sauce, too.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crab-cakes.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crab-cakes.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Korean-style crab cakes</div>
</div>


<p>Despite being fit to burst at this point, we were recommended the crack pie. IT WAS AMAZING. That&rsquo;s about all I can say. If you have an opportunity, get it.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crack-pie.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crack-pie.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Crack pie</div>
</div>


<p>As well as Daishō, there were a bunch of other awesome places we ate at.</p>

<p><a href="http://guu-izakaya.com/sakabar">Guu Sakabar</a> is an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Izakaya">izakaya</a>-style bar/restaurant. They have a bunch of smaller dishes on the <a href="http://guu-izakaya.com/docs/sakabar_menu1.pdf">menu</a>, and you order a few each and share. They have a wide range of stuff, from standard (like takoyaki) to weird (udon carbonara?). My favourite was kabocha korokke – a pumpkin croquette thing with a boiled egg in the middle, served with a sauce that was kinda like thousand island dressing.</p>

<p>They had an Ontario-produced sake which I can&rsquo;t find on the menu but it was delicious.</p>

<p><a href="http://416snackbar.wordpress.com/">416 Snack Bar</a> is a hipster tapas-style place. They had chalkboard on the walls and don&rsquo;t offer you any cutlery. The best thing here was either the foie torchon or the steak tartare.</p>

<p>The other place I enjoyed was <a href="http://patriatoronto.com/">Patria</a>, a Spanish tapas restaurant (all the places we went to were tapas, it seems). They had great authentic Spanish-style food (even jamón Ibérico!) plus some tasty sangria. We got a cornish hen paella, which was weird but worked pretty well.</p>

<p>These restaurants barely scratch the surface of Toronto, I&rsquo;m sure. We&rsquo;ve eaten really well here, no doubt due to the excellent choices of our friends <a href="http://twitter.com/mferrier">Mike</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/melissaiscool">Melissa</a> who pretty much recommended/chose all of these places to eat at.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Markhalle Neun and Sage]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/20/markhalle-neun-and-sage/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-20T08:43:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/20/markhalle-neun-and-sage</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s a great indoor market called <a href="http://www.markthalleneun.de/">Markthalle Neun</a> that&rsquo;s about <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/preview?ie=UTF-8&amp;fb=1&amp;cid=10953314371184579858&amp;q=Markthalle+Neun+GmbH&amp;ei=3sHwU4q8BLDQ7Aa4tYDgCg&amp;ved=0CL0BEPwSMA4">a block away from where we&rsquo;re staying</a>. It&rsquo;s not a traditional market in that there are people selling stuff every day. On a normal day there&rsquo;s a handful of stands or mini-kitchens selling locally-made food, wine, and other stuff.</p>

<p>On Thursdays, however, there&rsquo;s a &ldquo;street food&rdquo; gathering where a lot more people show up. All the booths are filled with people selling their food – everything from pancakes to samosas to steamed buns. There&rsquo;s also a couple of food trucks outside, too. It gets incredibly packed, but it&rsquo;s a lot of fun.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Street food Thursdays</div>
</div>


<p>There&rsquo;s also a Sunday morning &ldquo;breakfast market,&rdquo; which has more of a focus on breakfast foods.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve been to a couple of these events, but mostly we go on weekdays for lunch. There&rsquo;s such a wide variety of food there it&rsquo;s difficult to go wrong. Anyway, I&rsquo;ve taken pictures of pretty much everything I&rsquo;ve eaten there, so this will mainly be a bunch of pictures of delicious food.</p>

<p>The best thing I&rsquo;ve had so far has been the barbeque from <a href="http://www.bigstuff.de/">Big Stuff Smoked BBQ</a>. It blew away most of the BBQ I&rsquo;ve had in the USA.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bbq-ribs.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bbq-ribs.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">BBQ rib sandwich</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bbq-pork.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bbq-pork.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">BBQ pork belly sandwich</div>
</div>


<p>There was a Vietnamese stall that did rice-stuffed rolls and some steamed buns.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bun.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-bun.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Steamed bun with pretty much EVERYTHING inside</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-rolls.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-rolls.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Delicious rolls with rice and meat inside</div>
</div>


<p>There was a great vegetarian burger place. We accidentally went there because it had the shortest queue. Then we found out it was vegetarian, almost left, but stuck with it. The burger was so good! I think it was tofu or something, but it was mainly tasty cause they slathered it in peanut sauce.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-veggie-burger.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-veggie-burger.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The best veggie-burger I&#8217;ve ever had</div>
</div>


<p>The next place I went to, I had their veggie-burger but it sucked, so I went back to eating all meat all the time.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m English so I love savoury pies. What luck! There was a pie place in the market. I got a cheese and mince one and it was SO GOOD. I would eat ten more right now.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-pie.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-pie.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Cheese and mince pie (note: not <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mince_pie">that kind of mince pie</a>, which would probably be gross with cheese in it)</div>
</div>


<p>If you don&rsquo;t like pies (like Hampton), you can get a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reuben_sandwich">reuben sandwich</a>! It had pastrami on it. Apparently this guy from Portland moved to Berlin and was upset he couldn&rsquo;t get decent pastrami&hellip; so he opened a deli!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-reuben.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-reuben.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Reuben sandwich</div>
</div>


<p>Don&rsquo;t fancy savoury items? Well there&rsquo;s a tonne of sweet stuff, too. There&rsquo;s a great waffle place.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-waffles.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-waffles.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Making waffles</div>
</div>


<p>Usually I&rsquo;m not the biggest fan of waffles, but these were so good. Crisp on the outside and moist on the inside. Oh, and covered in caramel sauce.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-waffle-caramel.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-waffle-caramel.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">My waffle</div>
</div>


<p>The waffle place also did some crazy ice-creams&hellip;</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-icecream.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-icecream.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Raspberry and basil</div>
</div>


<p>And there was a lady selling ice-lollies (or &ldquo;popsicles&rdquo;).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-lollipop.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/mh9-lollipop.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Buttermilk and lemon</div>
</div>


<p>OK, that&rsquo;s all my Markthalle photos. We did eat some fancy food as well – at <a href="http://www.sage-restaurant.de/cms/">Sage</a>. I really like the interior of this place. It&rsquo;s in a warehouse and has lots of industrial touches – like giant chains hanging from the ceiling. But it&rsquo;s also bright due to the large windows and white canvases on the walls.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-inside.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-inside.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Sage interior</div>
</div>


<p>We went for a four-course Chef&rsquo;s surprise menu. It was a great choice – full of interesting flavours and ingredients that I&rsquo;d never come across before. Here&rsquo;s some pictures:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-octopus.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-octopus.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Octopus, potato foam, chorizo</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-monkfish.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-monkfish.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Monkfish, black potato purée</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-beef.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-beef.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Beef, spinach polenta, mushrooms, spiced pumpkin</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-icecream.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/berlin/food/sage-icecream.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Lemon sorbet, chocolate-covered marscapone ice-cream</div>
</div>


<p>It was super-tasty and you should definitely go if you&rsquo;re in the area. Get an apéritif on the beach beforehand!</p>

<p>Our time in Berlin is almost over, and next we&rsquo;ll be heading off to Stockholm for <a href="http://hybridconf.net/">HybridConf</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Food and Drink in Amsterdam]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/09/amsterdam-food/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-09T07:20:31-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/08/09/amsterdam-food</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We visited a couple of great cocktail bars while in Amsterdam. The first was <a href="http://www.door-74.com/">Door 74</a>. You need to phone up to get a reservation, but we did that literally minutes before knocking on the door, and they had a table.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Unassuming door</div>
</div>


<p>The menu was neat. I got the impression it was seasonal, as it was heavily themed on 60s sci-fi despite the bar not having anything remotely about that. They had a few drinks from every planet. Each drink had a ray-gun indicator next to it showing how strong the drink was.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-menu.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-menu.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Menu</div>
</div>


<p>Our friend got the special, some blend of vodka and fruit juice that was served in a tiki container. It was poured at the table, which was neat.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-kettle.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-kettle.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The special – poured out of a dry-ice kettle</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-gin.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/door-74-gin.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Tezuka&#8217;s Lost World</div>
</div>


<p>The other place we enjoyed was <a href="http://njoycocktails.com/">NJoy</a>. It&rsquo;s slightly odd – there&rsquo;s lots of neon lighting and trying-hard-to-be-hip furniture, like a scene out of Sex and the City.</p>

<p>The menu was arranged into pretentious categories – each a supposed personality type. Are you an Alchemist or a Trendsetter? A Dreamer or a Connoisseur? The drinks were all novel and had some really interesting combinations of flavours. The bartenders were really friendly and the drinks were well-made and delicious – and that&rsquo;s why we kept coming back.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-chartreuse.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-chartreuse.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Something with Chartreuse that I ordered</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-monkey.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/drinks/njoy-monkey.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Monkey&#8217;s Martini</div>
</div>


<p>A word of warning: NJoy is located on &ldquo;restaurant row&rdquo; (Leidsedwarsstraat). It&rsquo;s full of possibly the most pushy restaurants I&rsquo;ve ever walked past. In super-touristy areas, I&rsquo;m used to people asking, &ldquo;You looking for a place to eat? We have delicious steak!&rdquo; and me ignoring them. This was a whole other level. People hold menus in your face, they block your way, they won&rsquo;t let you past unless you&rsquo;ve responded to them. Our tactic to avoid this as best as we could was to appear to be in a heated debate as we rapidly walked the gauntlet.</p>

<p>Anyway, onto food. When travelling, I enjoy eating the local food. <a href="https://twitter.com/roy">Roy</a>, our Dutch friend who met us on our first night in Amsterdam, explained that there&rsquo;s not much that&rsquo;s considered Dutch cuisine. It&rsquo;s mostly French food or German. Anyway, we tried our best and visited <a href="http://www.thepantry.nl/">The Pantry</a>. They called themselves Dutch cuisine, so hey, let&rsquo;s give it a go.</p>

<p>I got a trio of what were essentially mashed potatoes with other stuff in them. In the picture below, starting from the top and going clockwise, there&rsquo;s:</p>

<ul>
<li>Zuurkoolstamppot (sauerkraut)</li>
<li>Hustpot (beef, carrots, onions)</li>
<li>Boerenkoolstamppot (kale)</li>
</ul>


<p>(with a meatball in the middle)</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/potatoes.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/potatoes.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Mashed potatoes</div>
</div>


<p>The sauerkraut one was the best. Nom nom.</p>

<p>The other thing that seemed to be everywhere was pancakes. We went to a pancake place and saw they had <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poffertjes">poffertjes</a> – a kind of cross between beignets and American-style pancakes. They were served with butter and icing sugar. Very healthy.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/poffertjes.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/poffertjes.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Poffertjes</div>
</div>


<p>We went for a memorable meal at a steak and ribs place – <a href="http://www.castellamsterdam.nl/en/">Castell</a>. We made a reservation, showed up on time, and the waiter showed us to our table. We were a little confused. Rather than a regular dining table, it was coffee table-height, and our seats were leather benches surrounding one end (another group was at the other end).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-table.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-table.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Our table (we ordered some escargot)</div>
</div>


<p>We weren&rsquo;t quite sure whether this was a pre-dinner drink table or what. But soon we received some wicker trays, one per person, on which to eat our steaks.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-lap.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/amsterdam/food/steak-lap.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hampton with his tray</div>
</div>


<p>I got the ribs, and Hampton got a steak. They came on wooden blocks with little copper pans of sauce, and were delivered onto our trays. Eating was challenging, to say the least. There was no real space to put your tray if you needed to get up. I couldn&rsquo;t really reach my drink without my shirt getting ribs all over it. It was <em>not</em> easy.</p>

<p><strong>But</strong> (and it&rsquo;s a big one) – those ribs were amazing. No, seriously – possibly the best ribs I&rsquo;ve ever had (and I&rsquo;ve spent time in the South). The meat was tender, falling off the bone, and had a crisp char. The rub they used had just the right balance of vinegar, spice, and sugar. I&rsquo;d <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aYsLh4QjBPc#t=16">step over my own mother</a> for those ribs.</p>

<p>Something we noticed in Amsterdam – the service is slow. Exceptionally slow. Even taking into account European-style service (which we&rsquo;re both fine with!), Amsterdam added an extra level to that. Not sure why, but there you go.</p>

<p>Anyway, now we&rsquo;re in Berlin for a couple of weeks. We&rsquo;re staying in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kreuzberg">Kreuzberg</a> district, so stay tuned for posts about that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[La Degustation]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/27/la-degustation/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-27T05:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/27/la-degustation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.ladegustation.cz/en/#index"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">La Degustation</span></a>, one of two restaurants in Prague to have <a href="http://www.viamichelin.com/web/Restaurants/Restaurants-Prague-_-Praha_hlavni_mesto-Czech_Republic?strLocid=31MzhkeDEwY05UQXVNRGczT0RFPWNNVFF1TkRJd05EWT0=">a Michelin star</a>, was our special treat as our time in Prague is coming to an end. Its slogan is &#8220;bohême bourgeoise,&#8221; which I found amusing.</p>

  <p>Inside, I don&#8217;t know if anything can be gothic minimalist, but I think that&#8217;s an accurate description. Arches ribbed the ceiling, and artfully-placed dim spotlights created wonderful shadows. The walls were bare and painted a light grey, and the furniture was all low-backed and dark wood. The windows onto the street had the restaurant&#8217;s signature checkered pattern.</p>

  <p>As we sat down, the waiter came over and gave us an envelope.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/envelope.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/envelope.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">We were handed an envelope</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/back-envelope.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/back-envelope.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The back of the envelope</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/contents.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/contents.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Open it to find the checkered pattern</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/menu.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/menu.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Two menu options</div>
  </div>

  <p>We went for the eleven-course menu, with wine pairings. It was definitely a lot of food, and I wish I hadn&#8217;t eaten so much of the delicious bread they brought. The menu focussed on Czech ingredients and dishes, but with modern, vaguely molecular-gastronomic twists. Apparently a lot of the inspiration for their dishes comes from a late-19th century Czech cookbook.</p>

  <p>I didn&#8217;t take pictures and I won&#8217;t bore you with a course-by-course detailing of everything. A couple of stand-out dishes, though: dijon mustard ice-cream with hot tomato sauce. The sauce was the perfect distillation of tomato flavour. Add that to the mustard (which wasn&#8217;t too spicy), plus the mixing of the hot sauce with the cold ice-cream and you get an incredible dish that&#8217;s not quite like anything I&#8217;ve had before.</p>

  <p>There was a foie gras course where the liver had been finely grated over wine jelly and pistachio. I&#8217;d never eaten foie gras grated before, and it really helped take away the heaviness you sometimes get. Then there was the beef tongue &#8220;signature dish.&#8221; </p>

  <p>I really enjoyed the wine pairings. They used mostly Czech wines, and it was nice to see the variety in types they produce here. There was also a great unfiltered Slovenian wine called <a href="http://www.scurek.com/www/index.php/en/wines/white-wines">Kontra</a>. The cheese course came with a delicious IPA from the <a href="http://www.beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/23493/">Matuška Brewery</a>.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">If you&#8217;re willing to splash out, this place is definitely worth it. It&#8217;s a modern take on Czech flavours and ingredients, and the courses are presented beautifully.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">9.3</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Midsummer House: 22nd December 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2013/01/05/midsummer-house/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-05T14:10:32-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2013/01/05/midsummer-house</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We were in the UK for Christmas, and my parents told us to keep one evening free from seeing our friends - they had a plan. They didn&rsquo;t tell us what it was - not even on the cab ride there. We were equally intrigued (what could it be? It had to be dinner, right?) and anxious (what if we didn&rsquo;t like it?).</p>

<p>As we entered the backroads of northern Cambridge, we realised we were going to <a href="http://www.midsummerhouse.co.uk/">Midsummer House</a>, the 2-Michelin-starred restaurant where we got married just over three years ago. Needless to say, we were both incredibly excited. We had the tasting menu with wine pairings, and it was incredible. I think it supersedes other meals I&rsquo;ve had there to be the best meal of my life. I took some pictures, so here you go:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/bloody-mary.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/bloody-mary.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Bloody Mary amuse-bouche
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/goats-cheese.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/goats-cheese.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Celery, goat&#8217;s cheese, and horseradish ice-cream.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/scallop.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/scallop.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Sautéed scallop, celeriac and truffle.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/trestle.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/trestle.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Before the third course arrived, we had this placed in front of us&#8230;
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/sweetbreads.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/sweetbreads.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Turns out, it was to hold this: sweetbreads, pistachio, maple syrup and mouli.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/brill.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/brill.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Roast brill, surf clams, cucumber, wasabi, sorrel.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/beef.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/beef.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Beef fillet, sautéed tongue, horseradish, turnip and Paris browns.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/pousse-cafe.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/pousse-cafe.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Pousse-café - maple syrup, egg-yolk, and Jack Daniels and chive foam.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/kumkwats.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/kumkwats.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Poached kumquats with lemon and thyme ice-cream.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/chocolate.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/chocolate.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Chocolate, caramel and chestnuts, chestnut frangipane.
  </div>
</div>


<p>I missed two courses: a broccoli, pear and blue cheese starter and an apple crumble thing with baked yoghurt. Both were intense and I must have dove in without thinking to take a picture.</p>

<p>The meal took four hours and I loved every minute of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
