<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Food | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/food/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-26T13:08:57+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Midsummer House: 22nd December 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2013/01/05/midsummer-house/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-05T20:10:32+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2013/01/05/midsummer-house</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We were in the UK for Christmas, and my parents told us to keep one evening free from seeing our friends &ndash; they had a plan. They didn&rsquo;t tell us what it was &ndash; not even on the cab ride there. We were equally intrigued (what could it be? It had to be dinner, right?) and anxious (what if we didn&rsquo;t like it?).</p>

<p>As we entered the backroads of northern Cambridge, we realised we were going to <a href="http://www.midsummerhouse.co.uk/">Midsummer House</a>, the 2-Michelin-starred restaurant where we got married just over three years ago. Needless to say, we were both incredibly excited. We had the tasting menu with wine pairings, and it was incredible. I think it supersedes other meals I&rsquo;ve had there to be the best meal of my life. I took some pictures, so here you go:</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/bloody-mary.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Bloody Mary amuse-bouche
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/goats-cheese.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Celery, goat's cheese, and horseradish ice-cream.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/scallop.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Sautéed scallop, celeriac and truffle.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/trestle.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Before the third course arrived, we had this placed in front of us...
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/sweetbreads.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Turns out, it was to hold this: sweetbreads, pistachio, maple syrup and mouli.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/brill.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Roast brill, surf clams, cucumber, wasabi, sorrel.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/beef.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Beef fillet, sautéed tongue, horseradish, turnip and Paris browns.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/pousse-cafe.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Pousse-café - maple syrup, egg-yolk, and Jack Daniels and chive foam.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/kumkwats.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Poached kumquats with lemon and thyme ice-cream.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/chocolate.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Chocolate, caramel and chestnuts, chestnut frangipane.
  </div>
</div>


<p>I missed two courses: a broccoli, pear and blue cheese starter and an apple crumble thing with baked yoghurt. Both were intense and I must have dove in without thinking to take a picture.</p>

<p>The meal took four hours and I loved every minute of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[San Francisco: Part Two]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/12/30/san-francisco-part-two/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-30T20:25:25+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/12/30/san-francisco-part-two</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My first post on SF was a bit tourist-y. This one will be more focused on food and drink. And other funstuff.</p>

<p>We ate at a neat burger place on Union Sq &ndash; the aptly-named <a href="http://www.burger-bar.com/">Burger Bar</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/burger-bar-view.jpg">
  <div class="alt">View from Burger Bar.</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/burger-bar.jpg">
  <div class="alt">The burger I had. I think it was buffalo?</div>
</div>


<p>The milkshakes (picture missing) were amazing. The nutella one was just ice-cream and nutella, pretty much. The burger was good&hellip; but I&rsquo;ve had better (I&rsquo;m looking at you, The Bird in Berlin.)</p>

<p>We went to an awesome beach &ndash; China Beach. It was really quiet and had insane views of the Golden Gate and its bridge.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/san-francisco/china-beach.jpg">
</div>


<p>Oh, and something else I&rsquo;d highly recommend is Nightlife at the California Academy of Sciences. It&rsquo;s on every Thursday and has a general theme every week (we went for 80s nostalgia/comedy). They have booze, you can wander around the exhibits, and they play pretty awesome music.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s about all I have to say. If you keep track of my whereabouts, you&rsquo;ll notice we&rsquo;ve now moved to San Francisco to live. It&rsquo;s awesome here!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lyon: Part Deux (La Cuisine)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/06/30/lyon-part-deux-la-cuisine/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-30T21:46:56+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/06/30/lyon-part-deux-la-cuisine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn&rsquo;t realise that Lyon was the centre for French gastronomy. But apparently it is. Anyway, I thought I&rsquo;d devote a whole post to the food I ate there, in addition to my first post on the city itself.</p>

<p>The first night, we ate at <a href="http://www.brasseriegeorges.com/">Brasserie Georges</a>. It&rsquo;s apparently pretty famous (it has a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brasserie_Georges">Wikipedia article</a> &ndash; a sure sign of prominence). They served some traditional Lyon food &ndash; including a pistachio sausage thing, which was pretty nice. Also on the list of traditional Lyon foods were a mustard sausage and calf&rsquo;s head. I think I made the right choice with a pistachio sausage.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/georges.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    I forgot to take pictures of the food.
  </div>
</div>


<p>The second evening, we went to a place called <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps/place?hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;bav=on.2,or.r_gc.r_pw.&amp;biw=1256&amp;bih=738&amp;um=1&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;q=Les+enfants+terribles+lyon&amp;fb=1&amp;hq=Les+enfants+terribles&amp;hnear=0x47f4ea516ae88797:0x408ab2ae4bb21f0,Lyon,+France&amp;cid=9879979365541420669">Les Enfants Terribles</a>&hellip; it was OK. Nothing too special. The duck salad I had to start had too much mustard dressing on it. The main was beef, coupled with some deeeeelicious dauphinoise potatoes. I think they must have used chicken stock or something. The dessert was pretty good&hellip; but that&rsquo;s not much of a surprise as I love all tartes au citron. The filling had a strange granular texture &ndash; I think they might have added ground almonds or something.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/duck-salad.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Starter: duck salad with some foie gras.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/beef.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Main: beef with dauphinoise potatoes.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/tarte-citron.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Dessert: tarte au citron.
  </div>
</div>


<p>For Sunday lunch, we went to a pretty decent restaurant near the hotel (in the Brotteaux area) &ndash; it was called <a href="http://www.nordsudbrasseries.com/">Brasserie de l'Est</a>. It seems to be part of a chain. The food was pretty good! I&rsquo;d recommend it. I forgot to take pictures, though.</p>

<p>On our final night, we ended up at <a href="http://www.hippopotamus.fr/">Hippopotamus</a>. I&rsquo;ve seen a few in Paris. They&rsquo;re some kind of chain that serves vaguely French food &ndash; steaks, etc. It was, as we kinda expected, mediocre. I had an assortment of fried goods. It was very American.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/hippo.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    The fried stuff from Hippopotamus.
  </div>
</div>


<p>One of the better meals I had was (strangely?) at the airport. It was the airport branch of the 2-Michelin-starred <a href="http://www.nicolaslebec.com/">Nicolas Le Bec</a>, which is in the centre of Lyon. It&rsquo;s called <a href="http://www.espace-lebec.com/">Espace Le Bec</a>. We both had a really delicious penne with bolognese. It had the most amazing cheese sliced over it, too. SO GOOD.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/lyon/lys-pasta.jpg">
  <div class="alt">
    Penne with bolognese.
  </div>
</div>


<p>So that&rsquo;s pretty much all the food I ate in Lyon. I wasn&rsquo;t there that long, so I can&rsquo;t really confirm or deny its status as le centre gastronomique of France. I&rsquo;ve had better meals in Paris. (But Espace Le Bec was definitely the best meal I&rsquo;ve had at an airport.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paris: April 2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/04/24/paris-april-2011/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-24T22:45:02+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2011/04/24/paris-april-2011</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After our trip to Zürich, we went to Paris by train. As with most rail travel in Europe, it was a great way to move between cities. There was a lot of kerfuffle with the hotels when we arrived &ndash; but we ended up in the beautiful <a href="http://www.closmedicis.com/">Hotel de Clos Medicis</a>. We were in the attic, which had amazing exposed beams and an upstairs bathroom.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/paris/medicis.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Our room (in the attic) in the hotel.</div>
</div>


<p>Best of all, we were in the Latin Quarter, which is so much fun. It&rsquo;s the &ldquo;bohemian&rdquo; area of Paris, with lots of cool bars, cafés and restaurants to eat in. Which is what we mainly ended up doing.Hampton and I have done most of the touristy things in Paris before &ndash; and we were there in March, too. When we were there, we discovered our love for the café culture. Seriously, why hasn&rsquo;t it been rolled out across the world yet? We would sit in a café from 3pm until 7pm reading, drinking wine. We&rsquo;d go for a meal somewhere, then return to another café for more wine, leaving at around 2am. It&rsquo;s so refreshing.</p>

<p>Anyway, this time we tried to do the same thing. We ate a lot of good food. My favourite restaurant was <a href="http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g187147-d715085-Reviews-Fish_la_Boissonnerie-Paris_Ile_de_France.html">Fish Le Boissonnerie</a>. Some pictures follow.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/paris/boissonnerie.jpg">
  <div class="alt">The outside of Le Boissonnerie</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/paris/bois-starter.jpg">
  <div class="alt">The starter: smoked eel and marinated carrots.</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/paris/bois-main.jpg">
  <div class="alt">The main: veal, pea risotto, chorizo puree and a parmesan crisp.</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/paris/bois-dessert.jpg">
  <div class="alt">The dessert: crème brûlée.</div>
</div>


<p>I didn&rsquo;t take a picture of the bread, though. The bread (which I think they got from an Italian restaurant across the street) was the most amazing foccacia I have ever tasted. I&rsquo;d go back to that restaurant solely for the bread.</p>

<p>So, other random things we did in Paris. We went on a boat tour along the Seine, which was nice. But it was super hot (a lot warmer than Zürich, that&rsquo;s for sure).</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/paris/pont-neuf.jpg">
  <div class="alt">Pont Neuf from the boat tour we did along the Seine.</div>
</div>


<p>We visited the <a href="http://equipement.paris.fr/marche-aux-fleurs-et-aux-oiseaux-cite-4506">marché des oiseaux</a> on Sunday. Every Sunday, the flower market on the Île de la Cité also has a bunch of guys selling birds. It was bizarre, and unsettling how many birds they can fit into those tiny cages.</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/paris/finches.jpg">
  <div class="alt">So many birds in such a small cage.</div>
</div>


<p>As for cafés, my favourite is still <a href="https://plus.google.com/117060472644786113352/about?gl=us&amp;hl=en">Le Contrescarpe</a>, on Rue Mouffetard. However, the best wine was definitely at <a href="http://www.michelrostang.com/">Le Rostand</a>, which was facing the Jardin du Luxembourg.</p>

<p>We didn&rsquo;t really go to that many &ldquo;bars&rdquo;, but we did go to <a href="http://www.bowlingmouffetard.fr/">Le Bowling Mouffetard</a>, a mix of Americana and UV lighting &ndash; in a bowling alley. That was very enjoyable. I remember going when I was in Paris in 2006. I&rsquo;m surprised I managed to find it again.</p>

<p>As the Royal Wedding is coming up, every French magazine seemed to have a cover story about the couple. This one really weirded me out:</p>

<div class="img">
  <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/paris/so-british.jpg">
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
