<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: North-carolina | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/north-carolina/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-10T17:29:57-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[East Coast Road Trip: Part Two]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/10/28/east-coast-road-trip-part-two/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-28T08:46:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/10/28/east-coast-road-trip-part-two</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On the southern outskirts of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asheville,_North_Carolina">Asheville</a> is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biltmore_Estate">Biltmore Estate</a>. Built by the Vanderbilt family in the 1890s, it&rsquo;s the largest home in the U.S.A. and is open for tours. It&rsquo;s ridiculously expensive to visit – $60 per person is the cheapest adult ticket. Once you get in, there isn&rsquo;t much guidance on where to go, so the audio guide is well worth the extra $10. If you&rsquo;re spending $60 already&hellip; might as well, right?</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/biltmore.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/biltmore.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Front of Biltmore</div>
</div>


<p>I&rsquo;ve been to a fair share of grand homes in the UK and France, and it was interesting to see the American version of that. Obviously, this house was built way after <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blenheim_Palace">Blenheim</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palace_of_Versailles">Versailles</a>. It had a lot more modern aspects that surprised me. For example, electricity was used widely throughout the house – the clocks were synchronised that way. The indoor swimming pool (!) was lit with DC bulbs. There was an electric <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dumbwaiter_(elevator)">dumbwaiter</a> from the kitchens. All of these &ldquo;modern&rdquo; marvels I&rsquo;d never seen in a grand home before.</p>

<p>Also, it was very noticeably a <em>home</em>, which isn&rsquo;t necessarily clear in other stately homes. Wandering around Versailles, how easy is it to imagine people living their lives there? Pretty tricky, in my opinion. Biltmore felt planned as a home – areas for family friends, areas for casual everyday living. It was far more welcoming in that regard. I&rsquo;m still not sure if it&rsquo;s worth the price tag, but I guess I&rsquo;m glad I saw it.</p>

<p>Asheville itself seemed nice, although we didn&rsquo;t stay in the centre. The only place we managed to get to was <a href="http://theadmiralnc.com/">The Admiral</a>, in the west side of the city. It was recommended by a number of people. Booking reservations was tricky – on a Monday night the only two slots were 5:30pm and 9pm. It&rsquo;s a popular place!</p>

<p>From the outside, it doesn&rsquo;t look like much.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/admiral.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/admiral.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The Admiral</div>
</div>


<p>It seems more like a dive bar than anything. Inside, it&rsquo;s even decorated like a bit of a dive bar. No tablecloths, neon beer signs on the wall. The menu is pretty high-falutin, though. Tasty cocktails to begin with.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/admiral-cocktails.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/admiral-cocktails.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Cocktails</div>
</div>


<p>Then some fancy versions of mostly Southern food. We ended up getting a bunch of small plates and one large plate – the pork chop – as we&rsquo;d heard so much about it. By far the stand-out dish was the mussels.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/admiral-mussels.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/admiral-mussels.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Mussels</div>
</div>


<p>They&rsquo;d been cooked in a PBR/tomato/chipotle broth and it was delicious. We also got the fried gnocchi, which tasted just like tater tots. The steak tartare was nice but came with a bunch of sriracha over the plate (whyyyyyy???). We got some fried sweetbreads with chipotle grits. They were good, but didn&rsquo;t really take advantage of the sweetbread itself – it could have been any random chunk of meat. The creaminess of the sweetbreads, if anything, just melded into the creamy grits. The pork chop was tough but tasty. It came with some way-too-sweet mac and cheese.</p>

<p>Anyway, after the meal we sat outside on the porch – right next to a gas fire. It was a pleasant end to the meal.</p>

<p>The next day, we headed to Raleigh for <a href="http://allthingsopen.org/">All Things Open</a>. It&rsquo;s a gigantic conference – I think there were about 1,000 attendees and ten tracks. I didn&rsquo;t manage to go to half the talks I wanted to, but I did have a good time hanging out. I finally got to meet the awesome <a href="https://twitter.com/trek">Trek</a>, who&rsquo;s hung out with Hampton at a bunch of conferences.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re looking for a decent cocktail in Raleigh, head to <a href="http://www.common414.com/">Common 414</a>. They had a solid selection of classic cocktails and didn&rsquo;t seem to get too busy (at least when we went, which admittedly tends to be earlier in the evening).</p>

<p>Due to a scheduling mix-up, we had to leave Raleigh earlier than anticipated. Our next couple of stops were in the heart of Virginia – and I&rsquo;ll be talking about those in the next post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[East Coast Road Trip: Part One]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/10/21/east-coast-road-trip-part-one/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-21T13:08:44-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/10/21/east-coast-road-trip-part-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After leaving New York, we flew down to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jacksonville,_Florida">Jacksonville</a>, Florida. We borrowed a car from Hampton&rsquo;s grandfather and started the next portion of our journey: the East Cost road trip. Hampton had been invited to conferences in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raleigh,_North_Carolina">Raleigh</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orlando,_Florida">Orlando</a>, plus we have family in North Carolina and DC, so we decided to drive around a little and I&rsquo;d get to see a few more of the off-the-beaten-track parts of the South.</p>

<p>Our first leg was from Jacksonville to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greenville,_South_Carolina">Greenville</a>, South Carolina. Hampton went to college at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Furman_University">Furman</a> – just north of the town.</p>

<p>The drive up was lonnng – it took us about eight hours (including stops and some hellish traffic around Columbia). We passed through Georgia:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/georgia.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/georgia.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Is the 1996 Olympics the only thing Georgia is proud of?</div>
</div>


<p>And into South Carolina:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/sc-gates.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/sc-gates.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">South Carolina had some pretty sweet gates</div>
</div>


<p>After driving west across most of South Carolina, we stayed in Greenville for one night. It was a neat town, with a fair few restaurants and it was pretty lively at night. There was a young kid busking – doing magic tricks with his Dad, which was super-adorable.</p>

<p>We went to Furman the next morning. It&rsquo;s a self-contained campus and is quite beautiful. There&rsquo;s a lake surrounded by trees and a bell tower on one end.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/furman.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/furman.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The bell tower</div>
</div>


<p>It was weird being at Hampton&rsquo;s old university. I think it was a strange trip for him, as he started recalling tales of parties or particular professors. What was also cool to see was the football pitch where <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clint_Dempsey">Clint Dempsey</a> got his start.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/furman-soccer.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/furman-soccer.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Furman&#8217;s football pitch</div>
</div>


<p>After that, we continued into the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nantahala_National_Forest">Nantahala National Forest</a>. There were a ton of beautiful lookout spots and hiking bits on the way there. Here&rsquo;s a few:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/slide-rock.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/slide-rock.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Slide Rock: apparently kids slide down this. Seems pretty dangerous.</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/hiking.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/hiking.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Some hiking trail that ended up being way too long</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/table-rock.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/table-rock.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Table Rock, an outcrop</div>
</div>


<p>Table rock was a little unnerving. It&rsquo;s basically a large, gently-sloping rock overlooking the forest. Every time you think you&rsquo;re at the edge, you can walk a little bit further down. It was strange seeing people further down the rock and thinking, &ldquo;Wow, they&rsquo;re in a dangerous spot!&rdquo;&hellip; and then passing them.</p>

<p>Of course, driving around the South you see some interesting decorations.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/drivers.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/drivers.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Ahh, the South</div>
</div>


<p>We drove further up into the mountains and stayed at the <a href="http://www.highlandsinnlodge.com/highlandsInnLodgeIntro.html">Highlands Inn Lodge</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Highlands,_North_Carolina">Highlands</a>, North Carolina. It was a nice place, although a little out of the centre (but I&rsquo;m sure you could walk if necessary).</p>

<p>The leaves were amazing – every road was a bordered with greens, yellows, oranges, reds and browns.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/leaves.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/leaves.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Autumnnnnn</div>
</div>


<p>After spending a couple of nights in Highlands, we drove along the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue_Ridge_Parkway">Blue Ridge Parkway</a> through the forest. It&rsquo;s a gorgeous road – you&rsquo;re basically on the ridge of the mountain range and have epic views from both sides.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s stopping points every few hundred yards because there&rsquo;s that many photogenic scenes.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/mountains.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/mountains.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Vistas</div>
</div>


<p>Here&rsquo;s a panorama:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/east-coast/blue-ridge-parkway.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/east-coast/blue-ridge-parkway.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Panorama of the Blue Ridge Parkway</div>
</div>


<p>We were heading east across North Carolina to our next destination: Asheville. I&rsquo;ll write about that and our time in Raleigh in my next post!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
