<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Toronto | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/toronto/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-14T17:34:05-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bar Chef]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/20/bar-chef/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-20T12:10:44-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/20/bar-chef</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>We&#8217;ve been using <a href="http://www.worldsbestbars.com/">World&#8217;s Best Bars</a> to find bars when we&#8217;ve been travelling. It&#8217;s a little hit-and-miss, and you need to do some extra research before you randomly pick one. But it&#8217;s great if you&#8217;re in a place that doesn&#8217;t really use Yelp or FourSquare. We showed it to Mike and Melissa, and they laughed at a lot of the choices for Toronto. One, however, they recommended: <a href="http://www.barcheftoronto.com/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">Bar Chef</span></a>.</p>

  <p>It&#8217;s in the second-coolest neighbourhood in the world (according to <a href="http://www.vogue.com/slideshow/1080625/fifteen-coolest-street-style-neighborhoods/">Vogue</a>) – Queen Street West. They serve fancy cocktails and want to &#8220;challenge the [&#8230;] cocktail experience.&#8221; SOUNDS FUN!</p>

  <p>Oh, it was dark inside, so most of my photos are a little grainy. Sorry.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/barchef.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/barchef.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Bar Chef placemat</div>
  </div>

  <p>We started out with two normal-ish cocktails. The Symphony No 5 was a gin/vanilla thing that was OK. The Basil Daiquiri was tasty – super-drinkable.

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/symphony-daiquiri.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/symphony-daiquiri.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Symphony No. 5 and the Basil Daiquiri</div>
  </div>

  <p>These two cocktails were pretty good. However, we noticed there was a &#8220;modernist&#8221; section that had more expensive ones – some with some weird ingredients (&#8220;spring fog&#8221;? &#8220;beach essence&#8221;?).</p>

  <p>Hampton got a $45 (!) Manhattan. It came under a giant cloche filled with smoke.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/manhattan-cloche.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/manhattan-cloche.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Cloche full of smoke</div>
  </div>

  <p>It rested on the table for a minute or two before the bartender came over and slowly swirled the cloche off the top of the pedestal. Underneath was the smokey Manhattan!</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/manhattan.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/manhattan.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Manhattan</div>
  </div>

  <p>It was seriously smokey. Even though I was only sat next to Hampton, my clothes smelt like a wood fire for the next day.</p>

  <p>The next modernist cocktail we got was the Black Truffle. It came with six tiny spoons. The spoons had a coconut foam/lime dust mixture on them. You were supposed to eat one of those, then drink the gin-based concoction. Those spoons were amazing, and they went well with the drink. The drink had elderflower in it, too, so I loved it.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/black-truffle.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/black-truffle.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Black Truffle</div>
  </div>

  <p>Next up, there was a Cedar. It came on a wood platter set up like a zen garden. There was a sprig of cedar in one corner, some cacao &#8220;soil&#8221; and chunks of pear. You dip the pear in the &#8220;soil,&#8221; and eat that before you drink. I didn&#8217;t get much from the food bit, but the drink (a gin-chamomile-pear thing) was clean and fresh.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/cedar.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/cedar.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Cedar</div>
  </div>

  <p>I think the weirdest drink of the night was the Spring Thaw. It came in a tiny glass surrounded by moss. The bartender came over and poured water (?) over the moss, and it started misting. I&#8217;m guessing there was perfumed dry ice in there somewhere – it smelled just like a spring forest.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/spring-thaw-mist.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/spring-thaw-mist.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Spring thawing all over the table</div>
  </div>

  <p>The cocktail itself was a gin-campari thing. It had a campari sorbet of some kind, and as you were drinking the sorbet melted into the rest. It&#8217;s a neat concept, but it was strange that the drink got more and more bitter as you went on.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/spring-thaw.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/barchef/spring-thaw.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The Spring Thaw cocktail itself</div>
  </div>

  <p>We also got a punch bowl, which I&#8217;d recommend if you&#8217;re tired of the pomp around the other cocktails.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">I love any kind of ceremony or ostentation around food and drink. There&#8217;s something fun about the process – in these cases, eating something special before you drink, or smelling a fog that surrounds your glass. So I&#8217;m already inclined to like a place like this – and I did. A lot. It&#8217;s definitely not cheap, though, and certainly not a casual after-work-drinks kinda place.</span></p>


  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">9.0</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Momofuku and Other Toronto Eats]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/16/daisho/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-16T10:15:28-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/16/daisho</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve enjoyed watching <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Chang">David Chang&rsquo;s</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Momofuku_(restaurants)">Momofuku</a> empire grow, but I&rsquo;ve never had the opportunity to eat at one of his restaurants. As he hasn&rsquo;t opened a restaurant in San Francisco, the closest I&rsquo;ve got is reading <a href="http://lky.ph/">Lucky Peach</a>. I was super excited to go to one of his restaurants in Toronto.</p>

<p>There are four Momofuku properties in Toronto – all housed in the same building. In order of increasing fanciness, they are Noodle Bar, Nikai (a cocktail bar), Daishō and Shōtō. The building is pretty cool – it almost looks like an Apple store with its glass exterior and giant Momofuku sign.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/momofuku.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/momofuku.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Momofuku sign</div>
</div>


<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toronto_International_Film_Festival">Toronto International Film Festival</a> is going on, and right next to the Momofuku building is the Shangri-la hotel. On its third-floor deck, there was a pre-premiere party for a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wild_(film)">new Reese Witherspoon film</a>. From our table we could see right into the pre-party and had a lot of fun figuring out what it was for. We saw <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Evans_(actor)">Chris Evans</a> there! But we didn&rsquo;t see Reese Witherspoon.</p>

<p>Anyway, onto the food. We were eating at Daishō, which has a bunch of smaller dishes plus some larger, 4-10 person plates if you want to do that. They also have a small, but interesting, cocktail list. I got a bijou and it was nicely done (although you couldn&rsquo;t really taste the Chartreuse).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/cocktail.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/cocktail.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Bijou and menu</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/whiskey-flight.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/whiskey-flight.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hampton got a whiskey flight</div>
</div>


<p>Momofuku is known for its buns, so we got some duck and shrimp versions. It was strange seeing the duck come in patty form – but it tasted absolutely amazing, so I didn&rsquo;t care.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/duck-bun.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/duck-bun.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Duck bun</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/shrimp-bun.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/shrimp-bun.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Shrimp bun</div>
</div>


<p>The steak tartare was made with such tender beef. They added enough yolk to keep it glossy, without it being too sloppy. Plus it has sunflower seeds in it which added some nice texture. One of the best tartares I&rsquo;ve had.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/tartare.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/tartare.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Steak tartare</div>
</div>


<p>The other popular thing on the menu is the ssäm (pronounced with a long &ldquo;a&rdquo;, like psalm). <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ssam">Ssäm</a> is a Korean dish whereby you wrap meat inside a large lettuce leaf. It&rsquo;s a make-your-own lettuce wrap kinda thing. We decided to go for the secreto ssäm, mainly because we didn&rsquo;t know what secreto was (turns out it&rsquo;s a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Iberian_pig">cut of pork</a>). It was really delicious!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/ssam.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/ssam.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Secreto Ssäm</div>
</div>


<p>We also ordered some crab cakes, which came out looking a lot more different than I thought. Turns out Korean-style crab cakes aren&rsquo;t patty-shaped. They&rsquo;re long tube-like things that aren&rsquo;t totally unlike crab sticks. They came in a spicy sauce, too.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crab-cakes.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crab-cakes.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Korean-style crab cakes</div>
</div>


<p>Despite being fit to burst at this point, we were recommended the crack pie. IT WAS AMAZING. That&rsquo;s about all I can say. If you have an opportunity, get it.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crack-pie.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/daisho/crack-pie.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Crack pie</div>
</div>


<p>As well as Daishō, there were a bunch of other awesome places we ate at.</p>

<p><a href="http://guu-izakaya.com/sakabar">Guu Sakabar</a> is an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Izakaya">izakaya</a>-style bar/restaurant. They have a bunch of smaller dishes on the <a href="http://guu-izakaya.com/docs/sakabar_menu1.pdf">menu</a>, and you order a few each and share. They have a wide range of stuff, from standard (like takoyaki) to weird (udon carbonara?). My favourite was kabocha korokke – a pumpkin croquette thing with a boiled egg in the middle, served with a sauce that was kinda like thousand island dressing.</p>

<p>They had an Ontario-produced sake which I can&rsquo;t find on the menu but it was delicious.</p>

<p><a href="http://416snackbar.wordpress.com/">416 Snack Bar</a> is a hipster tapas-style place. They had chalkboard on the walls and don&rsquo;t offer you any cutlery. The best thing here was either the foie torchon or the steak tartare.</p>

<p>The other place I enjoyed was <a href="http://patriatoronto.com/">Patria</a>, a Spanish tapas restaurant (all the places we went to were tapas, it seems). They had great authentic Spanish-style food (even jamón Ibérico!) plus some tasty sangria. We got a cornish hen paella, which was weird but worked pretty well.</p>

<p>These restaurants barely scratch the surface of Toronto, I&rsquo;m sure. We&rsquo;ve eaten really well here, no doubt due to the excellent choices of our friends <a href="http://twitter.com/mferrier">Mike</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/melissaiscool">Melissa</a> who pretty much recommended/chose all of these places to eat at.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Life Gives You Paekrosul: Making a North Korean Cocktail]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/10/north-korean-brandy-cocktail/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-10T11:24:50-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/09/10/north-korean-brandy-cocktail</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We made it to Toronto! But more on that later. What&rsquo;s more important is drinking unusual alcohol. While in Toronto, we&rsquo;ve been hanging out with two of our awesome friends, <a href="http://twitter.com/mferrier">Mike</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/melissaiscool">Melissa</a>. Last year, they visited the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Korean_Demilitarized_Zone">DMZ</a>, and <a href="http://melissadreamsofsushi.com/?p=6587">bought a bottle of North Korean brandy</a> known as Paekrosul.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/paekrosul.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/paekrosul.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Paekrosul</div>
</div>


<p>Apparently its name translates as <a href="http://www.physics.uq.edu.au/people/nieminen/chiew.html">&ldquo;Hundred-Years Liquour&rdquo;</a>, which is certainly promising.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/made-in-dprk.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/made-in-dprk.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">For realz made in DPR Korea</div>
</div>


<p>The bottle was a little tatty, and it was stoppered with a plastic cork. Inside, there was a bit of sandy sediment. Feeling the risk of going blind was one worth taking, we opened the bottle and poured ourselves a (small) glass.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/glass.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/glass.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Paekrosul, neat</div>
</div>


<p>I thought it smelled a lot like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baijiu">baiju</a>, a Chinese liquour that my Dad always gets as a business gift. Others described it as having more of a turpentine aroma.</p>

<p>Despite its nose-burning smell, it tasted fine. Harsh at first, it quickly becomes sweeter and it didn&rsquo;t have a burning aftertaste that you get with a lot of high-proof drinks. No one really wanted to drink much more than a sip, though. What do you do when you have alcohol that no one&rsquo;s going to drink neat? You make a cocktail of course!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/cocktail-time.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/cocktail-time.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Time to make a cocktail</div>
</div>


<p>Mike and Melissa have a well-stocked bar, so I had a lot of stuff to work with. But where to begin? I looked online for some brandy cocktails to see if I could modify them. One suggestion was the <a href="http://cocktails.about.com/od/atozcocktailrecipes/r/mtropltn_cktl.htm">metropolitan</a> – like a manhattan but with brandy instead of whiskey. I used one part sweet vermouth to three parts Paekrosul, plus some Angostura for good measure. It didn&rsquo;t taste that great, though. As the Paekrosul was sweet already, the vermouth didn&rsquo;t contribute much. Plus the main off-putting thing about Paekrosul was the smell. Neither the vermouth nor the bitters covered that up. Time to try a different route.</p>

<p>My favourite cocktails are all citrus-based. Citrus fruits also tend to have pretty strong aromas, so I thought using lemon or lime might be good.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/citrus.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/citrus.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Adding citrus makes everything better</div>
</div>


<p>I mixed in some lemon juice and it tasted pretty good. It tasted even better if you used a lemon peel as a garnish. Twisting the peel to spray the citrus oil over the drink covered up the turpentine smell pretty well.</p>

<p>I tried it with lime but it didn&rsquo;t work as well – the lime flavour wasn&rsquo;t strong enough.</p>

<p>I also ended up adding some <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cointreau">Cointreau triple sec</a> to the mix to add a little more citrus and sweetness.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/cocktail.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/cocktail.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The final drink</div>
</div>


<p>Ta-da! It wasn&rsquo;t the best cocktail I&rsquo;ve ever made, but I think I did a good job of mostly masking the worst flavours of the Paekrosul while keeping its more distinctive flavours. I&rsquo;m pretty sure by next summer it will be on every speakeasy menu from Brooklyn to the Mission.</p>

<p>I haven&rsquo;t come up with a witty name yet, so suggestions are welcome.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/ingredients.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/toronto/dprk/ingredients.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Final ingredients</div>
</div>


<p>If you have some Paekrosul , is as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li>3 parts Paekrosul</li>
<li>1 part Triple Sec</li>
<li>1 part lemon juice</li>
<li>Stir over ice, serve with an ice cube and lemon peel garnish.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
