<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tasting-menu | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/tasting-menu/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-23T13:24:37+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[La Degustation]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/27/la-degustation/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-27T10:30:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/27/la-degustation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p><a href="http://www.ladegustation.cz/en/#index"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">La Degustation</span></a>, one of two restaurants in Prague to have <a href="http://www.viamichelin.com/web/Restaurants/Restaurants-Prague-_-Praha_hlavni_mesto-Czech_Republic?strLocid=31MzhkeDEwY05UQXVNRGczT0RFPWNNVFF1TkRJd05EWT0=">a Michelin star</a>, was our special treat as our time in Prague is coming to an end. Its slogan is "bohême bourgeoise," which I found amusing.</p>

  <p>Inside, I don't know if anything can be gothic minimalist, but I think that's an accurate description. Arches ribbed the ceiling, and artfully-placed dim spotlights created wonderful shadows. The walls were bare and painted a light grey, and the furniture was all low-backed and dark wood. The windows onto the street had the restaurant's signature checkered pattern.</p>

  <p>As we sat down, the waiter came over and gave us an envelope.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/envelope.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/envelope.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">We were handed an envelope</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/back-envelope.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/back-envelope.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">The back of the envelope</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/contents.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/contents.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Open it to find the checkered pattern</div>
  </div>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/menu.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/degustation/menu.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Two menu options</div>
  </div>

  <p>We went for the eleven-course menu, with wine pairings. It was definitely a lot of food, and I wish I hadn't eaten so much of the delicious bread they brought. The menu focussed on Czech ingredients and dishes, but with modern, vaguely molecular-gastronomic twists. Apparently a lot of the inspiration for their dishes comes from a late-19th century Czech cookbook.</p>

  <p>I didn't take pictures and I won't bore you with a course-by-course detailing of everything. A couple of stand-out dishes, though: dijon mustard ice-cream with hot tomato sauce. The sauce was the perfect distillation of tomato flavour. Add that to the mustard (which wasn't too spicy), plus the mixing of the hot sauce with the cold ice-cream and you get an incredible dish that's not quite like anything I've had before.</p>

  <p>There was a foie gras course where the liver had been finely grated over wine jelly and pistachio. I'd never eaten foie gras grated before, and it really helped take away the heaviness you sometimes get. Then there was the beef tongue "signature dish." </p>

  <p>I really enjoyed the wine pairings. They used mostly Czech wines, and it was nice to see the variety in types they produce here. There was also a great unfiltered Slovenian wine called <a href="http://www.scurek.com/www/index.php/en/wines/white-wines">Kontra</a>. The cheese course came with a delicious IPA from the <a href="http://www.beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/23493/">Matuška Brewery</a>.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">If you're willing to splash out, this place is definitely worth it. It's a modern take on Czech flavours and ingredients, and the courses are presented beautifully.</span></p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">9.3</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Columbia Room]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/04/25/the-columbia-room/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-25T19:29:59+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/04/25/the-columbia-room</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div itemprop="description">

  <p>I was glad our friend had already been to <a href="http://columbiaroomdc.com/"><span itemprop="itemreviewed">The Columbia Room</span></a> and met us outside, otherwise I don't think we would have been able to find it. It's hidden in the back of an upscale dive bar called The Passenger on 7th St in D.C. Inside, it's tiny (I think there were ten seats) and sparsely-decorated (some apothecary-style bottles with herbs were behind the bar). The service, level of expertise from the bartenders, and the inventiveness of flavour pairings reminded me of the few Michelin-starred restaurants I've been to. Except with liquor instead of food.</p>

  <p>The set menu consists of three drinks and a couple of snacks, coming in at around $65 per person. Pricey, but definitely worth it.</p>

  <!-- more -->

  <p>After being offered cold towels scented with cucumber (!), we started out with a rum and lemon-based punch served in a teacup. It tasted pretty much like iced tea – but, y'know, alcoholic. So better than regular iced tea.</p>

  <p>The second drink, the Getaway, had two main ingredients: a black rum and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cynar">cynar</a> (<em>chee</em>-nar). </p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/dc/getaway-ingredients.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/dc/getaway-ingredients.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Ingredients for the Getaway</div>
  </div>

  <p>Cynar is a dark brown artichoke-based liqueur. It has a number of other spices in it, so it's not like you're drinking artichoke juice or anything. Mixed with the dark rum, some salted bitters and a bit of lemon, and wow. With each sip you went through four or five different flavour profiles – acidity of the lemon, saltiness, herbs, molasses. It was extremely drinkable and all three of us had to pace ourselves so we didn't finish it in two gulps.</p>

  <p>The Getaway was served with an artichoke (to pair with the cynar) and green olive tapenade-type thing. It was pretty tasty, but I wish there had been more of it. Or maybe I should have eaten more for dinner.</p>

  <p>For last cocktail of the set, we had a choice. Either a cynar and grapefruit/blood orange soda <strong>or</strong> a cynar and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Akvavit">akvavit</a> combination. Two of us plumped for the cynar/aquavit drink – it tasted a lot like a negroni. The soda drink was refreshing and a nice end to the tasting.</p>

  <p>As the previous cocktails were so good, we decided to stay for another one each. We asked the bartender for two gin-based drinks – one with citrus and one without.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/dc/dry-martini.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/dc/dry-martini.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Dry Martini</div>
  </div>

  <p>Hampton got a dry martini with Plymouth gin. It was pretty delicious. The bartender recommended Plymouth as a good go-to gin that mixes well with other ingredients.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/dc/last-word-ingredients.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/dc/last-word-ingredients.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Last Word Ingredients</div>
  </div>

  <p>I received a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Word_(cocktail)">Last Word</a> – Tanqueray 10 gin, Luxardo <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maraschino">maraschino liqueur</a>, lime juice and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chartreuse_(liqueur)">Chartreuse</a>. I had been drinking Chartreuse the previous Saturday, both neat and in a Chartreuse gimlet. I liked it a lot, so I was pretty excited it came up in the cocktail the bartender made for me here.</p>

  <p>The Maraschino liqueur was strange. I'm familiar with Luxardo-style maraschino cherries, so was expecting the liqueuer to be a deep purple syrup. However, it looked and tasted more like a simple syrup that had a hint of cherry flavour.</p>

  <div class="img">
    <a href="/images/the-journey/dc/last-word-cocktail.jpg">
      <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/dc/last-word-cocktail.jpg">
    </a>
    <div class="alt">Last Word</div>
  </div>

  <p>Mixing all of them together was amazing. The freshness of the limes worked well with the herbal qualities of the gin and the Chartreuse. The Maraschino added a touch of sweetness to round it all out. Apparently, the bartender likes to put a little more gin compared to normal Last Word-style drinks, which is what he said gives his the edge over the competition.</p>

  <p><span itemprop="summary">I highly recommend visiting this place if you're in the D.C. area.</span> We managed to make reservations a couple of weeks in advance for a Wednesday night. I hear the building is being taken over soon – although I assume they will be moving to a new location.</p>

  <p class="score">
    <span itemprop="rating" itemscope itemtype="http://data-vocabulary.org/Rating">
      <span itemprop="value">9.1</span> 
      <meta itemprop="best" content="10"/> / 10
    </span> 
  </p>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Midsummer House: 22nd December 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2013/01/05/midsummer-house/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-05T19:10:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2013/01/05/midsummer-house</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We were in the UK for Christmas, and my parents told us to keep one evening free from seeing our friends &ndash; they had a plan. They didn&rsquo;t tell us what it was &ndash; not even on the cab ride there. We were equally intrigued (what could it be? It had to be dinner, right?) and anxious (what if we didn&rsquo;t like it?).</p>

<p>As we entered the backroads of northern Cambridge, we realised we were going to <a href="http://www.midsummerhouse.co.uk/">Midsummer House</a>, the 2-Michelin-starred restaurant where we got married just over three years ago. Needless to say, we were both incredibly excited. We had the tasting menu with wine pairings, and it was incredible. I think it supersedes other meals I&rsquo;ve had there to be the best meal of my life. I took some pictures, so here you go:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/bloody-mary.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/bloody-mary.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Bloody Mary amuse-bouche
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/goats-cheese.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/goats-cheese.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Celery, goat's cheese, and horseradish ice-cream.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/scallop.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/scallop.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Sautéed scallop, celeriac and truffle.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/trestle.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/trestle.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Before the third course arrived, we had this placed in front of us...
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/sweetbreads.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/sweetbreads.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Turns out, it was to hold this: sweetbreads, pistachio, maple syrup and mouli.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/brill.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/brill.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Roast brill, surf clams, cucumber, wasabi, sorrel.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/beef.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/beef.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Beef fillet, sautéed tongue, horseradish, turnip and Paris browns.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/pousse-cafe.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/pousse-cafe.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Pousse-café - maple syrup, egg-yolk, and Jack Daniels and chive foam.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/kumkwats.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/kumkwats.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Poached kumquats with lemon and thyme ice-cream.
  </div>
</div>


<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/midsummer-house/chocolate.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/midsummer-house/chocolate.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">
    Chocolate, caramel and chestnuts, chestnut frangipane.
  </div>
</div>


<p>I missed two courses: a broccoli, pear and blue cheese starter and an apple crumble thing with baked yoghurt. Both were intense and I must have dove in without thinking to take a picture.</p>

<p>The meal took four hours and I loved every minute of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
