<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Walking-tour | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/walking-tour/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-10T14:08:43-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Touring the Jewish Quarter of Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/25/jewish-quarter-prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-25T06:58:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/25/jewish-quarter-prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Josefov">Jewish Quarter</a> (or Josefov) of Prague is in the Old Town, just north of the Old Town Square. We&rsquo;d been told that the <a href="http://www.jewishmuseum.cz/en/apinkas.htm">Pinkas Synagogue</a> was a must-see, so we set off on a visit without learning much about it. All I knew was that it&rsquo;s now a memorial to victims of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Holocaust">Holocaust</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Pinkas Synagogue from the outside</div>
</div>


<p>We arrived at lunchtime and the queue was really long and slow-moving. Not good.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-queue.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-queue.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Long queue waiting for tickets</div>
</div>


<p>However! We found an EXPERT WORK-AROUND for buying tickets without having to wait in line. Head slightly east on the same road and take the first left. You&rsquo;ll find <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Maiselova+38%2F15,+110+00+Praha-Praha+1,+Czech+Republic/@50.089592,14.4181715,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x470b94e8669ff2a5:0xb73abb80fc435169">a ticketing office</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ticket-office.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ticket-office.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Just around the corner – under 2 mins walk.</div>
</div>


<p>There was no queue and we got our tickets immediately. You can&rsquo;t buy a single ticket to see the synagogues/museums of Josefov individually – you have to buy a multi-attraction ticket. The most basic ticket was 300Kč (~$15) for four attractions: the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Jewish_Cemetery,_Prague">Old Jewish Cemetery</a>, the <a href="http://www.jewishmuseum.cz/en/aklaus.htm">Klausen Synagogue</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jewish_Ceremonial_Hall,_Prague">Ceremonial Hall</a>, and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_Synagogue_(Prague)">Spanish Synagogue</a>. You could pay 100Kč more if you wanted to see the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_New_Synagogue,_Prague">Old New Synagogue</a>, but we gave that one a miss. The ticket is valid over seven days, though, which is good if you don&rsquo;t have enough time to visit all the places in one day.</p>

<p>After we bought our tickets we went back to the Pinkas Synagogue and sailed past the line there to buy tickets.</p>

<p>The inside of the Pinkas Synagogue serves as a memorial to the 80,000 Bohemian and Moravian Jews that were victims of the Holocaust.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-room.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-room.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside the synagogue</div>
</div>


<p>There were about five rooms like the one above – and see those red and black, floor-to-ceiling patches that line the walls? Those are the victims&#8217; names, birth-dates and death-dates. Across the rooms they&rsquo;re written out like that, in letters maybe a centimetre high.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-names.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/pinkas-names.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Names, births and deaths of victims</div>
</div>


<p>At first, you don&rsquo;t quite understand it. Then as you start reading, seeing the families grouped together, it&rsquo;s a little overwhelming. Especially when you see room after room of them. It was powerful stuff, and something I&rsquo;d recommend everyone do while they&rsquo;re in Prague.</p>

<p>After exiting the synagogue, you walk through the Old Jewish Cemetery. While not that large geographically, it apparently contains over 12,000 tombstones.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Old Jewish Cemetery</div>
</div>


<p>Needless to say, it was crowded with graves. The tombstones stuck out at all kinds of angles, and many were only just sticking out of the soil.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery2.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/cemetery2.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Another view of the cemetery</div>
</div>


<p>The cemetary exit leaves you just outside of Ceremonial Hall and the Klausen Synagogue. As we already had the multi-ticket, we decided to give them a visit.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Ceremonial Hall outside</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall-floor.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/ceremonial-hall-floor.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Ceremonial Hall tiled floor</div>
</div>


<p>The Ceremonial Hall used to be a kind of mortuary, so had a bunch of exhibits on the rituals surrounding death in Judaism. It was kind of interesting, but mostly just items in display cases.</p>

<p>The Klausen Synagogue was similar. Apart from the Pinkas Synagogue earlier on, I&rsquo;d never been inside a synagogue before. I&rsquo;m not quite sure what I was expecting from the inside of a synagogue, but I was kind of disappointed that it looked just like a Christian church.</p>

<p>Inside the main area of the Klausen Synagogue, there were display cases showing items relating to Judaism. I found it a little strange. I almost wanted the museum part and the religious-building part to be more separate. Maybe it&rsquo;s just because I wasn&rsquo;t expecting it to be so much of a museum.</p>

<p>After leaving the Klausen Synagogue, the route to the next stop on our ticket took us past the Old New Synagogue. I only learnt afterwards that it&rsquo;s Europe&rsquo;s oldest active synagogue. Apparently, its attic is also the storage place for the infamous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golem#The_classic_narrative:_The_Golem_of_Prague">Golem of Prague</a> (<em>spooky noises</em>).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/old-new.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/old-new.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Old New Synagogue</div>
</div>


<p>We continued walking, made a couple of quick turns, and found ourselves at the Spanish Synagogue. Not much to look at from the outside, inside it&rsquo;s absolutely stunning.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Spanish Synagogue interior</div>
</div>


<p>The walls are covered in intricate patterns, mostly using reds and golds. The Star of David appears in motifs everywhere, and I spent ages just following the patterns and their interplay across the walls. The central dome is beautiful and has a Star of David-shaped chandelier in the centre.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish-dome.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/josefov/spanish-dome.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Dome of the Spanish Synagogue</div>
</div>


<p>Fun fact: it doesn&rsquo;t seem to be clear why it&rsquo;s called the Spanish Synagogue. One theory is that the interior design reminded people of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golden_age_of_Jewish_culture_in_Spain">&ldquo;Golden Age&rdquo;</a> of Judaism in Spain. Another theory is that it used to be a location for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romaniotes">Byzantine Jewish</a> worship, and that led to legends of the Iberian <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sephardi_Jews">Sephardi Jews</a> once worshipping there.</p>

<p>Like the Klausen Synagogue, the Spanish Synagogue is a museum as well as a religious building. I was mostly distracted by the detailing on the walls, but I did look at a couple of the display cases in the upper balconies. They were pretty interesting, detailing the history of Josefov across the centuries. If it hadn&rsquo;t been over 30ºC in there, I would have stayed longer.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m glad we ended up seeing more of the Jewish Quarter than just the Pinkas Synagogue, but I&rsquo;m not sure I&rsquo;d see the Klausen Synagogu and the Ceremonial Hall if I were pushed for time. I definitely found it more rewarding than most of Prague Castle, though. I made a <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/dir/Maiselova+38%2F15,+110+00+Praha,+Czech+Republic/Pinkas+Synagogue,+%C5%A0irok%C3%A1+23%2F3,+110+00+Praha,+Czech+Republic/Klausov%C3%A1+synagoga,+U+star%C3%A9ho+h%C5%99bitova+3a,+110+00+Praha-Josefov,+Czech+Republic/The+Old-New+Synagogue,+Maiselova+18,+110+01+Praha+1,+Czech+Republic/50.0900973,14.4211259/@50.090032,14.4178231,18z/data=!4m32!4m31!1m5!1m1!1s0x470b94e8669ff2a5:0xb73abb80fc435169!2m2!1d14.4181715!2d50.089592!1m5!1m1!1s0x470b94e85e9af185:0x294f2ae19539722d!2m2!1d14.416972!2d50.089277!1m5!1m1!1s0x470b94e877e558db:0xdd1a2cc59bf35380!2m2!1d14.417069!2d50.09002!1m10!1m1!1s0x470b94e868e5c8c9:0x94be0e2fdb884bfa!2m2!1d14.418567!2d50.090051!3m4!1m2!1d14.4190562!2d50.0899754!3s0x470b94e844b3b4d3:0x32c184f0e15a1660!1m0!3e2">map of the route we took</a> – but note that the bit from the Pinkas to Klausen is through the cemetery rather than around Maiselova.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prague]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/01/prague/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-01T08:43:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/07/01/prague</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve heard many people say how much they like Prague. I&rsquo;ve also heard many people say how much charm Prague has lost since the mid-90s, how it&rsquo;s now filled with tourists. I wasn&rsquo;t quite sure what to expect. Would it be inviting and elegant, or a tourist-trap nightmare?</p>

<p>Well, we&rsquo;ve been here for three weeks, and I can safely say we both love the city. We love it so much we&rsquo;re planning on extending our time here until the end of July. It&rsquo;s got a mix of many things we enjoy about other European cities: the architectural beauty of Paris, the efficient transit of Berlin, the edginess (and cheapness) of Gdańsk. Plus, as I <a href="/blog/2014/06/20/hemingway-bar-prague">mentioned previously</a>, it has great cocktails.</p>

<p>The first seven days we were here, four nights had fireworks displays. There was a <a href="http://unitedislands.cz/">free music festival</a> the other weekend. There was <a href="http://www.prazskamuzejninoc.cz/">Prague Museum Night</a>, where museums stayed open until late at night. There&rsquo;s usually an open-air concert on <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/St%C5%99eleck%C3%BD+ostrov/@50.08048,14.410501,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x20fab08b45c47614">this island in the Vltava</a>. It seems like there&rsquo;s always something happening, and I think that&rsquo;s one of the main reasons we&rsquo;ve been drawn to Prague as a livable city.</p>

<p>Having said all of that&hellip; there are a tonne of tourists in certain areas – and this is where I maybe see why some people say Prague has lost its charm. We are (thankfully) staying about 10 minutes&#8217; walk from the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Town_Square_(Prague)">Old Town Square</a>. We can easily get there if we want to see the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prague_Orloj">Astronomical Clock</a> chime, but we&rsquo;re not trapped by the tourists.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/oldtownsq.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/oldtownsq.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">All the tourists, ever</div>
</div>


<p>It&rsquo;s overwhelming, for sure. Cross into the Old Town and you pretty much hear only English being spoken. If you&rsquo;re thinking of staying in Prague, I&rsquo;d try and avoid that area if possible. The city is extremely walkable, so staying a little outside the centre shouldn&rsquo;t be a problem. We&rsquo;re just south of Národní, which is perfect.</p>

<p>Anyway, I&rsquo;ve jotted down some thoughts on the tourist-type stuff we&rsquo;ve done.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The first thing we did, and the first thing I&rsquo;d suggest doing, is a self-guided walking tour. I&rsquo;ve been thoroughly impressed with the Rick Steves walking tours we&rsquo;ve done in previous cities, and his <a href="https://www.ricksteves.com/watch-read-listen/audio/audio-tours/eastern-europe">Prague city walk tour</a> was no different. The tour is available as a free podcast and takes about two or three hours. The recording itself is just over one hour, but we stopped in museums and cafés as we went.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/ourladyoftyn.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/ourladyoftyn.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Listening to Rick in the Old Town Square</div>
</div>


<p>The tour covers a lot of the history of not just Prague, but the Czech Republic as a whole. I was completely ignorant of the recent history of the country and found the descriptions of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jan_Palach">Jan Palach&rsquo;s suicide</a> and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Velvet_Revolution">Velvet Revolution</a> quite stirring. You end up seeing all the main sights of Prague, which is great to orientate yourself. You can then go back and check out places that you find interesting on a different day (or stop along the way, as we did).</p>

<p>Another pretty common tourist thing to visit is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prague_castle">Prague Castle</a>, which you can see from most places in Prague. We decided to foolishly climb up. I would not recommend it – it&rsquo;s a pretty steep climb. Take transit there instead!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/viewfromcastle.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/viewfromcastle.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Those are the steps we had to climb up</div>
</div>


<p>The castle itself is apparently one of the largest castle complexes in the world. It&rsquo;s the seat of the President of the Czech Republic and has a bunch of government offices too. It&rsquo;s pretty cool, but&hellip; I wouldn&rsquo;t necessarily recommend it if you&rsquo;re only here for a couple of days.</p>

<p>There are a couple of ticket options – one has four of the major sights, the other has all ten of them. We went for the four-sight option, which was plenty. The audioguides were all out of battery (?!) when we went on a Monday, so that meant we didn&rsquo;t get quite as much information out of our visit. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._Vitus_Cathedral">St Vitus&#8217; Cathedral</a> was the highlight by a long shot. It had some gorgeous art nouveau stained glass windows.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/stvitusstainedglass.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/stvitusstainedglass.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Stained glass windows by Alphonse Mucha</div>
</div>


<p>The other attractions (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._George%27s_Basilica,_Prague">St George&rsquo;s Basilica</a>, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Royal_Palace_(Prague)">Old Royal Palace</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golden_Lane">Golden Lane</a>) were&hellip; not as impressive. The Basilica had some interesting old murals, the Old Royal Palace had the infamous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Defenestrations_of_Prague">defenestration</a> window. Golden Lane was just a bunch of tourist shops, so I&rsquo;m not sure why it was included as an &ldquo;attraction&rdquo; in the ticket price.</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pet%C5%99%C3%ADn">Petřín Hill</a> is another imposing feature on the Prague skyline. We took the funicular to the top, which Hampton enjoyed because he loves funiculars. Apart from that, there wasn&rsquo;t much up there. Looking at the hill, it&rsquo;s covered in trees. We didn&rsquo;t quite realise that that meant there&rsquo;d be no view from the top of the hill. All you can see from up there is forest, pretty much. You could pay 100Kč or so (~$5) to go up a replica of the Eiffel Tower, which I&rsquo;m sure had better views, but we decided to spend our money instead on an old mirror maze.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/prague/houseofmirrors.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/prague/houseofmirrors.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">19th century mirror maze</div>
</div>


<p>The walk down is pleasant, so if it&rsquo;s a nice day I&rsquo;d recommend taking a trip.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s about all the tourist stuff we have done. Like I said, we&rsquo;ve mostly enjoyed the non-tourist stuff here. It&rsquo;s a great city to explore, especially with the number of parks for lazing and the random outdoor concerts we&rsquo;ve experienced. A great site we&rsquo;ve been using is <a href="http://www.expats.cz/">Expats.cz</a>, which has a list of events going on every day.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Street Art in the Butte-aux-Cailles, Paris]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/19/street-art-butte-aux-cailles/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-19T06:43:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/19/street-art-butte-aux-cailles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our first major stop in Europe has been Paris. We&rsquo;re staying in an area new to us: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Butte-aux-Cailles">la Butte-aux-Cailles</a>. It&rsquo;s in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/13th_arrondissement_of_Paris">13th arrondissement</a> of Paris, in the south-east of the city.</p>

<p>The neighbourhood has a small-town feel, and isn&rsquo;t touristy at all. I&rsquo;ve only encountered other English-speakers when I&rsquo;ve left the area. It&rsquo;s fairly easy to get to other places, as the nearby <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Place_d'Italie">Place d&#8217;Italie</a> has a number of lines from its Métro stop.</p>

<p>There are a decent number of bars, cafés and restaurants on <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Rue+de+la+Butte+aux+Cailles/@48.8277143,2.3498739,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x47e67190f05e1315:0x4771112c8d0bf60b">the main street</a>. From about 6pm to midnight, they&rsquo;re packed with people – so much so, that there&rsquo;s often a crowd spilling out onto the street. It&rsquo;s a little strange for a neighbourhood that&rsquo;s fairly quiet the rest of the time.</p>

<p>Anyway, the thing that struck me the most about the area was that it seems to have a large amount of street art (apparently <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-03-26/how-overprotective-paris-became-the-center-of-street-art-.html">Paris is becoming the &ldquo;center of street art&rdquo;</a>). Every wall seems to have something beautiful or provocative on it.</p>

<p>The most famous (as far as I can tell) street art in the area is done by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sampsa_(street_artist)">Sampsa</a>, the &ldquo;Finnish Banksy.&rdquo;</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/hadopi-2.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/hadopi-2.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">HADOPI gang</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/hadopi.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/hadopi.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Close-up of a HADOPI enforcer</div>
</div>


<p>The two pieces by Sampsa were in protest of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HADOPI_law">HADOPI law</a> – a copyright infringement law from around 2009. Amusingly, the first logo for the HADOPI agency used <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/europe/france/6974249/Anti-piracy-agencys-logo-broke-copyright.html">a typeface without appropriate licensing</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/blood-sucking.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/blood-sucking.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The blood sucking HADOPI</div>
</div>


<p>The mosquito art was <a href="http://motherboard.vice.com/blog/paris-censored-anti-copyright-street-art">censored for a while</a> – removing the &ldquo;Blood sucking HADOPI&rdquo; line. But apparently it has been recently restored.</p>

<p>There are a bunch artworks done in mostly muted blues and greys. They&rsquo;re all of children. At first glance, they&rsquo;re kind of peaceful.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/boat.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/boat.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Boat</div>
</div>


<p>However when I started to study them there was something unnerving about them. The children never had faces.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/boy.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/boy.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Painter boy</div>
</div>


<p>As well as the lack of faces, the children are usually disappearing. They&rsquo;re walking through a waterfall or curtain into another world. Or they&rsquo;re being partially submerged. They&rsquo;re a little eerie.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/kneel.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/kneel.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Kneeling</div>
</div>


<p><a href="http://www.missticinparis.com/">Miss.tic</a> is another artist with a lot of works in the area. According to <a href="http://www.missticinparis.com/misstic_biographie.html">her biography page</a>, she&rsquo;s almost 60 years old. She has a bunch of stencils that tend to be of provocatively-posed ladies with humourous or ironic captions.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve done my best to translate the captions, but they&rsquo;ll no doubt be a little off. If anyone wants to correct me, please do!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic1.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic1.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;I have men-ancholy&#8221; (I think it&#8217;s a pun on &#8220;avoir du vague à l&#8217;âme,&#8221; meaning &#8220;to be melancholy&#8221;)</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic2.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic2.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;Abuse of pleasure is great for your health&#8221;</div>
</div>


<p>Miss.tic doesn&rsquo;t only do scantily-clad ladies, though.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic3.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic3.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;In our secret gardens, desire is created&#8221;</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic4.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/miss-tic4.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;Porn is an error of desire&#8221;</div>
</div>


<p>There are a couple of sculptures by the Italian street art group <a href="http://www.urbansolid.org/">UrbanSolid</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/ears.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/ears.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;Listening Area&#8221;</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/sculpture-prison.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/sculpture-prison.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Out of Eden</div>
</div>


<p>I liked these, although the prisoner is just around a tight corner, and at night I keep thinking there&rsquo;s a person waiting there. It&rsquo;s a little creepy.</p>

<p>There are a few pieces by <a href="http://www.janaundjs.com/">Jana und JS</a>. They have a nice style, and do work in a number of European cities. I like their focus on photography/photographers, who appear in a lot of their works.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/photo.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/photo.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Urban photographer</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/window.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/window.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Window</div>
</div>


<p>You may have noticed a small gecko logo next to a lot of the art. I&rsquo;m not 100% sure what the symbol is for – looking up the <a href="http://www.lezarts-bievre.com/">Lézarts de la Bièvre</a>, it seems to be some kind of art event held in June, with a focus on street artists.</p>

<p>Finally, here&rsquo;s a bunch of other neat stuff I saw that seemed to be one-offs by artists (at least, one-offs for this area).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/moss-bird.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/moss-bird.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">&#8220;Natural&#8221; street art: bird made of moss</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/skeleton.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/skeleton.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Looks like something for Day of the Dead (by <a href="http://www.bunnym.com/">Bunny M</a>)</div>
</div>




<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/world.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/paris/butte-art/world.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Pixelated world</div>
</div>


<p>Anyway, I <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/dir/48.8310625,2.3552585/48.8280933,2.3526657/48.8266199,2.3479307/48.8290213,2.3478663/48.8288321,2.3507471/48.8310907,2.3552156/@48.8292438,2.3512191,17z/data=!4m8!4m7!1m0!1m0!1m0!1m0!1m0!1m0!3e2">google-mapped</a> (Is &ldquo;google-map&rdquo; a verb? It is now, I guess) the route I took. It starts and ends at Place d&#8217;Italie, in case you&rsquo;re arriving by Métro, and takes about 30 minutes. Of course, just wandering around the neighbourhood – especially on a Sunday morning, when it&rsquo;s super-quiet – is nice too.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re leaving this area in the next couple of days to move to a hotel for <a href="http://2014.la-conf.org/">La Conf</a>. After that, it&rsquo;s off to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/M%C3%A1laga">Málaga</a> to meet my family.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vienna]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/13/vienna/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-13T07:33:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/05/13/vienna</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We took the <a href="https://westbahn.at/en/">Westbahn</a> from Linz to Vienna. It leaves every 30mins and takes about 1hr 20mins to get there. The train was swish – clean, with free wi-fi, power ports next to every seat. Plus a conductor (?) came through so you could buy tickets and drinks/snacks. I wish all trains were this nice.</p>

<p>It was pouring when we arrived in Vienna, so although we only had around 24hrs there, we didn&rsquo;t do much during the afternoon. However, that night we had a <a href="http://twitter.com/bastilian">friend</a> to take us to a restaurant and some bars.</p>

<p><a href="http://ulrichwien.at/">Ulrich</a> was a neat restaurant that wouldn&rsquo;t be out of place in San Francisco. It had clean, hip decor and a menu focusing on quality ingredients. The roast chicken was so good (but can you go wrong when you offer a side of bernaise with something?). We then went to <a href="http://www.barflys.at/en/">Barflys</a>, which I&rsquo;d read about as one of the top cocktail bars in Vienna. It&rsquo;s hidden in a hotel, but the cocktails are pretty decent, with more of a focus on US-stye than Cocktailbar Easy (I didn&rsquo;t see one pineapple wedge). However, it was a small room and allows smoking, so&hellip; it was a little suffocating in there.</p>

<p>Finally, we went to <a href="http://www.donautechno.com/main/">Donnau Techno</a>. It&rsquo;s behind an un-marked door in a quiet alley. Inside had an &ldquo;East Berlin&rdquo; feel – the floor was concrete and the furniture was fairly cheap. Ice was served from a bucket. There was a stand in the corner that sold sausages and pickles. The interior had vaulted ceilings and columns, and onto the walls were projected images. Apparently they change every night, as does the techno DJ behind a make-shift booth. We were there on a Sunday, so it was fairly quiet, but apparently it gets packed almost every other night of the week.</p>

<p>The next morning it was beautiful out, so Sebastian took us on a quick yet thorough walking tour of Vienna. We started in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Museumsquartier">Museumsquartier</a> (or &ldquo;MQ&rdquo;), a quadrangle with a number of museums.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/aus/mumok.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/aus/mumok.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Modern art museum – &#8220;mumok&#8221;</div>
</div>


<p>Unfortunately, we didn&rsquo;t have time to stop in any of them. Next time, I promise. We wandered past the Natural History Museum to the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hofburg_Palace">Hofburg Palace</a>, the winter residence of the Hapsburgs and the current residence of the President of Austria.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/aus/palace.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/aus/palace.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Hofburg Palace</div>
</div>


<p>We then walked past the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rathaus,_Vienna">Rathaus</a>, a beautiful gothic building. After that, we went through the windy streets of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Innere_Stadt">first district</a> where there were lots of expensive shops and embassies.</p>

<p>We ended up in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephansplatz,_Vienna">Stephansplatz</a>, containing the impressive <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephansdom">Stephansdom</a>. The roof in particular, a mosaic of coloured tiles, was spectacular.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="/images/the-journey/aus/stephansplatz.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/aus/stephansplatz.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Stephansplatz</div>
</div>


<p><a href="https://www.google.com/maps/dir/MuseumsQuartier,+Museumsplatz+1,+1070+Wien,+Austria/Heldenplatz,+1010+Wien,+Austria/48.2078019,16.3626916/48.210245,16.3605972/Stephansplatz,+1010+Wien,+Austria/@48.2145398,16.362559,15z/data=!4m27!4m26!1m5!1m1!1s0x476d07903eeb4fdf:0x94d429b3eb41ebff!2m2!1d16.358617!2d48.203337!1m5!1m1!1s0x476d0790aaca9f7f:0xc9b8a532e4d2e43a!2m2!1d16.363175!2d48.206358!1m0!1m5!3m4!1m2!1d16.3695358!2d48.2087922!3s0x476d0798e8c0b245:0x3759b284e1f4e281!1m5!1m1!1s0x476d079f3e69c281:0x20563c156aa1fde!2m2!1d16.374238!2d48.2085053!3e2">I made a rough map of the route we took</a> – it took us about an hour to wander through it, as we paused a lot to take photos. If you&rsquo;re short on time and need a whistle-stop tour, I&rsquo;d highly recommend it. However, we didn&rsquo;t get a chance to really take in everything. We would both love to come back to Vienna and maybe even go in some of the wonderful buildings we passed.</p>

<p>Plus, there seem to be a number of great bars and restaurants which we couldn&rsquo;t make it to. We&rsquo;ll be back soon!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
