<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Disney | malrase dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/categories/disney/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.malrase.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-20T14:56:07-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.malrase.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drinking at the Disneyland Resort]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2015/06/20/drinking-in-disneyland/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-20T14:00:29-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2015/06/20/drinking-in-disneyland</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We were in the mountains above Los Angeles for <a href="http://www.maxfuncon.com/">MaxFunCon</a>, a neat comedy/podcasting conference at which we had a lot of fun. Since we were in L.A., why not head to the Disneyland Resort in Anaheim, too?</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s Disneyland&rsquo;s 60th anniversary, so there&rsquo;s a lot of cool stuff going on. In particular, the fireworks at Disneyland are spectacular. If you can make it before the celebrations are over, it&rsquo;s well worth it. Make sure to get a prime spot on Main Street and you won&rsquo;t be disappointed.</p>

<p>Anyway, the rides and all that are fun, but a more pressing question is: are those of us who like cocktails doomed to saccharine cruise-ship drinks while at the parks?</p>

<p>We set off to find out.</p>

<p>The first point: of the two parks in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disneyland_Resort">Disneyland Resort</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disneyland">Disneyland</a> is completely dry (well, apart from <a href="http://www.snopes.com/disney/parks/club33.asp">Club 33</a>). The only park you&rsquo;ll find a drink in is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disney_California_Adventure">Disney California Adventure</a>.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s where we started our investigatory stroll. Our first stop was the Alfresco Tasting Terrace. We&rsquo;d been there on a previous trip, but since then they had stopped serving cocktails. There&rsquo;s only wine and beer now.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/disney/june15/alfresco-terrace.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/alfresco-terrace.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Alfresco Tasting Terrace</div>
</div>


<p>They have wine flights, which are pretty fun. And all the wineries seem to have some connection to Disney – some ex-executive started a winery, and now you can drink it here.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s also a pretty good spot to grab a glass of wine to go. This is especially handy before the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_of_Color">World of Color</a> show. Seen below is us with our to-go cups of wine.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/disney/june15/alfresco-wine-to-go.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/alfresco-wine-to-go.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Booze you can take with you = the best</div>
</div>


<p>Our next stop was more fruitful: the Carthay Circle lounge. It gets busy after around 5pm, and the lounge is first-come-first-served, so make sure you get a seat. The drinks were good, and decently priced ($10-12 each). Because of the Disneyland 60th anniversary, they&rsquo;re putting diamond-shaped cubes in every drink (including Martinis and Manhattans), so if you want your drink unsullied, make sure to mention it.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/disney/june15/carthay-circle-lounge.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/carthay-circle-lounge.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Carthay Circle Lounge</div>
</div>


<p>They didn&rsquo;t just have standard cocktails, either. They had some crème de violette/tequila thing that came with a candied flower on it. It tasted great!</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/disney/june15/carthay-violet.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/carthay-violet.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Violet cocktail from Carthay Circle</div>
</div>


<p>We headed over to The Cove, which is by the Paradise Pier area of the park. Like the Carthay Circle lounge, this place gets really busy, so come early. It&rsquo;s a lot of fun people-watching and sitting outside (if you can take a little sun). I was pleasantly surprised that the discontinued cocktail menu from the Alfresco Terrace was now over here! So I had my favourite drink from that – the Smoked Turkey.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/disney/june15/the-cove.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/the-cove.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">The Cove bar – Smoked Turkey and a Manhattan</div>
</div>


<p>(Oh, you should also get the lobster nachos while you&rsquo;re there. Deeeelicious.)</p>

<p>After we&rsquo;d exhausted Disney California Adventure, we went to our favourite bar at the resort – Trader Sam&rsquo;s Enchanted Tiki Bar. It&rsquo;s located by the pool at the Disneyland Hotel. It&rsquo;s a bit of a trek from the parks (about 10-15mins walk through Downtown Disney), but we enjoy it. Here&rsquo;s the entrance:</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-entrance.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-entrance.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Entrance to Trader Sam&#8217;s Enchanted Tiki Bar</div>
</div>


<p>There&rsquo;s a doorman – like every other bar, this one gets really busy. The doorman had implemented a one-in-one-out policy.</p>

<p>Inside, it&rsquo;s filled with trinkets and tchotchkes over the walls. Every surface is covered in this stuff, and it&rsquo;s really interesting to read/look at. Like everything at Disney theme parks, there&rsquo;s a back-story to every item. Nothing is just put up without thorough thought. There are letters from people Trader Sam has met on adventures. There&rsquo;s things people have mailed. It&rsquo;s quite incredible.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-indoor.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-indoor.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside Trader Sam&#8217;s</div>
</div>


<p>The drink menu has a standard tiki-theme – mostly rums and fruit juices. Most of the drinks have ridiculous names (&ldquo;Tiki Tiki Tiki Tiki Tiki Rum,&rdquo; for example).</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/disney/june15/trader-sams1.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/trader-sams1.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">HippopotoMai-Tai and a Lost Safari</div>
</div>


<p>The Mai Tai was fine, but nothing special. The Lost Safari was really good, though.</p>

<p>For our next round, I ordered the Krakatoa Punch. It came with a glowing &ldquo;ice-cube&rdquo; in it. When I ordered it, the bar lights went low. Through one of the trompe l&#8217;oiel &ldquo;windows&rdquo;, a volcano erupted in a neat little display.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-krakatoa.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-krakatoa.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Krakatoa Punch</div>
</div>


<p>In fact, these things happen for a number of drinks. Every 15 minutes or so, you&rsquo;ll be interrupted. The Shipwrek on the Rocks causes a ship in a painting behind the bar to sink. Plus the bartender sprays you with water.</p>

<p>Our final drink was the Uh Oa. It&rsquo;s a sharing drink, and arrives with a flaming sugar cube. You throw cinnamon and nutmeg onto the flames, creating sparks, while the whole bar erupts in chants of &ldquo;Uh oa! Uh oa!&rdquo;</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-uh-oa.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/disney/june15/trader-sams-uh-oa.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Uh Oa!</div>
</div>


<p>Trader Sam&rsquo;s is entertaining. It&rsquo;s exactly how you&rsquo;d imagine Disney would want a bar to be – adults can get the sense of fun and magic that is often left only to kids.</p>

<p>That was our drinking experience at Disneyland Resort. When we&rsquo;re next down at Walt Disney World, I&rsquo;ll try to do a similar thing for those parks, too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Disney Experience]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/11/29/the-disney-experience/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-29T06:31:49-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.malrase.com/blog/2014/11/29/the-disney-experience</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For our five year anniversary, we decided to head down to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walt_Disney_World">Walt Disney World</a> for a few days. I had never stayed &ldquo;on property&rdquo; (i.e. in a Disney-branded hotel) before, so we opted to stay in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disney%27s_Port_Orleans_Resort">French Quarter New Orleans</a>. It&rsquo;s priced in the middle of the pack – not as expensive as the Grand Floridian or the Contemporary, but not as cheap as the All-Star resorts. (See a handy table on the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walt_Disney_World#On-site_Disney_resorts">Wikipedia page</a>.)</p>

<p>We also wanted to get our hands on the new Disney <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MyMagic%2B#MagicBand">MagicBand</a>. It&rsquo;s an all-in-one ticket to the parks, key to your room, and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disney%27s_Fastpass">FastPass</a>. We were really excited about getting them. You customise them online and they come in the mail.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/orlando/band-box.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/band-box.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Magic Band box</div>
</div>


<p>The packaging reminded me of an Apple product – it was uncluttered and put the product up front.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/orlando/band-in-box.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/band-in-box.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside the box</div>
</div>


<p>The bands even had our names on the inside in case they got mixed up.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/orlando/band-behind.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/band-behind.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Inside of the band</div>
</div>


<p>Staying on-site also gives you the opportunity to take the Disney buses from hotels to the parks. You don&rsquo;t need to worry about the hellish carpark at the end of the day. We decided to do the Disney dining plan, too – one snack, one quick meal, and one sit-down meal per day.</p>

<p>We checked into the hotel, and although the surroundings were nice, the room was disappointing. It was laid out exactly like a motel – a sink area you can see as you walk in the door, a curtain to separate it from the rest of the room. It seemed like that could be a useful layout for families, but it didn&rsquo;t have the &ldquo;magical&rdquo; feeling I was expecting – especially for the price we were paying. I couldn&rsquo;t help but compare it to the far better Lowes Royal Pacific Resort at <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_Orlando">Universal</a>, where we stayed the previous week.</p>

<p>We were there for four days – with one day in each of the four WDW parks. On our first day, we headed to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epcot">Epcot</a> to catch the end of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epcot_International_Food_%26_Wine_Festival">Food and Wine Festival</a>. Held every autumn, they put up extra food stands around the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epcot#World_Showcase">World Showcase</a> representing different countries/cultures.</p>

<p>Anyway, as Epcot is one of the parks where you can drink, we decided to take advantage of the Disney bus system. Here&rsquo;s a pro-tip: <strong>don&rsquo;t use the Disney bus system</strong>. Waiting at our hotel&rsquo;s bus stop, was awful. Three or four buses for the same park would go past, and no passengers would get on. When our bus did come by, it was packed. After about fifteen minutes&#8217; wait for the bus, it was another fifteen minutes to get to the park. Then you&rsquo;re dropped off quite far from the entrance, so there&rsquo;s some extra walking. It was <strong>not</strong> worth it. In the Disney vs. Universal battle, the walkable distance from the parks to the resort hotels makes Universal a much more convenient experience.</p>

<p>Our day at Epcot was a lot of fun, though. Spending a whole day at Epcot allowed us to wander through the World Showcase. We managed to walk through all the countries – into the back areas and shops, which tended to be empty. The amount of detail is incredible. It also helps that some of the countries (such as France and Germany) have wine. That kept us in a good mood.</p>

<div class="img">
  <a href="{{ root_url }}/images/the-journey/orlando/epcot-drinking.jpg">
    <img src="http://www.malrase.com/images/the-journey/orlando/epcot-drinking.jpg">
  </a>
  <div class="alt">Wine at Epcot</div>
</div>


<p>We did Hollywood Studios the next day, then the Magic Kingdom. I was blown away by how busy the Magic Kingdom was – it was a Wednesday in the off-season and even high-throughput rides like Pirates of the Caribbean or the Haunted Mansion were at 50-minute queue times.</p>

<p>Animal Kingdom we left for the final day. They&rsquo;re apparently undergoing a lot of expansion, and we wanted to check it out before <a href="http://disneyparks.disney.go.com/blog/2014/01/construction-begins-for-avatar-inspired-land-at-disneys-animal-kingdom/">Avatar land opens</a>. We rode <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expedition_Everest">Expedition Everest</a> a couple of times – it&rsquo;s a great ride, but the only must-do at Animal Kingdom.</p>

<p>Two other disappointing things: the dining package and the FastPass options on the MagicBand. We got the standard dining package which, as I mentioned above, covers a snack, quick serve meal, and a sit-down meal. We booked it through Disney – as we were staying there three nights, we assumed the package would cover four days. Unfortunately, that&rsquo;s not the case – so be aware of that.</p>

<p>Also, the sit-down meal gives you two courses. However those two courses are <em>only</em> the entrée and dessert. You can&rsquo;t switch the dessert for an appetiser. That kinda sucked for us as neither of us really eat dessert.</p>

<p>We used two of our &ldquo;sit-down&rdquo; credits on <a href="https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/dining/grand-floridian-resort-and-spa/citricos/">Citricos</a>, the fancy restaurant in the Grand Floridian. I&rsquo;ve got to say – the overall experience was a little strange. The food was top-notch, and you could see the Magic Kingdom fireworks from the main dining hall. But the drinks were terrible and there were mostly families there – so not particularly romantic or anything. Can&rsquo;t really complain about families, though, it being Disney and all that.</p>

<p>The best thing to do if you <em>do</em> get the deal is grab a Starbucks coffee at either the Magic Kingdom or Epcot. It counts as a snack – no matter how many extra espresso shots you get. Pretty neat.</p>

<p>FastPass is the way you skip lines at Disney. You used to get a card with a specific return time on it, but now you pre-arrange three rides you want to do at specific times. Staying on Disney property <em>does not</em> give you more than three. Everyone gets that. Compare with Universal, where if you stay on property you get an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_Express_Pass">Express Pass</a> &ldquo;free,&rdquo; and it works any number of times for all designated rides.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t think we&rsquo;ll be staying at a Disney resort any time soon. If we do, I think it would have to be one with better transit options (i.e. one on the monorail). Driving to the parks is a far better option than the bus. I just don&rsquo;t see any real benefit that staying on-property offers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
